Hey guys, this is Ed Rowe.
So today we're going to be building this complete full stack learning management application
with a Next.js front end, Node.js back end, and most importantly, fully deployed on AWS.
So this application is probably one of the most extensive applications I've ever built on YouTube.
And I might even use this for my own purposes of creating a course.
So this is a production-ready application with its own set of use cases.
All right, so here we have our landing page with the loading screen when it pops up.
And you can see some animations happening.
And then from here, we can hit search for courses.
And we can see all our courses being listed.
And we can see different details about each course if we want to take a look at those.
And from here, we can hit sign up for creating our account.
So now this is part of Clerk authentication.
All of this is provided by Clerk to make it easy.
So I am going to create an account.
I'm going to call this toughhuff for the first and last name.
The email is going to be bigtoughyhuffy@gmail.com.
And I'm just going to add some kind of password.
And over here, after signing up, we can see our verification code.
I'm going to copy that, paste it over here.
And we have our email verified for an account.
Once we are signed in, we can see this list of courses page.
We can see billing information for the users.
We can see their profile information.
And this is provided by Clerk.
You have ability to see the profile and security as well.
And then over here, you can see the settings page.
And you should be able to update your settings if you would like.
You can see that we have a little bit of a tag which says user updated successfully,
which is very nice.
In the billing, once we have a transaction, we'd be able to sort it based on payment types.
And we can then go to courses.
Over here in the courses, we have the list of courses that are available.
And this is right now just mock data.
And if we want to search up courses, we can do advanced, things like that.
And then we can even select for specific categories.
Now, it says view only because this is a list of all the courses that
everyone's created in the application.
But if we wanted to create our own course, we can select create course.
And it'll take us to this page.
Now, this page is going to include a number of course titles.
So let's say test this course.
And we're just going to write some random description.
We're going to put course category.
And we're going to give it a price of 30.
Now, over here, we can add a section if we would like.
We can do section one, put some description over here.
And we need to make sure it's over 10 seconds or 10 letters.
And then we can add a chapter as well.
Chapter one, so on and so forth.
And then from here, I can now add a video.
We can add any video for our chapter video.
And that's going to represent the video we have for that specific chapter.
And then we can also add more sections if we would like.
Write a description.
We can save it and we can even reorder the sections as we want to.
And then from here, I can add a second chapter.
We're going to add some content.
And we are going to select a different video.
And we are going to hit save.
So right now, we have not uploaded this video.
So right now, all of these changes are temporary because it's not saved on the back end.
However, if I hit save draft, you should see that we have created a upload URL,
which has been sent to the front end.
The front end is going to get a pre-signed URL from S3.
And we are going to upload our video.
We're uploading each video one at a time.
That's why you're seeing another upload URL right here.
And then we have another video uploaded.
And the course now has been fully updated successfully.
So that is perfectly fine.
And everything is working as expected.
If we go back to the courses page, we can see our course has been created.
Test this course.
Now, before we go to the course and see what's been uploaded and been created,
let's actually see that we have both an edit and delete.
So if you were to create a course and have some course information and hit back to courses,
you can see the course that we've created.
Over here, we can select delete.
And we can also be able to delete the course as well to see the changes.
And there you go.
It is gone.
So now, if we want to see what's happening in this course,
we can now sign out of this account.
And it'll take us back to our landing page.
And this is where things get pretty cool.
We can go search for courses.
And over here, we are looking for test this course, which is a course we have created.
We can see the sections that we have created.
Chapter one, chapter two.
Obviously, you would put actual information.
You can hit enroll now.
And now you can see this is our checkout page.
We can see our course information as well as the price.
And you can see that there's a guest checkout and a sign in page for our course.
Or you can also do sign up, which is on the same exact checkout page.
So let's do that because the other user was a teacher.
Only teachers can create courses.
But this time, we are going to create a user.
And we're just going to call this some dumb for the user.
We're going to say just some dummy email.
And we're going to add a password like this.
And once you have this completed, it also has validation, which is very nice from Clerk.
And we're going to hit continue.
And we're going to be asked for verifying our email.
So I'm going to go to my email off screen.
And I'm going to paste the code.
And it's going to say we are verified.
And it's going to take us to this page now, the second page of our application.
And again, we have the same course preview.
And over here, we are going to be using Stripe.
Now the Stripe credit card fake like testing value.
So you don't actually use real money is going to be 42424242 like so.
And from here, we can just put whatever expiration date and security code and zip code.
Just FYI, if you put something like 20, it's going to show that there's validation.
So all of this is provided by Stripe.
And it's very cool that it gives you all this information.
And you can also have secure one click checkout with link.
But this is completely optional, and you can ignore it.
So when we're done with that, we can hit pay with credit card.
And it's going to say purchase course successfully.
And it's going to show that we have purchased the course successfully.
From here, we can hit go to courses.
And once we have our courses, now we're going to be seeing our courses list page.
Now this is the only course that this user has enrolled in, which is what we just purchased.
But before we click on the course, I want to show you that we also have a profile account for
this particular user.
We can also do user settings as well.
Save that and we can have the user updated successfully.
And from there, we can go to billing.
And we can see that we have a payment history of Stripe as well right here.
And then finally, let's go to our course and select this.
And we are taken to this awesome course page.
Now we can see the videos that we have uploaded.
And this is pretty awesome.
Now there's no sound for this because it's just a video.
And we go scroll through.
And by the way, once you're at 80% of the video upload right here, you can see that it gets
marked as complete.
You can do the same for the next video.
We'll go over here.
And this will also get marked complete as well.
And you can mark it so it's unmarked like this.
You can see that it's on incomplete now once you select this button.
I've seen other learning management application, but I don't think any of them have this functionality
of completed and uncompleted check of their user progress, which is very important for
this.
And there you go.
This is our application.
And we'll also even go through with our courses.
I'll show you how you can create this particular sidebar.
This is an awesome sidebar that ShadCN just created.
So we're going to be using this sidebar to make everything work properly.
And finally, everything in our application is going to be responsive.
You'll be able to see your application at different screen sizes and everything should
work perfectly fine.
And because our application is production level and it is full scale, we have a lot
of diagrams for this application.
In the link in the description, you'll be able to go to this page and see everything
you need to know about this application.
First, you can see that we have app screen design.
So this is a screenshot of every single page in our application.
So you can know and build the application if you have the desire without looking at
my video.
If you want to take that challenge, you can completely do so by looking at these designs
and then recreating.
Secondly, we have the entity relationship diagram.
Basically, this is a diagram of all the data schemas, data models that we are going to
incorporate in our application.
And this is the structure of our data.
And I'll go very much in detail and why we chose this particular database.
And then we'll go through different aspects such as authentication flow in Clerk.
And then we'll go through checkout flow of how that works.
And then we'll go through a course editor.
And finally, and most importantly, you'd probably be most excited with is the AWS
architecture.
I'm going to go through in depth of how we can set and deploy this application onto Clerk,
Bracel, API Gateway, Lambda, ECR, DynamoDB, S3, and CloudFront.
So a link in the description if you want to go to this particular diagram.
All right, from here, let's talk about the tech stack we're going to be using for this
application.
For the front end, we're going to be using Next.js, Redux Toolkit for state management,
Redux Toolkit Query for API interactions.
The styling will be handled by Tailwind CSS, along with ShadCN for component library,
TypeScript for typings, Framer Motion for animation, React Hook for forms, Zot for
validation, and Stripe for payment.
I also mentioned that we are using a separate backend that is not part of Next.js because
it makes the application more scalable and prevents front end become too tightly coupled
to backend.
Hence, our application will be running with Node.js and Express Framework.
Now, more and more, I really, really want to emphasize this is the most important part
is that this app is not like others where we are using services like AppWrite or Convex.
This is an actual enterprise level application.
Now, don't get me wrong.
Those are those services that manage your backend aren't wrong per se or evil in any
kind of way.
They do have their purposes for small scale applications.
But I want you to really understand that it really takes away the capacity to really
customize and scale out your application at affordable cost for large companies, which
is one of the worst things you can do for your development career.
More and more with the age and the coming of AI and in this rough job market, you're
going to be expected to learn more than just front end.
And if you really want to survive, you're going to have to learn backend and deployment.
So in this video, I'm going to do the best that I can to make this step by step and make
sure it is super easy for you to follow and make sure you understand every aspect of the
enterprise level of tech, including backend data modeling and AWS.
So for AWS, we're going to deploy our application on AWS with the modern serverless
containerized architecture.
Our backend is going to be dockerized using Docker, allowing us to package our app into
a very consistent environment.
This container is then going to be stored in ECR, Elastic Container Registry, which
will then be used with AWS Lambda for hosting our backend.
We'll then be using API gateway to securely route requests to Lambda, while DynamoDB
serves as our NoSQL database for fast, scalable storage of application data.
And when it comes to our video content in our application, S3 will be used for handling
that storage.
Finally, we're going to ensure our videos are delivered with low latency and high
availability.
That's why we'll use CloudFront as our content delivery network.
And finally, included in these tools is going to be Clerk Authentication, which is the
sponsor for this video.
Clerk is a very nice tool for authentication.
Now, when it comes to authentication, you can definitely use something like AWS Cognito
as part of AWS.
I tried it myself, but even I ran into some trouble.
Cognito can be restrictive in certain ways and requires a lot of complex setup.
Whereas Clerk, on the other hand, offers a lot of easy pre-made tools for your application,
as you saw in the demo, having pre-built settings, sign in, sign up components, user buttons,
along with a lot of other really useful features.
And we'll get to that in this video, but Clerk makes managing users and adding users
roles super straightforward.
And their documentation is very good, so you'll have no trouble setting up Clerk.
Now, just for you guys to note, specifically for authentication, this is the one area where
it's perfectly fine to use an external service outside of AWS.
Authentication is a very tricky area, and having a dedicated company focused on authentication
can sometimes even be better than using something like Cognito, which requires extensive and
careful implementation to get just right.
Anyways, we'll finally then use Vercel for hosting our Next.js front end to integrate
smoothly with the rest of our AWS services.
So this architecture combines Docker's AWS serverless and storage capacities and global
CDN to create a very scalable application.
Now, don't worry if this setup seems complex.
I'm going to break down every step and guide you through the process using very simple
terminology, making it accessible for beginners.
As always, I designed this application myself, so you are free to use parts or even the entire
project for your portfolio.
Let's dive in and start building.
So the first thing we're going to be doing is we're going to be installing Node.js.
So Node.js is a server-side JavaScript runtime built on the Google Chrome V8 JavaScript engine.
Basically means that you can run JavaScript code on your computer.
So go to the link in the description and you can install Node.js.
And then from here, we're going to be installing NPX.
So NPX will help us install some npm package binaries.
So if you go to the link in the description, you can run npm install -g npx.
And then for our text editor, we can use Visual Studio Code.
I'd probably recommend this text code editor, but you can use other options if you want
to use those.
All right, so open up VS Code and open up a directory where you want to create the project.
Once you have done that, we're going to open up the terminal via control apostrophe.
We're going to open this up and we are going to write npx create-next-app @latest.
And we're just going to say y.
And we're going to call this learning-management.
Hit yes, yes, yes, yes.
Basically yes and no to the defaults.
And then from here, I'm going to write ls so we can see that we created that directory.
And then we're going to open up our folder directory, rename this to client.
We're going to change directory into client.
And before we do anything else, we're going to go to the extensions tab.
And what you want to do is go to es7 plus.
You want to make sure you have react/redux/react-native snippets.
So we're going to be using this to create our React components easily.
And also, you want to make sure you have the prettier extension so that we have the code
formatting when we save it.
So make sure you install these two extensions.
Then from here, we're going to install two Brave extensions.
We're going to install pesticide.
So this will allow us to see our CSS.
And we can see how our entire website is structured via the div and how it's layout.
And then also Redux DevTools, which will help us debug our Redux state when we use it.
So from here, we're going to be installing some packages in our client directory.
So I'm going to write npm i lucide-react.
So this is for icons.
UUID for unique IDs.env for environment variables.
Date-fns for date function utilities.
Framer-motion for animations.
React-hook-form for forms.
Zod for form validation.
@hook-form/resolvers.
And @hello-pangea/dnd.
Now, currently, this is November 10, 2024, which is when I'm recording this.
If you take a look, I am using Next 15, which is using React Canary 19, meaning this is
almost like an unstable version, but they say it's stable.
But it's going to have some issues with these packages.
So, for example, React-hook-form is not going to be compatible with this particular one.
So we are going to have to use --legacy/peer-dps.
Or you can use --force.
But basically, this will install some peer dependencies that are older.
Now, if you're in the future and React 19 is more stable and some of these packages
get updated to be more compatible, you might not have to use this.
But for now, we're going to be using this.
There might be potential bugs because some packages might not be compatible with 19.
But we'll just give this a shot.
All right.
And then from here, we're going to have to install some dev dependencies.
So I'm going to do npm i -D.
I'm going to do @types/node and then @types/uuid.
And I'm going to write --legacy/peer-dps.
So from here, now, there is going to be a link in the description.
I have a link to asset download.
So this will include a bunch of assets that I have prepared.
And this is including mainly a lot of TypeScript and some util functions as well as pre-made CSS
classes.
This application is much less about styling.
Because in the previous videos, I've spent a long time styling, doing all of that creation,
which I don't know how much teaching value there is for me to just style it right in
front of you.
It does take a lot of time.
But I want to focus more on the logical and functional aspect of this application, which
is generally much more interesting.
And I do think it is much more valuable for teaching content.
But let me know what you guys think about this idea.
Anyways, get that asset download file.
And we're going to drag it over here.
And I'm just going to say copy folder.
And we're going to put it into here.
And you're going to see client and server.
And it's going to have a bunch of files.
We're going to just focus on one thing at a time.
The first thing I want to do is I'm going to drag globals.css.
And we're going to replace global CSS like this.
I'm going to close that.
We'll come back to the assets later.
But for now, what I want you to see is that I have a huge host of so many classes.
Because we are not going to spend time doing styling for this application.
We're just going to be using those classes for our styles.
They are already using Tailwind classes.
We're going to be using those.
And we're just going to apply those classes directly onto those components.
In a future video, I do have a very soon upcoming video where I cover CSS and how to do it.
That is the video you should probably watch if you ever want to do styling.
Anyways, if you see here, I have an import, which is the main thing I wanted to show you.
This is what we're going to import.
We're going to import a Google font of DM Sans.
And we're going to set this up in our application.
So I'm going to go to layout.
Go up over here.
I'm going to import DM underscore Sans from next slash font slash Google.
And from here, I'm going to remove these local fonts because we're not going to use those.
We're going to do const DM Sans is equal to DM underscore Sans.
And we're going to say subsets colon Latin like.
So display is going to be swap.
And this is just all set up for our font.
And we're just going to do dash dash font dash DM dash Sans.
I'm going to erase the local font.
I'm going to go down to our class name.
I'm going to erase all of this.
And I'm just going to do DM Sans dot class name like so.
And close it like this and paste it.
So we'll have our font up and ready.
And then from here, I'm going to delete this font folder.
And I'm going to go to page.tsx.
And I'm just going to delete everything in our div and just say,
"Hi, get rid of all these classes because we don't need them."
Remove the image.
We're going to save it.
And we just want to make sure everything is running.
So I'm going to write npm run dev.
So that's how we start our next application.
So we can now go to HTTP local host.
We're going to paste it in our browser.
And we're going to get this error.
And that's because we haven't placed a lot of the configurations that we need.
So we're going to go to our asset downloads.
And we're going to start importing everything or moving everything that we need.
So we're going to have a components folder.
So I'm going to just drag this components into our source directory.
That's going to be for later images.
We're going to grab all of these images, place them in public, keep it over there.
And we have lib with schemas and utils.
We're going to cover a lot of these things as we go along.
So I'm going to pass this into source.
I'm going to drag the state as well.
So that's going to be for our Redux that we'll do very shortly.
I'm going to drag in types as well.
And finally, I'm going to drag Tailwind config actually into our client directory.
And we are going to replace the Tailwind config that we have in our global directory.
Now this Tailwind config consists of a lot, a lot of setup that we have with primary,
secondary, a bunch of colors, border radius, and some shad-cn preparation.
We're going to have all of these all set up in our configuration.
So with all of that, we still can't see our server just yet.
So if you see require Tailwind CSS-Animate, we're going to have to install this.
So we're going to do npm tailwind css-animate because this is part of the Tailwind config
that we added.
And we also need to do --legacy-peer-dps.
Install that.
And once we have that, you can ignore the linting error.
We're going to just do npm run dev.
And from here, we should actually be able to see the server.
If I go to it, you can see that we just have "Hi" at the very top.
Now if you do have some other weird issues and it's still not working, you can delete
.next.
You can delete this folder and then just close out rerun npm run dev if you have any issues.
All right, cool.
And then from here, we're going to finish setting up our Tailwind and we're going to
be installing shad-cn as well.
So we're going to configure all of this to make sure everything is going to work as
expected.
So now I did drop in Tailwind config.
I just want to briefly go over what's happening.
A lot of this is custom styling that is provided both by shad-cn, which already provided it,
but also custom colors that I put myself.
So custom grays is a color that I wanted to put.
Primary bg.
So these are different shades of colors that I wanted.
And then primary is more like a purple color.
Secondary is like a slightly light green color.
And these are defaults provided by shad-cn when we install them.
So those will already be there.
So I'm going to remove that.
But let's get on.
The first thing I want you to do is go to extensions and we're going to be able to see
a Tailwind extension CSS IntelliSense.
So give this one an install.
It's going to allow you to see all the Tailwind classes as you type it.
So it makes it a lot easier.
And also, if you want, you can install Tailwind documentation, which provides little Tailwind
documentation that you can open up if you want to search directly in VS Code.
This is up to you.
I use it sometimes.
Sometimes now I just Google it.
It doesn't really matter.
And once you have that installed, we're going to go back to our directory, open up our terminal,
and I'm going to start installing shad-cn libraries.
So the first thing you want to do is npx shad-cn @latest init -d.
So anytime you want to start installing shad-cn libraries, this is how you want to begin.
And like I said, with React 19, which is supposedly unstable, we're going to use legacy-pure-deps.
All right.
So unfortunately, if you go to the utils, it basically updated and replaced my utils
file, which I did not expect.
So if you go back to your asset download, I'm just going to delete everything.
I'm going to copy the entire asset download that we had earlier.
So I'm going to paste the asset download over here.
We can have everything all set up back again.
So if you go back to lib utils, basically has all the normal class names that you would
expect, but it has a lot more.
So I'm just going to copy this time.
I'm not going to drag it, but I'm going to replace it over here.
So I'm going to delete this, rename this to utils.
This has a lot more functions and constants that we are going to be using.
I didn't want to spend the time to give you guys utils functions or like have you guys
write them because they're just basically logic questions that you have to figure out
yourself.
Anyways, we're going to close all of this and we have shad-cn installed.
And then from here, we're going to install a bunch of sad shad-cn libraries, or basically
components, I mean, if you don't understand how shad-cn works, it installs every single
component one at a time, but we're going to install a good number of them.
So we're going to first add an accordion avatar button card, dialogue, form, input, label,
navigation-menu, popover, progress, select, separator, sheet, sidebar, skeleton, switch,
table, tabs, text area, toggle, and tooltip.
I know there's a lot, but we're going to go through as we build the application.
And again, we're going to use legacy-peer-deps.
And then once you have that installed, we can go to tailwind-config.ts.
It does replace this for some reason.
This should not be a string.
I don't know why I replaced that.
So we're just going to replace it to be true.
Close that.
And we want to double check that we have our components.
So if it's working, you could see in our components folder, another separate folder
called UI, and it should have all our components in there.
And you should also see another folder called hooks.
And we're going to see use-mobile.
It has added that.
And then from here, we're going to go back to client and we're going to add tailwind-class-ordering.
Basically, it's going to order our tailwind CSS classes if it needs to.
So this is entirely optional.
npm i -d prettier-plugin-tailwind-css.
We're going to do legacy-peer-deps.
And we just have to go to tailwind-config.ts.
Go down to plugins all the way down over here.
And we're just going to write comma prettier-plugin-tailwind-css.
And then finally, let's just give it one more shot just to make sure everything is working.
We're going to go back to localhost, refresh the page,
and we should see that it's still exactly the same.
This is what you expect.
As long as you don't have an error, you are good to go.
All right.
So from here, we're going to be installing Redux Toolkit.
Now, we're going to close this client out.
I've already created a folder called state, which I dragged from the asset downloads.
If you remember, we have an API file, we have an index, and we have Redux.
So we're going to first install the packages we need for these files.
So I'm going to do npm i react-redux@reduxjs/toolkit.env.
Actually, we already installed .env.
I'm going to do legacy-peer-deps.
All right.
So now, before I used to make you guys copy, but now we just have this folder.
I have this folder that I told you to just drag without us having to do much else.
There's a few last things we actually need to set up.
So I'm going to create a new file called providers.
So this is a place where we want to keep all the providers or anything that
needs to be put on the global state for our Next.js application.
So over here, I'm going to write use client.
And we are going to import react from react like so.
We're going to import store provider from at/state-redux.
So that comes from this file.
So this file includes everything we need to create our Redux store.
So we're just going to import that.
And I'm going to create providers component.
We're going to use children colon and children colon react.react node.
Return.
And we're going to pass in store provider.
And we're going to pass in children like so.
And we're just going to make sure we do export default providers.
With this, we're going to go to our page directory.
Actually, my mistake.
Go to layout directory.
And around our body, I'm going to bring in providers.
From the directory that we just created, we're going to make sure that goes around the children.
And this is all we have to do to set up Redux.
All right.
So from here, we are going to create a file called dot env dot local.
And we're just going to set we're going to go to our Redux, our API file, we're going to see
process dot env dot next public API base URL.
So basically, anytime we make an API request, this is the base URL that we're going to be
using.
So we're just going to copy this guy right here.
Go over here.
Paste that environment variable.
And we're just going to do HTTP colon slash slash local host colon 8001.
That is where our server is going to be hosted.
And we're going to take care of that a little later.
And there you go.
Our Redux is basically set up.
One of these days, I might create a little bit of a tool that will automatically set
this up for you, which will make things easy.
But we'll see if that happens.
All right.
So now with all of this set up, we can actually start building our application.
So we can go and there is a link in the description to get to this specific page where we can see
different pages of our design.
Right here, I have set up a very detailed page where it includes our entire application.
Now, these are screenshots.
These are not Figma designs.
So it's probably not as good as quality.
But the application turned out a little different from the Figma designs that I've created.
But we can see that we have search pages.
And we're going to start with the landing page and the search pages for our course.
Now, if you want to see the final application, it would look something like this.
On refresh, you'll see a loading page and you can see some animations.
And you should be able to click search for courses and see these particular pages.
All right.
So to start off, I move the application on the right side and I'm going to close this
over here.
I'm going to open up the page component over here in the app directory.
And we're going to start building over here.
Inside our home directory, I'm going to put a class name of non-dashboard layout.
So this will set up the layout for our non-dashboard page.
And I'm going to call this non-dashboard navbar.
So I collectively called this particular area of the application where we have search pages,
authentication pages, checkout pages as non-dashboard.
Everything else right here, as you can see, these are the pages where we actually have
a dashboard layout.
And this is when you are signed in.
You can see a dashboard that's relevant to you.
Whereas these are non-dashboard pages.
Let me close that so you guys can see a little better.
So we are starting with the search page and we are going to create this particular navbar
over here.
So I'm going to close that out, create a non-dashboard navbar, and I'm going to import
non-dashboard.
Navbar like so.
And we're going to do from at slash components slash non-dashboard navbar.
I'm going to save that and we are going to go to our components directory and I'm going
to create a new file.
I'm going to call this non-dashboard navbar dot TSX.
Close this out.
Get some space.
Actually, RAFCE.
So we don't have any types because this is not going to take anything.
And we are going to create our navbar from here.
So I'm going to erase all of this and we're going to add a nav element over here.
So this is important for, you know, HTML element semantics.
So make sure you understand that.
We're going to have non-dashboard navbar.
And inside here, I'm just going to write hello, just so we can see that this is being
inputted.
Now, sometimes the linting does not work properly.
So you're going to have to retype it and it'll import it correctly.
So right now we don't see it on our application because we haven't run.
So open up your terminal and write npm run dev.
Make sure it's running.
And I'm going to refresh the page.
And as you can see, we now have hello for the navbar, just to see that we have the navbar
written over here.
So we're just going to quickly erase that and we're going to add some divs.
So we're going to have a class name of non-dashboard navbar double underscore container.
Now, when you see this, this type of naming is called block element modifier.
Typically, right now I do have all the classes set up over here in global CSS.
You can see that a lot of these classes, let's just search up non-dashboard navbar.
They have a bunch of tailwind classes all applied.
And I'm doing this because I don't want to focus on CSS.
Like I mentioned, these are already pre-made, but I am using something called block element
modifier.
So that is basically you start with the relevant element and then you write whatever is the
class it's relevant to.
This is just an easy way to organize.
Now in a real production application, I would probably not do class names like this.
I would probably leave the tailwind classes as is.
But if you ever wanted to use block element modifier, you can do it this way.
But specifically for tutorial purposes.
Anyways, let's get back to it.
We're going to import link.
And if you see what I'm doing as I'm typing, I have linting coming in, which shows what
we're going to import.
Make sure you use that because it's very important because it gives you both ease of
use and getting used to that prevents errors.
Because sometimes if you don't do it correctly, you're going to have typos and you're not
exactly sure what happens.
So it's good practice to use those typings.
So right here we have a link and I put non-dashboard navbar brand that gives us a link to our home
page.
Below this, I'm going to write div with the class name of flex items center and a gap
of four.
So the items will be flexed below and we're going to do class name with relative and we
are going to group it.
Inside here, we're going to add a search input.
So we're going to import link once again.
We're going to have an href of search.
And this will just take us to a search page.
And we're going to give it a class name of non-dashboard-navbar double underscore search
input.
Inside here, I'm going to do a span with the class name and we're going to say it's
hidden.
And it's going to be in line for any screens that are above small sizes.
So this is going to say search courses.
And you can see we have a little search bar right here.
But right now, we don't have the text.
So we're going to add another span and we are going to say hidden for small screens.
So we are making sure these are responsive designs.
So as you can see, we have a search bar.
If you open up, it goes to search courses like this.
And then from here, we're going to import book open, which is an icon from Lucide React.
I'm going to do class name of non-dashboard-navbar double underscore search icon with the size
of 18.
And as you can see, we have now an icon opens up and it will take us to a search page.
We're not going to click on it because we don't have a search page just yet.
So as of right now, we have these two sets.
We're going to actually go below the three divs and we are going to create another div.
So this will represent the right side.
And we're going to have a class name of non-dashboard-navbar double underscore actions.
And in here, I'm going to say button with the class name of non-dashboard-navbar
double underscore notifications button.
Close that out.
We're going to put a span with the class name and give it a non-dashboard.
Actually, let's just copy all of this so we can make this easier.
Dash indicator.
And we are going to close this span.
And finally, we're going to put a span.
Finally, we're going to give it the bell icon.
So this is for the bell icon with notifications.
We're not adding notification functionality for this particular application,
but it is there if you want to add the functionality for a bit of stretch goal.
So we have the bell icon.
We have the search.
And it does seem I did miss something.
So the search courses should be on the left side.
If you take a look at the final application, it should be on the left side, not on the right side.
So there was a div that we did miss.
And so right above the link of Edbro, we're going to write div class name is equal to non-dashboard-navbar.
But this should be search right here.
Close this out with the div and we're going to wrap it around right here.
And that should emphasize the correct layout now.
And if you go down, this should instead not be plural.
So we're going to save that and we should be able to see the notifications
with that little bell icon that says that you have.
Now, from here, we're just going to give this a comment, say.
Sign in buttons.
So this is where we're going to have authentication.
We're going to have some kind of user information.
This will be where a clerk is going to exist.
But we're going to come to that when we talk about authentication.
All right, next part, we're going to create the main part of the landing page.
So this right here with a little bit of carousel to make it look OK.
And then we have search for courses as well, the courses that pop up here.
So if I refresh the page, you can see some animation of the skeleton
and some nice little other design aspects to it.
So let's get started with that.
So going back to our page component, we're going to add another section
and we're going to call this main with class name,
with non-dashboard layout double underscore main like so.
And inside here, we're going to create a landing component.
I'm going to import it, even though we haven't created it just yet.
So I'm going to import landing from at slash app slash friends,
non-dashboard friends slash landing slash page.
Now, this is the path where we're going to put our landing file.
So we're going to create a new folder.
We're going to call this friends non-dashboard and I'll explain why.
The reason why we have this parents is so that it is not included in the path of the URL.
So anytime you use parents inside the app directory,
it's not going to be included when you go to that URL.
So if I instead create a folder inside here, I'm going to call this landing.
And if I create a file called page dot TSX,
that means from the home route at localhost slash landing.
This will be the page that shows it excludes the non-dashboard URL.
But also because we have it, we have this landing page over here.
This is also going to show at the home route.
So this exact page will be on landing and this home route.
So we'll have both of those shown.
So from here in our component, I'm going to write RFC.
And we are going to call this landing component like so.
And we aren't seeing anything because we have this linting error.
So we're going to say landing and also, and it seems like I needed to refresh the page.
So now you'll see the landing text over here.
So from here, I'm going to use animation.
So I'm going to do motion dot div like so.
So motion dot div is from framer motion.
So we're going to import motion, not morsion, motion from framer dash motion.
So this is a little bit of an animation library.
We're going to make sure we have motion dot div like that.
And inside here, we're going to start with an initial opacity of zero.
So this is the initial state of our animation.
And we are going to animate it in with an opacity of one.
So that means it fades in.
We also need to set the time in which it animates.
So we're going to use transition property, give it a duration of 0.5.
And we're going to give it the class name of landing like so.
So if you save it, you're still going to see this error.
I'm not exactly sure why it doesn't show you the right error.
Seems like a Next.js problem.
But we want to use use client over here.
So now, as you can see, the landing kind of fades in, which is very nice.
From here, we're going to add another motion dot div.
And we're just going to copy this entire animation set properties like this.
I'm sure we close it, but we're going to change a few things.
This time, we actually want things to move.
So we're going to give it a Y of 20.
So it initially starts from position 20 above.
And we want to not do that.
But we start animating to the zero position.
And we should actually put this to be landing double score under hero.
So now if you see that there is a little bit of movement going up into this animation.
And then from here, we're going to do a div with the class name of landing
double underscore hero dash content.
Inside here, we're going to do an H1 tag with the class name of landing double underscore title.
With the courses and with the P tag with class name of landing double underscore description.
Like so I can just write it out correctly.
And this is a list of the courses you can enroll in.
And we're just going to write a little break point.
And we're going to say courses when you need them and want them.
Just some random text.
So we have this over here.
We also need the call to action.
So we're going to say div with the class name of landing double underscore CTA.
And we're going to pass in a link with the href slash search.
And inside here, this will be basically the button that we have.
It'll take us to the search page.
And we're going to give it a class name of landing double underscore CTA dash button.
And we're just going to say search for courses.
And we need to make sure we import the link.
So we're just going to use IntelliSense to do that.
So make sure you grab the next link, not the Lucide React one.
And we should see we have a search for courses button.
And then from here, we're going to create a div.
We're going to call this class name with this.
And we're going to give it a landing double underscore hero dash images.
Close this div out.
And inside here, I'm going to put an array to slash hero1.jpg, comma, slash hero2.jpg like so.
Slash hero3.jpg like this.
So this will represent the little carousel image that we saw.
And we're going to pass in source, comma, index.
And we are going to return.
And we're going to grab the image from next image.
We're going to give it a key of source.
Give it a source of source as well for the image.
We're going to do alt.
And we're going to call this hero banner.
This is just a description of what the image will look like.
We're going to do index plus one.
So this is a very unique alt for each one.
We're going to give it a fill property with priority.
And what we want to do is index.
And we're going to set this to current image.
Now, we haven't created current image property.
So let me just close this image tag out.
And we're going to go up and set up a little bit of a hook that will
set up our interval in which the image timing will happen.
So I'm going to go up here right above the return.
I'm going to call this const current image.
And we're going to do use carousel, which we have not created.
And we're going to put total images of three.
So this little hook is just going to be used so that we can cycle between our images.
So I'm going to go over here, go to our hooks folder that has been created earlier.
I'm going to create a new file.
I'm going to call this use carousel.ts.
Inside here, I'm going to import use state, use effect from react.
Like so.
And we're going to create an interface because we need some props that we need to pass
into this component.
We're going to say total images will be number with an interval, which is optional.
With a number like this.
From here, I'm going to do export const use carousel.
Pass an array or object basically with total images and an interval with the default of
5000.
So five seconds.
And we are going to pass in the use carousel props that we just created.
Create an arrow function.
And we are going to pass in a state with current image.
Set current image.
And we're going to do use state of zero.
So we're going to start with the first image, which is zero index.
And then we're going to create a use effect that will cycle between those images.
So what we do is we're going to create a timer.
We're going to set interval.
So this will allow us to cycle between images based on the timer of every few seconds.
We're going to do set current image.
We're going to grab the previous.
Make sure we do.
The previous number, which in this first case would be zero.
We're going to add one.
And then we're going to modulus total images like so.
And we're going to pass in interval time over here.
And we're going to make sure we return an arrow function with clear interval and timer.
And with the bracket of total images for interval.
So it'll cycle to any time these changes.
And then finally, we're going to return the current image.
So this is a very clean way so that we can grab the current image and it'll cycle through.
Each period, each time based on an interval.
So it just gives us a number cycled every five seconds.
And we're going to go back to our landing page, import that hook that we just created.
And we can go to our image over here.
And we now have the current image.
We still need to add a few things.
So sizes is basically a way for us to optimize our images based on the screen size.
And this is provided specifically for Next.js.
But you can also do this with plain old CSS.
It's just a different way of adding it.
So we're going to do a max width of 1200 pixel.
We're going to do 50 viewport width and then 33 viewport width.
So this basically is a responsive design of how the resolution of the image should be
based on the size of the screen.
So it's a more image optimization technique.
And then we have class name.
We should also set this to be landing double underscore hero dash image.
But we're going to have a conditional situation where if the index is equal to
the current image, we're going to set this landing double underscore hero image to be active.
So this is the way that it shows the correct image at the correct time.
And once we have saved that, we can now see that we have an image.
And it cycles through every five seconds.
Nothing too crazy.
And then from here, right below the motion.div, but in the other motion div, we're going to
create another one.
Motion.div.
Like so.
Close this out.
And we're going to copy the properties once again.
So we'll have to rewrite it.
Paste it over here.
Now the opacity should be zero.
Y is 20.
So this is all fine.
But this time we're going to add a viewport element.
This should be amount of 0.3 and wants to be true.
So these two properties determine when it gets animated.
And this means that it will only do it once.
The animation should only happen once, right when you enter that viewing section of the
page.
And now when we do it like this, the animate property needs to be while in view instead.
Instead of the landing double score hero, this should be featured instead.
And below this is where I'm going to add the tags.
So we're going to start with an h2 header tag.
And we're going to do class name of landing double underscore featured dash title.
Close this out.
We're going to say featured courses.
And below this, I'm going to have a p tag.
We're going to say class name is equal to landing double underscore featured dash description.
Save it just so you can see.
In here, I'm just going to have a bunch of text.
So I'm going to say from beginner to advanced.
In all industries, we have the right courses just for you.
And preparing your entire journey for learning and making the most.
A bunch of gibberish, whatever.
You can change that text to whatever you want.
And then right below that, we are going to have some tags.
So we're going to say class name, we're going to landing double underscore tags like so.
Put this in brackets.
I'm going to say web development like so.
Enterprise IT.
React Next JS.
Web development.
And enterprise IT.
Now, usually I would spend the time to make it more relevant.
But for now, we're just going to have a bunch of these text.
We're going to map this out.
Give it the tag text with index.
Close this out with the span.
Give it a key of index with the class name of landing double underscore tag.
Close this.
Pass in the tag element.
And we'll see that we have our tags like this.
It looks kind of bad that we just have duplicate values.
So I'm going to just change this to be back end development, something like this.
So it looks a little bit different.
There we go.
And then the final part of this page is going to include the actual courses.
Now, this course is going to come from our back end.
So right now, what we're going to do, I'm going to pass in a div.
Call this class name of landing double underscore courses.
But for now, we're going to add a comment courses display over here.
And the reason why we're going to do this is because we need to do the back end first.
And we're going to create the courses back end API endpoint to fetch this data.
Actually, before we do that, I just want to do one more thing.
It's if you refresh the page, we don't have this loading skeleton like this.
If you see over here, that's the loading skeleton that will show up when the courses page comes in.
So we're just going to create this.
You're probably not going to be able to see it until we grab the courses.
So I'm going to do loading skeleton like so.
And we're going to create this out real quick.
So we're going to return.
There's not much to this.
So we're going to do landing skeleton.
So basically, what we're doing to create this skeleton over here, when you see this,
is basically we need to replicate the entire layout of the page.
But we're just going to replace it with empty object.
Now, this is one of those situations where I would just say, use AI for this,
because this is very tedious.
And the AI is pretty good at doing things like this.
If it's just to replicate something, it's a very convenient tool to do this.
So that's exactly what I did, and it got it right on the first time.
So skeleton double underscore hero dash content.
And I'm going to pass in skeleton, which is going to come from our components UI skeleton,
which is from our shadcn library.
We're going to grab the class name to landing skeleton double underscore title.
We're going to close this.
And I'm just going to copy this out, paste it four times.
And we're just going to change the class.
So subtitle dash secondary.
This should be button over here.
And then I'm going to paste it one more time.
This should be hero dash image.
So right now, you're not going to be able to see that.
On yours, because we haven't implemented just yet.
Below this, I'm going to have a div with the class name of landing skeleton double underscore
featured like so.
And I'm going to paste skeleton two more times.
This should be featured dash title.
It should be featured dash description.
And below this, we're going to do div with class name of landing dash skeleton underscore
tags.
And the reason why we need to replicate the entire thing is so we have the exact same
positioning so that it's nice because you want it to be exactly the same, simply because
it's going to just have the same layout.
So it doesn't cause like a layout shift.
So it's not it's very smooth when you look at the loading.
Like if you take a look and I refresh, it's in the exact same positions that it's supposed
to be.
That's why if you take the time to do this, it makes it look all right.
From here, we're going to do a key with an index class name landing skeleton underscore
tag like so.
And I'm going to copy this over here and we're going to do the same thing, except there should
be courses.
There should be only four of these.
And we're going to do course dash card.
And there's that.
So we're just going to keep it like this.
We're going to be using it later on.
So while we put the courses on hold, we're going to go back to our page.
We're just going to finish this up with a further component.
They're going to place this over here.
I'm going to go back to our directory and inside the components folder, I'm going to
create a new file, call this further.
And I'm going to use RFC.
We have their further component already.
And inside here, we're going to have it pretty simple.
I'm just going to say class name is going to be further inside here.
I'm going to put a P tag and we're going to have a symbol of the copyright.
Little at sign.
So that's going to be and copy semicolon 2024 at row all rights reserved like so.
Passing our div with class name.
With further double underscore links like so passing our div curly braces, I'm going
to say about privacy policy, licensing contact, and I'm going to do dot map pass in item and
return an arrow function.
And I'm going to pass in a link from next link like so say key is equal to item.
Each ref is going to be slash item dot to lower case, perens dot replace any spaces
with dashes class name.
By the way, these links will go anywhere, but if you wanted to, you can add these links
to be legitimate.
And we're going to pass an item over here.
Save that.
And over here, we're going to go back to our main page, import further from at components
further.
And you should be able to see that we have our further over here.
Perfect.
For us to grab information about the courses, we need to turn our attention to the back
end.
And when we turn our attention to the back end, we need to focus on the database and
how our data is structured.
This part, also known as data modeling, is a very, very important part of your application.
And some people don't even do this step, but it is extremely important because the way
you structure your data affects your entire application.
It is the foundation.
It is the very root foundation of your entire application.
So if you structure your data in a very poor way, it will affect how messy your application
will become.
Everything else will become messy and become hard to work with.
All these other applications, all these YouTube tutorials where you're building an application,
but they're using managed back ends and managed databases such as app right or a convex
databases, which are, you know, I'm not knocking on them.
They're great.
They're great tools for what they're supposed to do, which is manage your back end, manage
your database.
But I will say for you as a developer, doing those type of databases is not good for your
future as a software engineer.
Now, I know there's a lot of videos out there.
You guys are learning all these new front end technologies like Svelte and then on the
back end, Hano, Express.
I will say, I will say this is my honest opinion.
You are almost wasting your time trying to learn the latest technology, especially in
front end.
There is a point, there is a cap on how much people believe your ability as a software
engineer is if all you know is front end engineering.
It is a sad truth of the harsh job market.
And it's simply because demand, right?
Supply and demand.
There is an extremely large amount of front end engineers.
There's so many front end engineers who are just building CRUD applications, doing front
end, just styling and designing a website.
But I will tell you, it is a very, it is a losing, it is a losing proposition to go against
AI, which is specifically targeting front end much more than back end right now.
It is affecting both, but front end engineers are getting more clobbered by AI.
Even people who are non-technical, they're starting to build websites with AI.
They're just telling AI to do it.
And they're going to think, why, if I can do this, why would I pay someone to build
these applications for me?
Now, you might think that they would do the same thing with back end and DevOps.
And as someone who's been doing that for quite some time now, I can tell you it is
a lot harder for them to grasp the right ways to do back end and DevOps, because there are
a lot more decisions that are higher level that require a lot more planning that affects
the downstream effects and scalability that is harder for AI to cover that.
So I encourage you guys, you probably know enough React, you probably know enough front
end and using something like a managed back end and managed database, a convex database
app, which have their purposes and have their use case of building fast MVPs.
It is not useful for you as a developer to learn those technologies because back end
and DevOps is going to be where you can stand out.
And as someone who's been hiring developers nowadays to help me out on task, I can tell
you the supply of front end developers is almost overwhelming.
There are people who would do it for pennies versus back end engineers, which are a lot
harder to find.
Anyways, you don't have to take my word for it.
It's just my opinion.
You can give it a shot.
Anyways, so back to our data modeling in our course, we have a number of properties.
You can think of this as just basically a large object.
This is how we sort our data.
So we have our course and we have a lot of these properties that are going to be sorted
into this basic course.
And it's also going to have nested objects in this case.
So we're going to have section, chapters and comments.
So sections just categorize a group of chapters and chapters are where we're going to actually
have the video URL stored.
We're also going to have transaction and user course progress schemas that are going to
include a number of properties, but I'll come to those when we talk about it.
But for now, know that in this particular data model, we're storing all our information
into a single course so that anytime we fetch the course object, we grab all the properties
relevant to the course in one API call, in one fell swoop from our database.
However, we do not store the progress of the user because you know how the user watches
a video, they are progressing through and we need to save information on how far they
have gotten in that course, whether they completed a certain section or a chapter.
That is where the user course progress is aligned.
Now, when it comes to data modeling, these are high level decisions.
You could put the user course progress in this course object, but the problem is sometimes
with the user course progress, this becomes way too dense.
There is too much data in the same object and that is a problem.
This is why we have to spend the time to model out data structures like this.
So for example, in the user course progress, if we put this into the course object, that
means the user course progress concludes information about a single user, about a single
course and how much progress they have made.
But the problem with that is in that same course, if we had thousands of users that
are applied to the same course, this object would become massive.
That means when you fetch the data, it's going to become a massive object of too much
information, which is, you know, if you use DynamoDB, it has limits of how much each item
in the database can hold.
So for every course object, it's going to be too much information.
That is exactly why we separated the user course progress, which is just specifically
how much they've gone through in each course.
And we'll go more into detail of how we structure.
But before we go further, let me explain the decision on choosing DynamoDB as the database.
Because some of you have been requesting me to go through some system design ideas.
So we're going to talk about why DynamoDB was chosen for this particular application.
And when you choose any database, the first thing you want to ask is whether you choose
SQL versus NoSQL.
Now, in this case, as you can see, we have three different schemas, which is actually
not that many.
This is a pretty low amount of tables that you would need for an application.
And there isn't that many relationships.
You might have a course and there might be transactions that involve the course.
So transactions are related to course in that kind of way.
Same thing with the user course progress.
It is related to the course ID.
But in short, this is not that many relationships.
When you have a social media application where you have a post and every post might have
users both liking and commenting, that can spiral out of control in a number of relationships.
Those require SQL type databases because you want to be able to fetch all of those in one
go.
In this case, when we grab a course, we just need the course information.
And then sometimes we might want transaction information in another separate API call because
we're calling them separately.
We don't need that many relationships.
That is exactly why DynamoDB is the NoSQL choice that we're going to use because we
don't need that many relationships.
And SQL does, it brings ACID guarantees.
You can look that up.
I'm not going to go into it, which basically means like it's more secure and more consistent.
But it also becomes with a lot of overhead maintenance.
So sometimes you want to avoid those because you want scalability and speed, which is NoSQL's
strong point.
So once we have decided that we aren't going to use SQL, then we can decide using DynamoDB
versus other NoSQL.
And DynamoDB is very fast and performant.
And it's going to scale on its own.
So you don't have to worry about doing all the scaling.
You don't have to worry about managing your database in that kind of way.
AWS handles it for you.
So you don't even have to worry about that.
Even if you compare it to something like MongoDB, which you probably have heard, DynamoDB is
even better because it's already all managed.
You don't have to worry about much of the infrastructure.
It's going to scale automatically just for you.
You don't have to worry about that.
And there's no networking issues.
If you saw my other videos where I'm dealing with networking, there's not that many networking
things that you need to deal with when you're using DynamoDB.
And especially when you're using the AWS ecosystem, this is ideal.
And also DynamoDB is very cheap.
There is a free tour and it's always going to be free.
You don't even have to have a free tier account.
It's going to have a very generous free tier that's going to always be available, especially
for you as a developer.
This is important for me to make this decision because you guys would not be willing to pay
for hosting on some paid server just for your own, you know, like dev projects.
Now, I have listed some disadvantages, which I've already covered.
It's not ideal for tables with many relationships.
It's not great for highly nested data structures.
And I'll come to the course later on when we have sections and chapters, which becomes
a little bit of an issue because it's quite nested.
It's not very nice.
And DynamoDB is not good for filtering, sorting and aggregation.
If you have like a table and you need complex filtering needs of all your data, those are
situations where, you know, no SQL in general is not good.
MongoDB is better at filtering than DynamoDB.
DynamoDB is much more fast and performant in skills, but it is even worse than MongoDB
and DocumentDB of complex filtering and sorting.
So just be aware of DynamoDB.
DynamoDB excels more so than MongoDB if you have less tables.
Ideally, you have less tables.
And there used to be a period where people would just go extreme with DynamoDB and they
would do a single table for their entire data.
Nowadays, it's almost frowned upon.
You should only use the tables that you need, but you shouldn't force one table.
But that's a story for another day.
That's that.
Anyways, I know I've been talking for a long time for this backend and database.
Now, let me know in the comments section if you like what I'm doing with explaining a
lot more, because sometimes it's just a lot of talking when you talk about the decision
making behind something like this, because there's a lot of, you know, I can't really
do this live.
It's kind of a process where you just have to kind of consider a lot of different things.
And so it just ends up being about talking.
So let me know in the comments whether you like it or not.
All right, so enough talking.
Let's go and download DynamoDB.
Now, DynamoDB is hosted on AWS, but we're going to be using the DynamoDB local so that
we can make sure everything works locally before we deploy everything onto AWS.
So go to the link in the description and you can go to this page, deploying DynamoDB locally
on your computer.
Now, before we do this, you may or may not have the Java runtime.
So you also want to download Java if you need to, which you go over here and you can install
based on your operating system.
Once you have that installed, I'm not going to go through that process, but I will go
through the process of downloading DynamoDB local over here.
So you can see right here, I'm going to choose zip.
Save that.
Once we have downloaded that, we're going to open up our directory.
I'm going to extract it.
I'm going to call this DynamoDB-local like this.
And if you go back to the link, you can see that we have this particular URL.
So now you can open a command prompt and navigate to the directory, but we're just going to
use absolute entire path.
So what I'm going to do is I'm going to get info in Mac.
You can do the same thing equivalent in Windows.
I'm going to just copy as path name for this.
So the command for this is going to be java-djava.library.path is equal to.
I'm going to paste the path that we had and I'm going to write DynamoDB-local, which
represent this folder right here, and I want the path to DynamoDB-local_lib.
So I'm going to do DynamoDB-local_lib.
So that gets the path of the library and we want to write jar as well, but this one is
going to be the path to the jar file right here.
So I'm going to do the same thing, DynamoDB-local/DynamoDB-local.jar and we are going to do shared DB.
And I believe this should be lowercase b like that.
Yeah.
So let me close this out one more time so you can see the actual full path right here
is the path to the library file and this is the path to the jar file.
So that comes with the download that we have.
So once you have this correct, when you press enter, you're going to see you have DynamoDB-local
with the following configuration.
So this is the port.
So that's how simple it is to run DynamoDB.
And then with this, we can run commands to execute on the DynamoDB.
Now, if you want to access DynamoDB programmatically, you're going to need the AWS CLI.
Now, in another link, I know there's a lot to install, but this is AWS.
So you have a lot of things, a lot of moving pieces.
So AWS CLI is pretty easy and simple to install.
You go to this link and you just go to your particular OS and install the package over
here and follow the instructions.
And most of this is just you download the file, it's going to run an installer, go through
the commands, and then you just have to make sure it's working AWS-version.
Should be pretty straightforward.
And over here, I'm going to open up a new window and I've already done this, so I'm
not going to configure it, but there is a command.
Once you have AWS installed, the CLI, you're going to run AWS configure.
You're going to see AWS access key.
This is where you're going to put your access key, secret key.
Now, you don't have to do it right now.
We will configure this later if we need to on AWS account.
But for now, you don't really need to do so.
You can just add fake keys.
Like, for example, they just said fake my key ID, secret key access.
So you don't need to do anything.
You just put these fake values and should be enough to work.
And once you have done that, we can just grab this link over here.
Let me just cancel this out.
If I paste it over here, we should be able to get table names.
So right now, we have nothing in our table for our database, but we are basically calling
our endpoint, which is at port 8000.
So it should be working and you should be able to see an empty array right here.
So that's pretty much all you need for running DynamoDB locally.
OK, there's one more thing I want to show you in regards to this.
So right now, this path right here is what is running our server.
So I cancel it out.
I just wanted to show you the path one more time.
But anytime we close the database, we're going to lose all the data that we stored in our
local database.
We don't want that.
We want our data to persist.
So if we reopen it again, we have our information.
So we just add another configuration.
We write DB path.
And what we want is the path to our current folder.
So this is where my directory is saving or this is where my code base basically is.
So right now, this is what I want to be stored.
So if I want to do, I can grab this as path name.
I'm going to paste that, write run.
And when you run it, it's going to do the same exact thing that we did.
But when we store our data into our DynamoDB table, it's going to save information or persisted
data into this particular folder path.
All right.
So from here, there's one last thing that we can install.
I know there's quite a bit of things that are coming along.
It's a lot of setup.
But this part is optional if you want to see.
So what I want you to do is go to this NoSQL Workbench for DynamoDB.
This will allow us to see the database in a visual UI and table desktop application.
So you can install this, run the instructions.
It's pretty simple.
In this case, we have everything installed.
Once you have that installed, you can open up NoSQL Workbench.
Now, the main thing you just want to take a look at, you can ignore everything.
You just have to look at Operation Builder.
I already have these connections.
I'm just going to delete them so I can redo it.
What you want to do is see Operation Builder.
You go to Add Connection.
And you want to select DynamoDB Local.
Right now, it's not going to work.
Once we set up our database, we're going to come back to this.
We're going to hit Connect when we're ready.
And it's going to show us the data that we have in our database.
We just don't have our backend set up, so it's not going to work yet.
All right.
So that's probably more setup that you probably don't want to do.
So we can finally, finally go back to our backend.
Now, as you can see, we actually have the database.
There's nothing stored in here right now.
But that is where we did a database path.
That's how we can use that.
So now we can finally, finally write our code for the backend.
So I'm going to create a new folder.
And I'm going to call this server.
And then from here, I'm going to open up our terminal.
I'm going to close out the terminal, go to our parent directory via cd --.
And I'm going to do cd server like so.
Inside here, I'm going to do npm init -y.
So we set up our package JSON.
And I'm going to install a number of packages.
So I'm going to do npm i @awsstk/client-dynamoDB.
So this allows us to access AWS SDK and DynamoDB.
I'm also going to install AWS SDK body parser to parse our request for Express.
And then we're also going to install Express.
And then cores.env for environment variables.
Helmet for a little bit of security.
Morgan for logging our backend API calls.
Dynamoose for DynamoDB style.
It makes it -- it's kind of like Mongoose if you ever use MongoDB.
Provides an easy way to validate your database.
And UUID for unique IDs.
And then from there, we're going to install a number of dev dependencies.
So npm i -D.
We're going to do rim ref.
This will allow us to run a few things simultaneously for our scripts.
Same thing with concurrently.
Nodemon for a development server.
So it automatically updates.
ts node for TypeScript.
Then TypeScript itself.
And then a number of types, which is going to be @types/cores.
@types/express.
@types/morgan.
@types/node.
@types/uuid.
Then from here in our server directory, we're going to create a new folder.
We're going to call this source.
This is where all our code files will exist.
And I'm going to create a new file.
Call this index.ts.
We're going to import a number of things that we already installed.
So express from express like so.
Import .env from .env like this.
Import body parser from body parser.
Import cores from cores.
Import helmet from helmet.
Import morgan from morgan like that.
And then import star, meaning everything, as dynamos from dynamos like so.
And then we're going to leave a comment saying route imports.
So I accidentally hit a hotkey.
Don't worry about that.
And then I'm going to add configurations.
And this is where we're going to have all the middleware set up.
So .env.config.
And from here, I'm going to set is production.
And we're going to set an environment variable called process.env.node_env.
And we're going to say that is equal to production.
We're going to keep it like that.
And I'm just going to say if is production, then we're going to say dynamos.aws.ddb.local.
So this is just basically set up our dynamos.
And this is all we need to do if you want to use the local dynamos database.
Once we have that, we can set up our other middleware.
So our express.
And then we're going to do app.use with express.json.
And then app.use_helmet.
If I can spell that correctly.
App.use_helmet.crossorigin resource_policy.
Put the policy colon cross dash origin.
App.use Morgan and put common as well.
App.use.
Now typically, you would normally just like copy this.
Or you can use AI to like make the code writing faster.
That's what I would use.
But I'm just writing this out just for you guys.
Because I know you guys like just following along sometimes.
So body parser.url encoded.
We're going to put extended colon false.
And then app.use_cores like so.
And then from here, I'm going to set up routes and say app.get/recres.
And we just use this particular route as home route.
So we can just check if everything is working.
And I'm just going to say hello world.
And I'm going to create our server as well.
And I'm going to say port is equal to process.env.port will be 3000 like so.
And if it is, I'm going to say port is equal to process.env.port.
Not production basically.
So if it's local, we're going to do app.listen to our port.
We're going to make sure everything runs.
We're going to say console.log server running on port with the port variable.
And I did make a mistake up here.
This should be exclamation.
So it's not production as well right there.
So there you go.
And then we also need to set up the environment variables.
So I'm going to create a new file, call this .env.
And we are going to set up a number of ports.
We're going to do port 8001 because our database is running on port 8000.
And then I'm going to also set up an environment variable, node_env_development like so.
With that, we have most of our back end set up.
But we're going to go to our package.json.
Inside the package.json, I'm going to get rid of the test script.
We're going to write a build script.
We're going to use rimref, dist, and npx-tsc.
By the way, the reason why we use rimref, which is just a way to make easy to delete
directories and also their contents like everything in that folder recursively.
And this is cross-platform compatible.
So for Windows and Mac, it will delete the folder dist and run TypeScript.
And the way our folder structure will be set up is that our source directory is going to
include all our TypeScript files.
But because we don't use, we're not using like webpack with Next.js, which automatically
handles all of this TypeScript compilation into JavaScript, we have to kind of set this
up ourselves.
So what we do is basically we're writing a script that will take all our TypeScript
files in our source directory, create a folder called dist that will include all the files
that we have from TypeScript, but into JavaScript.
So this needs to, anytime we build it, we need to remove everything from the dist folder.
And then we run npx-tsc.
So that is compiling our TypeScript.
And then as we continue along, we're going to write all the commands that are necessary.
So the first thing we want to do is have a command for start.
So we do npm run build and node dist/index.js.
So anytime we want to actually run our server, we're going to build it.
So run this command and then we run node dist index.js because there's going to be a folder
called dist and our index.js that got compiled from index.ts will become index.js in our
dist directory.
And then we're also going to have a dev script.
This is going to be very similar.
We're going to do npm run build, but we're going to use concurrently to run our TypeScript
file.
So we're going to do /npx-tsc-w/"/nodemon.
We're going to run double dash execute ts-node source/index.ts/".
It is a little tricky to get these values right, so you can look at the repo and just
copy it if you need to.
But basically what's happening is we're running tsc, so we're compiling the TypeScript
files, but we're also running nodemon to make sure we watch the source index for any
changes.
So anytime we make changes to our directory, nodemon is going to redevelop the server so
we don't have to turn off the server and rerun it again just so we get changes.
So it automatically will watch for changes.
And we're going to have a command called seed.
So we're going to do ts-node source/seed/seed-dynamo-db.typescript.
So basically this will run our seed script from our Dynamo database.
And if you remember, we have our asset download.
We also have our folders for servers that we can pass in.
And inside this, we're going to have a seed file with seed-dynamo-db.ts.
But before we do that, let's set up the TypeScript file or TypeScript installation.
So we're going to run npx tsc --init in our server directory.
That will create a tsconfig.json.
And what we want to do is configure a few things.
So I'm going to search up module.
And in here, I'm going to change this to node-next.
I'm going to uncomment module resolution, and that should be node-next as well.
We're going to go to resolve json-module.
Uncomment this out.
And then finally, we're going to go to out directory.
And this should be /dist.
And we're going to go all the way down.
And at the very end, before in between these closing braces, we're going to write include.
We want to make sure we include all these files so we can access all of them.
And then we're going to have source/data**/*.json.
So we get all the seed files.
And we're going to leave it like that.
All right.
With that, we have all of that set up.
Now we can move these folders into our server directory.
So in our source, we're just going to drag all three of these folders into our source directory.
And I will explain what all of these are.
So here in our models directory, this represents each schema that we talked about earlier.
So if we go back over here, this is the schema of each data model.
And we have one for a course, transaction, user course progress.
And for each of these, we're going to have different schemas as well.
So this is the main one.
It basically identifies what we want.
So if teacher_id, if we say it's required true, so that if we want to insert data,
it's going to force us to put teacher_id.
So we can put required true.
You can put the different types.
And in the link in the description, you can check out what the documents are saying about
Dynamos.
It's very similar to Mongoose.
It has different strings or different, you know, like different types.
So make sure you look at this if you want some details on it and what's happening.
But that is basically our models.
I didn't want to go through it and write this in front of you because it takes kind of
quite some time.
But we also have the seed file.
So seed, we actually need to install Pluralize.
So I'm just copy that npm pluralize.
Download that.
That should make this okay.
But it does seem like we need to install the dev types.
So you can do npm i --save-dev or capital D if you want, @type/Pluralize.
And that should take care of this linting error.
So once you have this, you're going to see this particular page.
And this is going to allow us to seed our database.
Now, you don't have to worry about everything that's going on.
But basically what happens is we're going to have a bunch of seed data.
So this is just mock data, just so we can actually look at when we get to our website,
we have a list of courses, a list of information that we can use on the front end.
And we're just going to seed that into our database so that we don't have to worry about
having fake or, you know, creating the data, make it so that it's easier for development.
So in the seed function, we're just going to delete all the database.
We're just going to create the tables and make sure everything works.
And then finally, we just have a bunch of utils function because this would take too long for me
to go through every single thing.
So this will just be a couple functions that are just going to be automatically written.
And with that, let's try running our server.
So I'm going to write npm run dev.
And as you can see, we have our dist folder, which should basically work.
And while we don't have a UI to check this, we can use curl,
which will allow us to make an API call from the terminal.
And I'm just going to do HTTP colon slash local host colon 8001.
Open this up so you can see what I'm doing.
And I'm going to hit enter.
And what you should receive back is "Hello world!"
And we should be able to see this request, which is from Morgan.
It shows our request, get HTTP 1.1 status 200, meaning it was a successful API call.
And that is our server in action.
So that's how you test back in APIs.
You can use curl, but you can also use a tool called Postman.
A lot of people like using Postman for testing back in APIs.
I don't personally use it that much, but it's up to you.
This gives you a very more extensive way to call your back end.
So HTTP slash slash local host colon 8001.
And you can just hit send to make sure it's a get request.
And you should be able to see "Hello world!" right here.
So it's up to you if you want to try this out.
It gives you kind of a UI to make API calls to your back end if you need to.
So there's that.
Now with all that, now we can create our API endpoints for our back end.
So we're going to start with the course controller.
So in our source directory, we're going to create a new folder.
We're going to call this course-- actually, sorry, controllers.
And we're going to create a new file.
And we're going to call this course controller dot ts.
And by the way, this is the way you would normally structure your back end code.
You have generally a controllers.
This is where all your logics exist.
And then you have models where this is a structure of your models.
It depends on your database, of course.
And then you're going to have a folder called routes, which we'll create soon.
And then finally, you'll have all of them routed to the index page.
This is a typical setup.
There might be some variations to this.
But this is generally how you would organize a back end.
It's pretty structured.
It's not like the front end where it gets much more chaotic.
Back end tends to be more structured when it comes to the back, the folder structures,
essentially.
So we're going to go to our controller.
Let's close out everything so we can just focus on course controller.
And we're going to start with export const list courses.
And I'm going to do async because this will be an async function.
We're going to do rec with request.
And that should come from Express for our typings.
And then res with response.
And that should also come from Express as well.
And we're going to give this a promise with a void.
And we're going to use an arrow function.
Inside here, I'm going to do const category.
And we're going to do rec.query like so.
And by the way, when we list our courses, there's going to be a category value that
comes from the front end, which we can do all or a specific type of category.
And we are going to use that in a try catch block.
So we're going to do const courses is equal to category.
And if category is not equal to all, we are going to make request to our Dynamoose database.
So we're going to do a wait.
And we are going to bring in the model of course like that.
And we are going to run the scan function, which will grab the back end.
And we can filter it based on category, making sure it's equivalent to the category value.
And we're going to execute that.
This is if the category exists.
Otherwise, if it doesn't exist, we're just going to grab the entire course database.
So we're going to do course.scan exec and that executes the entire scan of the course
table and just grab all that information.
And once we're done, we're going to do res.json.
So we're just going to return a message.
And we're just going to say courses retrieved successfully.
And we want to pass in data courses.
Now, if you take a look, this is a good way to structure your endpoint.
We have a message that we can send to the front end that you can use to display if you
want to use it for something like notifications or, you know, like alert toast messages.
We're going to be using this message for that value.
And then the data is going to be the actual data, of course.
And then from here, we're going to do a catch block in case there is some issue trying to
fetch from the database.
We're going to set res.stat is 500.
And we're going to say JSON and we're going to give it a message of error retrieving courses.
And we're going to pass in error.
It's good to have a message that describes where it messed up so you understand that
this is what you created and this is where it basically messed up in your back end.
OK, so that's pretty straightforward.
List courses is nothing too difficult.
We're also going to create a function to grab a single course.
So we're going to do export const get course.
And this is just to grab a single course if we need to.
And we're going to do async again.
We're actually just going to copy this entire thing right here to make it easier.
And you know what?
Actually, let's just copy this entire thing inside here.
To make our lives easy, and then we could just replace everything we need.
So for a get course, we're going to actually use a params instead of a query string.
Now, if you're unfamiliar with query versus params, so query strings, let's say you have
a path, it kind of looks like this.
This is a query string where you have a path question mark.
And you'll see something like key one is equal to a value.
Key two is equal to a value.
And this is generally for more optional parameters.
So sometimes you don't need it.
Whereas path parameters, which is what we have, rec dot params looks more like this.
So you'll have it with a slash and it's part of the URL string.
And a lot of times this is more for, you know, this is basically required.
And in get course, you obviously need rec dot params because we need an ID to grab the
specific type of course information that we want.
So it is more required versus a category, which is much more optional in this regard.
So speaking of rec dot params, we need course ID, which we grab from the rec dot params.
Inside our try block, we're going to put a course and we're going to await course dot
get course ID.
So this just grabs the course specifically with the course ID pretty straightforward.
And we obviously want to check if the course does not exist.
We want to do res dot status 404, which generally means something was not found.
So we're going to say course not found that gets sent to the front end and we are going
to return and exit out.
Otherwise, we're going to say course with the singular retrieve successfully and we
want to pass in singular course.
And we want to change this error retrieving course to be singular as well.
Pretty straightforward.
These two are pretty simple.
It's going to get complicated eventually, but for now we're keeping it simple.
So now we have these controllers, which includes the logic, but we also need to create the
routes.
So we're going to create a folder.
We're going to call this routes and we're going to pass in a new file called this course
routes dot TS.
And for something like this, we need to import express, especially because we're using
multiple files.
When you use multiple files, you're going to use router is equal to express dot router.
So this allows us to divert the different routes that we have for our back end.
And all we have to do is router dot get and we're just going to put a slash comma list
courses.
So that is going to be grabbed from a course controller.
So now this is not this is right now it's saying it's the home route, but we're going
to have an entry point for this later on.
And then we're also going to do router dot get do slash colon course ID like so.
And we want to import get course as well.
Make sure you use IntelliSense for all of this to make it easier.
And finally, we're just going to do export default router.
Once we have this, we can then go to the index file.
And this is where we can have an entry point for this category of routes.
So when we create these course routes, this is specifically routes for course controllers.
So this is a very specific category of routes that we have.
And I can just say app dot use slash courses and we can import course routes, which will
have to manually do it up here.
So I'm going to import course routes from dot slash routes slash course routes from
our endpoint.
So basically, to hit our endpoint, we are going to hit the slash courses, which can
involve hitting this endpoint.
So if I just write, let's actually just call this.
I just want to show you we're going to use curl HTTP colon slash slash local host colon
8001 slash courses.
So we're going to say courses retrieved successfully.
But right now, the data is empty because we have not seeded our data.
So that is exactly how you would hit your courses.
Now, if you wanted to hit the get course, you would pass in.
You would pass in slash, you know, some whatever ID of the course right here.
But we need to seed our data first.
So let's do that.
Now, seeding data always makes me a bit nervous because every single time I've encountered
a lot of issues trying to see data.
But let's give this a shot.
So right now we have this seed function.
I created the seed file.
You don't have to worry about what's happening here.
But so let's try running it.
NPM run seed.
See what happens.
So we have table deleted course.
Created initialized transaction user course progress.
Created course as well.
And we have successfully seeded all our data.
So hopefully that worked out.
And for us to check, we can actually go and finally open up our NoSQL workbench.
We're going to add a connection.
Click DynamoDB local.
Make sure it's set to port 8000.
We're going to hit connect.
We're then going to hit open.
And if it's successful, we should be able to see course transaction.
And user course progress.
So perfect.
Everything is working as possible.
Just FYI, it is possible you might have some issues with seeding database.
Hopefully this code works out because seeding has never been easy for me to get correct.
Because the data is always kind of messed up or there's some random issue that occurs.
So do your best to try and resolve what you can for seeding the database.
Hopefully it just works off right off the bat.
Once we have this, now we have seed data.
And actually, yeah, it was already running.
So there's a little no point.
So I'm going to open up another terminal.
You just only have to have one server.
I accidentally had two servers running.
So I'm just going to do curl HTTP colon slash slash local host colon 8001 slash courses.
And that should basically give us our course list.
So now this is very unreadable.
And that's why, you know, curl is not very useful in this regard.
But if you were to go to postman, I can do slash courses.
We should be able to send.
And now we can see in a very nice formatted way of all the course information that we have over here.
And this basically should reflect what we have in our seed data.
So right here is exactly what we should be seeing.
And if we actually wanted to see the other endpoints, so we have slash courses.
We also want to do course ID.
So if I grab this first one, we should be able to get this specific course.
And only that one.
So it's a little bit jumbled.
We can just instead use our postman.
To send.
Yeah.
And as you can see, this is only one course.
When we grab the courses, we're just getting that single course.
So everything is working as expected.
And now, since we have finally set up our back end, we have our courses endpoint.
We can now go back to our front end.
So we're going to close all of these.
Close up server.
Now we're going to go to our source directory.
So now we need a way to call our back end.
And that is where Redux Toolkit query comes into play.
And that exists in our API directory.
So API file, I mean.
So in our API.ts, we can go to our endpoints.
So this is exactly where you would place API calls.
So now, as we have seen, we have .env.local.
This is the endpoint that we reach.
But these endpoints will tack on whatever URL that we want.
And it's, in a way, abstracted away for you.
And it makes the code pretty nice to use.
So in the endpoints, I'm going to call this list or get courses.
And we're going to do build.query.
And inside the build.query, this is what we are going to receive from the back end.
So in this type, this is the type that we get from the back end.
And what we need to send is going to be on the second part of this query.
And this is going to be category with a question mark colon string.
And we're going to close this.
And we're going to do curly braces with query like so.
And inside here, we're going to pass in the category,
which is what we're going to pass in when we call this particular hook inside the component.
We'll come to it.
But for now, let's build this out.
We are going to set the URL to be courses.
So basically, this part right here is going to be tacked onto the URL local host right here.
So it will tack on courses like this when we make this particular endpoint API call.
And then from here, we want to send the params to be category.
So this is going to come from where we call this basic hook that gets created from Redux toolkit.
And we pass that into the params for our query string.
And then finally, we have provides tags.
And we want to set this to be courses within a string.
So I forgot a comma here.
So make sure you have that in the tag types.
We are going to add courses as well right here.
So essentially, what these tag types are,
they basically represent the data that we receive from the back end.
So when we do get courses, we're getting a list of courses.
And we are saving it to a tag of courses.
This will be important when we do invalidation of courses.
But we'll talk about that a little later.
And then over here in our export const, we're going to write use get courses query.
So the standardization of this tag name is pretty simple.
You have get courses.
So all you have to do is add a use with a prefix and query for the suffix.
Now while we're here, we'll do the same thing for the get course.
So this is for the single one.
This time, we're just going to copy the build query like we did.
But this is not going to be an array.
And also, we're just going to pass in a string when we make the API call.
So query is going to be ID.
And the path is going to be courses slash ID like this.
So this is how we make an API call to the back end.
Remember when we did courses slash the ID value, this is how we grab it.
And we're going to do provides tags like so.
And actually, let's not use that.
In telesense, we're going to do result error ID like so.
And what we're going to do is we're going to do basically an array.
And we are going to do type courses.
And we are going to do ID.
Now this may be a little confusing.
But basically, what happens is that when we grab the course,
we are going to find the type of courses for the tags.
But we're going to find one that has the exact ID of the get course.
And the reason why we need to specify this is so that when we grab this course,
if we grab it individually, it's going to update the course values automatically on the front end.
So basically, when we grab the list of courses, and then we call get course,
it's going to update that specific course in this list.
So it's a way of doing invalidation that makes life a lot easier.
And this is similar to React query.
So it's not anything that different from React query, if you're just confused.
But it is pretty much identical.
And we're just going to do use get course query as well.
And that's that.
That's how you can make an API call.
So we want to do from here to make the API call, I'm going to go to components or actually
app page, we're going to go to the landing page.
And we're going to scroll up, we're going to do const data, courses is loading, is error.
And we're going to grab use get course is query that we created the plural one,
I'm going to pass an empty array.
And by doing so, we can grab the courses value.
So for now, let's console log this and see what we have on the front end.
Now you're seeing this linting error, mostly because it's just not being used.
But let's check this out.
So I put the browser over here.
Right now, we're not running the front end,
we're running the back end, but we're not running the front end.
So I'm going to go back to our parent directory,
go into our client, and I'm going to run npm run dev.
All right, so now when you have the server running, we're going to open up our dev tools,
you can do it via alt command I, if you're using browser or a brave browser or Chrome.
So you have it up here, you can see that we have our courses object,
courses retrieved successfully.
And in the data object, we have our list of images,
we have all of this information, including enrollments, sections,
and all of these chapters.
So we have our entire course object successfully.
Now, I want to warn you about something weird,
is that you also see courses undefined inside the terminal.
So we're basically grabbing the courses information on the next JS server side.
So why is that?
So if you understand how next JS works, is that this component gets run two times,
it gets run on the server.
And it also gets run on the client side.
So before it goes to the client, like to the user,
it runs this entire component as well.
But it cannot fetch courses on the server side.
So instead, we're fetching the data when this application is hit on the front end,
and then we grab the courses information after that.
That's how we grab it.
Now, we're not going to go into next JS details where you can do server side components,
or server components, and you're fetching the data on the server side.
We're going to stick with Redux toolkit query,
and we're going to do everything client side.
I will have a video on explaining next JS why sometimes it's okay to do something like this,
and it's not that detrimental to your performance or any of that.
You don't need to.
It really isn't completely necessary unless you need big performance gains.
Otherwise, it adds a lot of development overhead and complicates things in many different areas.
There's a reason why a lot of people complain about it.
But either way, we're sticking with this pattern for now.
So now, I want to bring your attention to the console.
So now, if you see the courses, we have this data.
So now, if you do course, the reason why it's set up to be courses.data,
which is kind of inconvenient to use.
And this is kind of the part where I really like Redux toolkit query.
It makes it so much easier to do this on a complete scale.
So if I were to go to this base query, we can actually format this across all our endpoints
because all our endpoints is going to have that structure where we have the data object.
So let's go back to our controller.
When we set this, we have a message and a data.
But we also want to, when we grab the data,
we always want to just grab the course information.
For example, like this, we don't want to write courses.data.
We just want to use the courses information directly.
And the way you can do that is if you were to go over here into this base query,
we can actually just define our own custom base query up here.
And we're just going to use orgs.
So when you set this up, you're just going to grab different types.
So we can make this basically work.
Right now, we're just dealing with types for this.
Do extra options with an empty object.
And we're going to do an arrow function.
From here, I'm going to set the base query to be the same thing.
So we're just going to copy this over.
We're going to set this up so we have the base query and the base URL just like this.
Now, right now, we can do a try and then we can do a result,
which will grab information from the back end.
So anytime we make an endpoint like a get courses call,
it's going to run through this custom base query.
And it's going to apply it to every single endpoint.
So both get courses and get course, this will basically be a custom version.
So we can modify it to whatever we want.
So right here, we're going to do args API, extra options like so.
And typically, if you just want the same results, we can just do return results.
So this will basically make it so nothing has changed.
Let's just make sure we do catch error is going to be unknown.
We just want to make sure the error message works out.
So we're going to do error instance of error.
These are just this is just error handling in the proper practice.
So we're just going to give this unknown error if none of this works out,
because we can't always predict what the error message is going to be.
So we're going to give it a status of fetch underscore error.
And error is going to be error message.
Now, you don't have to worry about what this is happening.
It's just error handling.
It's up to you on how to handle it.
So right now, this will give us the exact same result that we have already been doing.
But let's say if we wanted to do what we mentioned before,
where the data is going to be the actual result,
we can just set this to result data and we can set this to be result data data.
So basically, it unwraps our data directly.
And by the way, should actually copy this.
Some of the typing is incorrect.
So create API and fetch base query should be correct.
But not for this right here.
We should remove slash react.
We can move create API, fetch base query from that
and remove fetch args and base query API like this.
And we can just change this to be any because it's causing issues.
And finally, what we need to do to actually use that custom base query,
we're going to write custom base query like this, save it.
And if we go back to our courses object, refresh.
Now, we should actually see this is our data.
We no longer have the message.
We don't need the message.
But we just have the array of objects right here.
And that's exactly what we want.
And that's why I really like Redux toolkit query.
Now, you can do the same thing in Zestand,
but it's just a little more boilerplate.
A lot of this is kind of structured in to Redux toolkit query.
Makes it very easy to do.
All right.
So now we can go back to our landing page
and we can continue on with our courses information.
So we can go down to our landing courses section.
And inside the courses display,
now we can actually put the courses as well.
And if courses exist, we are going to grab the first four courses just for easy sake.
Typically, you would hand code, figure out which courses that you want to feature.
So that's just dependent on what you want to do.
But in this case, we're just going to show the first four courses.
We're going to do a course index with an arrow function, pass in motion.div.
So back to our animation, I'm going to go back up, copy these values again.
So we don't have to write it and we're going to pass in a key.
The key is going to be course.courseId, like so.
And we're going to change a few things.
So opacity is going to be zero,
but we want this to be moved up 50.
So 50 from the bottom and it goes up 50 pixels.
So while in view, it's going to go to its supposed final destination.
Transition is going to be a duration of 0.5.
But because we have a list, we can say delay with index multiplied by 0.2.
So that means every single course gets delayed 0.2 seconds.
And for this, we don't need once.
We're just going to have it repeat anytime we want.
So the viewport amount is going to be 0.4, which is a nice good number.
We're going to get rid of class name for this one.
And we're just going to put random text over here.
And you can see that we have a little bit of a cool animation going on.
But we want to display the course information.
So we're going to create a course card.
And we're going to call this search because we're going to have multiple course cards as well.
So in here, we are going to have a course.
And we're going to pass in the course information that we grabbed
and from the course data that we retrieved.
So let's create that.
So we're going to go back, go to our components directory.
I'm going to create a new file.
And the reason why we're creating it over here is because we're going to use this component
in two different spots.
So anytime we reuse any kind of component, we're putting it in the components directory.
So I'm going to start with RAFCE with course card search.
And inside here, it's going to take a couple parameters.
We're going to check if course width is selected and on click.
So it's going to take three props.
And we are going to pass in search course card props, which is already created.
Now, by the way, I haven't explained this, but these types are created from the index.d.ts
that we transferred earlier because I did not want to focus on writing all of these
type typings, which is kind of annoying to do on a tutorial.
And it's not very instructive for me to just spend time on doing so.
So we have that.
Inside our return, we are going to pass in a number of things.
So on click is going to be right here.
So we're going to have an on click handler that we passed in from the component props.
We're also going to have a class name.
We're going to pass in course card search.
And we're going to group this with the class.
And we're going to make sure if it is selected.
And this is for situations where we are on the search page.
So right now we're on the landing page.
So is selected is not a relevant prop.
But when we're on the selected page, we'll come to it where we will use this.
But we're going to create this right now.
So we're going to say course card, course card search to be selected like so.
And we are going to say course card search.
And this is if it's unselected.
So we'll have two different stylings for selection versus unselected.
Inside here, we're going to have a div with class name of course card search.
And an image container.
And we're going to have an image tag or image element from next image.
And we're going to pass in source with course dot image.
And we're just going to put placeholder dot png.
Now it doesn't exist, but you can add it if you want.
So it's like a backup image.
And we're going to pass in course dot title for the alt.
Give it a fill property.
And if you remember, we're going to use sizes for optimization purposes.
We're going to put max width of 768 pixel for 100 viewport width.
Max width of 1200 pixel for 50 viewport width, 33 viewport width.
And then class name is going to be course card search.
Let's actually copy this so we don't have to write it every single time.
And we're going to do double underscore image.
And we're going to make a self-closing tag for the image like that.
So I know we still have an error happening, but we're going to continue.
We're going to create and finish this course card.
Finish this out.
So we're going to start with the class name.
Paste that course card search.
Double underscore with content.
And inside here, we're going to give it a div with h2 class name.
Pass in the search double underscore title.
Pass in course dot title for the h2.
And then have a p tag.
We're going to do class name, course card search, double underscore description.
And then we're going to pass in course dot description like this.
And then continue forward.
We're going to do div class name with margin top of 2.
Close this out with the p tag.
Class name is equal to course card search again with teacher.
And we're going to do by course dot teacher name like so.
We don't need that.
And on the next line, we're just going to do div again.
Class name is equal to course card search footer.
And we're going to pass in a span with class name, course card search, price.
Like so.
And it should be format price, which is going to be a util that we have.
It's going to format the course into the proper values.
So it's just a very convenient function.
I don't want to spend time doing that.
And then we're also going to have another span with class name, course card search,
enrollment.
And over here, I'm going to say course enrollment, question mark dot length.
Enrolled.
So that will set up our entire course card.
So right now, it is still showing an error because if we go back here, we are missing some props.
And the only prop we're basically missing is going to be the on click handler.
So when you click on the course over here, if you see this pages, when you click it,
it should take you to the search page.
And it should take you to specifically the course ID with the query string on that page.
So it will be selected on this page, but we haven't created that page yet.
But let's create the route handling just for that.
So let's open this up.
And I'm going to go up here right under landing.
We're going to give a function called handle course click.
Like so.
And inside here, we're going to pass in course ID with the string type with an arrow function.
And we are going to do router dot push, which we have not defined yet.
It's going to be slash search question ID is equal to dollar sign course ID.
Now, the router should come from next JS.
So we're going to do router is equal to use router from next router.
We're going to execute that.
And that should give us router dot push.
And we should go down and we can finally go over here to course guard search.
We're going to do on click handle course click, and we can just pass that in.
And actually, this needs to be an arrow function because we need to be able to pass in the course.
So I'm going to do course dot course ID like so.
And we are getting this error, and that's because we are using the wrong one.
So this is next router, but next navigation should be the correct one.
And there we go.
We have another different error.
So we need to import course card search from at components course card search.
And even with all that, we're going to get this particular error.
And that's because let's go over here.
That's because we need to configure this hosting URL because these are remote images.
So let's open up our directory in our client directory.
We're going to create a new file.
We're going to call this next dot config dot JS.
And I'm going to write this weird comment thing right here.
Let's close this.
And then we're going to do at type import parens next dot next config like this.
And over here, I'm going to say const next config is equal to an object.
We're going to say images with remote patterns with an array.
And we're going to say protocol is going to be HTTPS comma host name with images dot pexels dot
com because this is where we're getting the image.
It's just a free image that we're just using.
And we're going to give it a port with empty string path name with slash star star.
So it allows all the path from the host name.
And we're going to do module dot exports is equal to next config.
And then we're going to save that.
If we open up our server, let's try refreshing it.
Let's refresh it one more time.
And now we can see we have our course list.
Everything is all perfect.
We have the animations.
If we scroll up here, we can see that if we refresh it, we're going to see these courses.
Now, we don't see the loading skeleton, but let's actually implement the loading skeleton this time.
So if you go down here, I'm going to do if is loading.
And by the way, we have react to query with is loading.
So that determines when the courses are being received from the back end.
We're going to pass in the loading skeleton.
And we can see save it.
And see that we have our skeleton coming in.
So if you refresh it, you can see it's not exactly what we saw earlier.
So if I go over here, there's actually a class name that we need to add.
I'm going to go over here, right.
BG gray 700.
And this is part of the tailwind skeleton.
So if you look at here, this is in the UI.
We just need to add that specific thing.
And now if I refresh it, now you should be able to see everything in terms of the skeleton working out.
Refresh it.
It looks pretty nice.
So now there's a couple of things I want to actually add.
So if I go to the app layout page, like the root, there's actually one thing I wanted to do
is if I go into div right here, just to make everything consistent,
we want to add a class of root layout.
So this is just going to be applied on our entire application.
Yeah.
By the way, this layout file, it applies to the entire application.
So if you have any styling there, it's going to apply it.
Now, right now, it's not going to really change anything because most of it's there.
All right.
And then one more thing, I want to add a layout page for non-dashboard.
So this will apply to every single page, not just the search page,
because right now we have this set up in our home page.
So that's only for home page.
But if we wanted to create a search page, so I'm eventually going to have a folder called search.
I want a layout that mimics exactly that because we need the non-dashboard
navbar over here and we want to apply that for every single page.
So going back to over here, let's actually just copy this entire thing,
paste it over here in this non-dashboard, and we're going to give it a layout.
And we're going to pass in children like so.
Give it children with react.react node like this.
And inside of here, it's going to be children like this.
So we don't need to pass in landing.
And so if we go to /landing page, we should see the exact same layout.
And there's one thing that I did mess up once again in non-dashboard navbar.
If you see this area right here under book open, there's four closing divs.
One of these divs should actually be near the end like this.
When you save it, this navbar should be the same width as the rest of the page.
So it was just like a small mishap.
I always have some issues with that.
All right.
So from here, we're going to handle the search page.
So in our finished application, if you hit search for courses,
you're going to see this particular page.
What's going to happen is on larger screens, you're going to see multiple courses.
And then responsive, it's going to be one.
But over here is going to be a selected course.
When you are on the search page, it's going to show the first selected course.
But if you click on the second one, you're going to see the ID being passed
once you click on one of these search.
And you can also go back over here, go to featured courses.
You click and you can see that the search ID has been selected.
And we can go to this particular page.
We're also going to create this nice little accordion that shows each of these sections.
And just remember, all of this information is coming from the backend.
So it's pretty nice that we are connected to a backend that is not managed.
This is we are managing the backend ourselves.
So let's get started.
So to start off, we're going to go to the search page and we are going to create a page over here.
We're going to do RFCE and put search like this.
And over here, we're going to grab the search params.
Let me open this up like this.
We're going to grab the search params so we can grab it from the URL.
And then we're going to identify the ID via searchparams.get.
So this is all part of next.
And you can grab the ID value from the URL.
We always want to grab the URL and grab information from the URL.
So sometimes you can use the URL in Next.js as your own as a state.
Instead of using Redux or instead of using local state,
you want to use the URL state because it's a lot more reliable to do so.
From here, we're going to grab courses.
Is loading, is error.
And we're going to use the same function that we called earlier using use get queries.
We're going to pass in an empty object to grab the courses information.
And then finally, we're going to create a state.
And we're going to call this selected course because this is going to save the selected
course information.
And we're going to set use state like so with course null.
And we're going to pass in the null value over here.
Now use state is not defined.
So we're going to pass that in.
And finally, we're going to grab the router because we want to
change pages if we click on one of the search courses.
So we're going to grab it from next navigation as well.
Now you see all these underscore that's from our linting that they're not being used.
But it's OK.
So here to do with the situation where we have a course ID, if the course ID exists,
we're going to set that one as the selected course.
But if it doesn't have any search, we are going to set the first course as a selected
option.
And the way we do this is we're going to use use effect.
Now, personally, I always try to minimize the amount of use effect.
And this is one of the situations where, you know, I could use the params.
But sometimes it is easier, especially in a situation like this, to use use effect because
use effect is problematic because you run into a lot of asynchronous issues.
If you have too many use effects, they can coin conflict and cause a lot of problems.
So you have to be very careful.
And you always want to try to minimize.
You can't avoid it completely, obviously, but you always want to minimize the number
of use effect hooks that you have in your react components.
So basically, if the courses exist, but also if the ID exists, we're going to say we grab
the courses and we're going to find the course ID that we have.
So we are going to grab the course ID and see if it is equal to the ID we have in the
search params.
So we're going to find that specific course, get that information, and we're going to
set the selected course as the value.
Otherwise, we are going to set the courses to be zero if it doesn't exist.
If for whatever reason, it has problems finding it.
Otherwise, if the ID does not exist, like we said, we are going to set selected course
to be the first value or the first course in the courses array.
And finally, we want to add some dependencies.
We're going to add courses.
So it'll rerun anytime these values change.
So anyways, from here, we want to make sure that the courses are loaded.
So we're going to have an is loading state and we're going to return and we're going
to create a component called loading.
Now you could put text or you can customize the loading component, but we're going to
have a default loading component for every situation that will make it look nice.
And even though it's not going to be very specific for what's loading, this is going
to show us a loading spinner and it's super easy to create.
So in the components folder, I'm going to create loading that TSX.
Inside here, I'm going to do RAFCE as usual.
I'm going to give this a class name with loading like this.
And in here, I'm going to bring in loader two from Lucide React.
So it's basically an icon, but we're going to give it a class name of loading double
underscore spinner.
So this is just going to spin and animate the loader icon.
And this will make a very nice little effect and will give us a very nice loading component
that's super easy and we can put this anywhere.
And we also want the text of loading dot dot dot.
So we have this class name loading text.
So if we have this, we can now pass in this loading component.
Make sure we import that.
Now, if we go to the search page.
We have this error use rather that just means we need to set this to be used client.
And I'm just going to show you how that is the loading spinner looks like.
So if you take a look, we have a very convincing loading screen or a loading icon.
And this is very nice because it's so simple and it works in any kind of situation.
So we're just going to remove that.
And in here, we also want to get check for errors.
So we're going to say is error and we are going to say if courses does not exist, we're
going to return div failed to fetch courses like so.
Now, inside here, I'm going to select both of these with alt.
I'm going to write motion dot.
Div and we are going to import framer motion.
So let me just move this out so we have more space.
We're going to import motion from framer motion, and that should quiet this guy out.
And we're going to say initial is going to be opacity of zero.
Animate with opacity of one transition with duration of zero point five and a class name
of search.
And then from here, I'm going to give this an H1 tag, say class name is equal to search
double underscore title with list of available courses.
Below this, I'm going to have an H2 tag with class name with search underscore subtitle.
We're going to call this courses dot length to give us the course length and courses available.
All right.
So from here, we're going to do div class name and we're going to do search underscore
content.
And I'm going to go to.
The landing page.
And we're going to go to the course.
Card right here.
Grab this motion div.
Paste it inside our search courses.
Now, of course, is going to cause an error because we need to fix this.
We're not going to have a key for this.
So we're going to start with the opacity of zero.
Why a 40 opacity of one?
Why have zero over here?
Transition delay should be zero point two.
And instead of while in view, we're just going to animate.
So we're just going to trigger it right away.
We don't need a viewport for this one.
And we're just going to give it a class name of search underscore courses dash grid.
And inside here, we're just going to pass in courses dot map.
Pass in a course using arrow function.
And make sure we close it with two.
Parents.
And a curly brace.
Now, of course, card search is missing a couple of things.
So we're going to say key is equal to course that course ID.
Course is being passed and now we can pass in is selected.
Now, is selected is going to be based on selected course.
Question mark that course ID.
And we're going to check if it's equal to course dot course ID like so.
So if it is the current course, we're going to pass that in.
This is going to be handle course select.
And we're going to pass in course over here.
So now let's make sure we're importing the course card search.
Now, we haven't created handle course select, which is what we are going to do right now.
So we're going to scroll up.
Right after the is loading to make sure the courses already exist.
So we're going to do handle course select.
We're going to pass in course with a course type.
With an arrow function and we are going to set selected course.
To be the course value.
And we are going to say router dot push.
So anytime we press the course.
And we pass it.
We are going to go to slash search question mark ID is equal to course.
Dot course ID.
And we're going to keep it like that.
So if we take a look right now.
What we should see is that anytime let's open it up a little more.
Anytime we select, we are going to see that the ID is being selected over here.
So by the way, if I go over here and I select it.
You should be able to go directly to that selected item.
That's exactly why you should have the state stored in the URL.
Use that state.
That is a reliable source of the state that you can use.
Now, if I were to remove that and go strictly to source or search,
you're going to have the first course being selected.
All right.
So now let's create the selected option or the selected course viewer on the right side.
So we're first going to create a function called handle enroll now.
So this is just going to be the link that we can pass.
And this is the URL that we'll go to if someone clicks the enroll now button.
Let's close this out.
So if someone clicks this enroll now, this function is going to be triggered.
So that's what we're going to create.
So we're going to do router dot push.
And we're going to set slash check out question mark.
Step is equal to one.
And I'll cover this very shortly when we do the next step.
This is very shortly when we do the checkout flow.
But for now, we're just going to keep it like this.
We're going to have course ID and show sign up is equal to false.
So we're going to have that function.
But now we can go down.
And below the first motion div, we are going to say selected course.
If that exists, we are going to grab a motion div.
We're just going to copy this over here.
Paste it.
Make sure we close the motion dot div.
And we're going to make a few adjustments, the duration and the delay.
The delay should be 0.5 seconds.
So it happens after.
And we're going to change the class name to be selected course.
Now, when you do animations, it's very nice to have like a slight delay for the second part.
So this first animates in.
If you see, let's refresh.
You're going to see that happen.
And then you see this one coming right now.
There's no there's no height because we haven't put anything in.
But that's how the animation should happen.
It's a very nice way.
It's a pleasing effect for the eye.
If something comes in sequentially.
A few seconds later or like half a second later, basically.
And now what we need to do is we're going to create like a selected course,
kind of like a card, basically just like a viewer.
One more time.
Make sure we capitalize it.
And what we're going to pass in over here is going to be the course,
like the selected course, so we can use that information.
And then also we're going to pass in the handle enrolled now,
as well as the function directly into here.
Now we just need to create this course.
All right.
So in cases like this, where you have a file structure like this,
selected course is not going to be reused in any other place.
So in this situation, generally you create a new file and you just put
select selected course.tsx.
So you can put the component directly right there and it's very convenient.
So I'm going to do RFCE, start up the selected course.
And inside here, we're going to pass in course with handle enroll now,
colon props.
We're going to do selected course props like so.
Inside here, I'm going to pass in class name as we normally do with selected
dash course.
Inside here, I'm going to give it a div,
remove the text like so.
And we're going to pass in H3 with the class name
of selected course underscore title
and course dot title like this.
And what I want to do is in the search page, we're now going to import that correctly.
Make sure we save it.
Make sure we see what we're supposed to.
So we have this.
We just have the title right now.
So we're going to be adding the rest.
From here, we're going to have a P tag.
We're going to say class name is equal to selected dash course.
And we're just going to copy it because we're going to constantly use that.
And we're going to say author.
This should be double underscore.
Close this out.
And we can just do by course dot teacher name.
And we're going to put like a little horizontal line.
Put an empty space and put a span over here.
So it's styled differently.
Pass in selected course, enroll mid dot count like so.
And we're going to pass in course dot enrollments, question mark dot length.
All right, that's good.
I'm going to copy the class name like this.
So we don't have to rewrite this every single time.
And then right below the first div, first closing div,
we're going to do class name selected course content like so.
Put a P tag, pass the selected course with description.
And we're going to do course dot description like this with a P tag.
And over here, we're going to do div class name selected course sections.
Close that out.
Put in h4 sections dash title.
We're going to put course content.
And then over here, we're going to create a separate component called accordion sections.
Now we'll come back to it because we are going to create a separate component
because we'll be reusing this accordion sections in multiple places in the application.
But for now, let's continue on finishing this card.
So class name selected should be further for this part.
We're going to do a span.
This should show the price.
We're going to bring in format price from our utils.
So like we did before with the pricing,
it's nice to have a util function that grabs the price, makes everything easy.
And then here, we are going to import from shadcn add components UI button.
And in here, we're going to pass in on click,
pass in the handle enroll now function that we created,
pass in course with course ID, pass in the class name of BG primary 700,
hover background primary 600.
So in this case, we don't really have a class for that.
And we can just pass in enroll now.
So you should see we have the title, we have the author and the course number of people enrolled,
description, course content, price, and the enroll now button.
So now we're going to have the accordion sections, as you can see here, this is pretty nice.
It's going to animate in and out very smooth.
And we'll be able to show all the sections.
Now, because we're using this and reusing this in multiple places,
we can create this accordion sections component in multiple places.
So let's start by creating this.
We're going to say accordion sections, we're going to pass in sections,
which is the course dot sections like so.
We haven't created this.
So we're going to go down to components, create a new file, accordion sections, that TSX.
And over here, I'm going to do RAFCE, have the accordion sections displayed like that.
Inside here, I'm going to pass the sections in, we're going to give it accordion sections,
props, like so.
And there should be a colon over here.
And what we're going to use is ShadCN's accordion.
So we've already installed that.
So instead of this being a div, we're going to pass in accordion,
which doesn't seem to be triggering correctly.
It's not the Radix UI we want.
We want to import accordion from at slash components slash UI slash accordion, like so.
I'm not exactly sure why the IntelliSense is not grabbing the information earlier.
So accordion should be item and accordion trigger as well.
So over here, we need to set type to be multiple with the class name of width being full.
So it takes up the entire space.
So in here, since we're passing in the sections, we need to create
each sections, we're going to map it out, pass the section in, use an arrow function like this.
And inside here, we're going to do accordion item, pass in a key with section dot section ID.
With value section dot section title and class name of accordion dash section.
Close this out.
And inside here, we're going to have the accordion trigger, which is basically what it looks like
before you open it up for each item.
We're going to give it a class name of accordion dash section double underscore trigger, like so.
So I'm going to copy this once again to make our lives easier.
And inside here, I'm going to do H5 with accordion section title.
Like so.
We're going to pass in section dot section title.
Let's see if this works out.
So we have some linting errors.
So I'm going to close this out like this.
So make sure you have double closing parens.
And we're going to go over here.
We're going to pass in the linter.
Make sure you are importing that.
And let's see if it actually displays something so far.
Yep, there we go.
We have the titles.
That's what the accordion trigger is doing with the accordion item.
But we actually need accordion content to show what's going to happen when you open it.
So I'm going to pass in accordion section.
But this time, it'll be content like so.
And inside here, we're going to have a UL tag with section dot chapters dot map.
And we're going to pass in chapter, have an arrow function.
And inside here, we're going to have a list item with key chapter dot chapter ID.
Like so.
Pass in class name.
Actually, we can just paste what we had before with chapter.
Close that up.
Bring in file text, which is an icon, just so it looks a little better.
We have class name with margin right of two with a four, height of four.
And we're going to make sure we close that.
And finally, we're going to have a span with class name text small.
And put chapter title like so.
And now we should be able to see the opening and closing of these accordions.
That's pretty nice.
All right.
So the next thing we're going to be setting up is going to be authentication.
So we're going to be using clerk authentication.
So clerk is a very nice managed authentication that makes
auth a lot easier and provides a lot of components and a lot of pre-made
assets that you can use to set up your application and provide auth and keys.
So if you take a look, here is our screenshots of the auth pages.
So these components are basically pre-made components that clerk provides.
And it makes it a lot easier because if you use one of these components,
it is pre-made with best practices built in.
And all we have to do is style it a little bit with like different colors.
And from there, you can let clerk take care of the rest.
So the first thing we want to do is we want to create a clerk account.
So you can go to the clerk page and set up your account.
So when you're signed in, you can probably create an application.
This might look a little different because I've already created an application.
So you would choose one of these options and you would choose
all the settings that you want for your application.
In our case, we just need email and basically GitHub and Google.
So a couple of those are perfect.
So now I've already created it, but you can create your application.
So if I go over here, this is what you'll see with application.
And you can go to the configure setting and you can see the settings that you have.
And you can check for authentication strategies.
Basically, I have email address with phone number canceled.
Username is not allowed.
So we're just going to use emails with password and you can have email verification code.
So a lot of these configurations make it super easy for us to set up our authentication.
So the main thing we want to look at is the API keys.
So over here, you can see that we have a publishable key and a secret key.
So right now, I'm just going to add a test key.
So at the very end, I'm just going to delete this.
But once we hit a create secret key, we're going to have this test key over here.
I'm just going to copy this.
You're never going to be able to see this once again.
Actually, you can.
You can see it.
But if you want to delete it, you can delete it.
So basically, I hit the copy and what we want to do is in our application, we're going to go.
Let's close all of this inside our dot EMV dot local.
I'm going to create next public clerk publishable key.
And also clerk underscore secret underscore key.
So I'm just going to paste my secret key, but I'm also going to copy and paste my publishable key.
And I'm going to save those.
This will be important for us to use the sign in.
Clerk is going to need these values when you're using it.
All right.
So now from here, they have a next quick start.
You can go in the link in the description if you want to follow this along.
There is multiple steps to it, but we're going to I'm going to walk you through every step.
So the first thing we're going to do is open up our terminal, close out our client server.
And we are going to run NPM I at clerk slash next JS and then at clerk slash clerk JS.
We'll be using this later and also at clerk slash theme and finally next dash themes.
So we are installing the clerk like we did or like it shows us in clerk,
but we are also adding themes because we're going to need those to style our
component a little bit easier.
And also, you got to remember, we got to do legacy dash peer dash D E P S.
And from here, I'm going to run NPM run dev once again.
Not that it really matters right now, but we are going to go close all of this out
and go to layout the main layout over here where we have the providers.
And we are going to wrap everything with the clerk provider.
So I'm going to put this around the HTML tag and I'm going to import
clerk provider from at clerk next JS.
This will provide us with the authentication and all the state that clerk provides
and makes it easier for us to use.
Now there is a middleware file that determines the routes that it basically
protects certain routes that we can configure.
So let's go to, let's go to this, this page right here where we see our entire application.
What I want to show you is the flow of the page.
So right here, these, these pages right here don't require authentication.
Actually these two right here do, but these five do not require authentication.
Whereas all of these with the user pages and the teacher pages and the second two
pages of the checkout that requires authentication.
And furthermore, we have user pages right here.
These are all the dashboard pages, but this is specifically for users, people who watch the course.
But we also have a different type of role.
And that's going to be the teachers.
These teachers will be able to create the course and they have a different set of pages,
different configurations that they will get to see if they are a teacher role.
So essentially we need to configure this so that certain pages have that authentication
and make sure that they are authenticated to go to those pages.
And that's exactly what the middleware file is going to be for.
So to do this, I'm going to close out the layout and inside the source directory, like
on the outside, we're going to create a new file called middleware.ts.
And we are going to do a number of things.
So I'm going to import clerk middleware and we're going to import create route
matcher from @clerk/nextjs/server.
And then we're also going to import next response from next/server.
Over here, I'm going to say is student route.
So this will determine all the routes that are specifically for students.
And we're going to use the create route matcher pass in in the array
with string/user/parens.n*.
And we're going to close this out like that.
And we're also going to create is teacher route.
Which is going to be similar.
So we're just going to paste that, except this is going to involve teacher.
So essentially, anytime, well, basically these routes is going to have the /user
as part of the URL and the other ones are going to be /teacher.
So we're going to make sure we route match those.
And to do this, we're going to use clerk middleware.
And we're going to use an async function with auth rec.
And we're going to have an arrow function.
And we're going to grab session claims like this.
And we're going to await the authentication.
And we're going to set user role is going to be session claims?metadata.
We're going to be storing our user type, basically whether they are a student or teacher
in the metadata.
And we'll cover that very shortly and how this will work.
But we're going to set as user type, it's going to be either student or teacher like this.
And we're going to do .user type student.
Student is will be the default user type if there is no value.
So if is student route, we're going to pass in rec.
So if user role does not equal to student.
And by the way, all of this has documentation on clerk.
So you can go in depth of how all of this works.
But over here, we're going to say if the URL, let's say new URL should be slash teacher
slash courses rec.url.
We're going to return a next response.
And we're going to redirect them to the correct URL.
So basically, we're just checking if it's a student route.
And if the user role is not student, we're going to redirect them to the teacher.
Otherwise, if it is teacher route, like so.
And if the user role is not equal to teacher, we're going to pass in the user.
We're essentially redirecting the user to the right location.
And we're just handling this all in clerk middleware, which makes it very nice and easy to do.
So over here, I'm going to do export const with config.
And we're going to set the matcher to be an array.
And over here in the clerk setup, I'm not going to type all of this out.
But right here, we're just going to grab this inside the matcher.
And we could just save it.
So with that, we basically have our user routes redirecting to the proper location.
Now, we have not created the user roles and we have not set that up.
But before we get to that, let's actually create the sign in and sign up components.
All right.
So I want to take your attention to the clerk docs components page.
So over here, there's a lot going on.
We started with Next.js full stack.
We have a documentation on those.
But over here, this is where we are going to use UI components.
So the components that we're going to be using is going to include sign in, sign up,
user button, and user profile.
So these are much more pre-made components that already have a specific look and a styling.
And it provides all the functionality you need.
If you are ever curious about what properties are needed, it's all documented pretty well
in their documentation.
Sign in and sign up are slightly different.
And then user button includes the little, you know, the navigation at the top over here,
for example, like this.
Those are user button.
User profile looks a little bit different.
But this is how you can configure the setup in clerk.
And you don't have to create these components.
It makes it a lot easier.
Now, just FYI, there is an alternative option called elements.
So this is if you really want to customize your flow for, you know, like very, very customized
components.
But it is in beta.
And it is much more safer to be able to use one of these authentication components.
And then we would use these components and style them using the appearance prop, which
is located over here.
And I will cover that as we go along.
So with that, let's actually start creating our sign in components.
So because we're going to be using the sign in component in a couple places, I'm going
to create a new file.
I'm going to call it sign in dot TSX.
And over here, I'm going to start by doing RFCE.
And we're going to have sign in.
I'm going to call this sign in sign in component like this.
And inside our div, instead of a div right here, I'm going to use sign in from at clerk
next.
Yes, I'm going to save it like this and use it like this.
And then from here, this is not actually using the components.
So we're going to go to our app page and we're going to create a new folder.
And we're going to call this inside this off component.
I'm going to create a new folder.
I'm going to call this sign in.
And for using clerk, we have to use a catch all folder.
So that is done via creating another folder dot sign in with double bracket friends.
That's the way for this to work.
And we need to create a component or a page dot TSX.
So we have a sign in page by itself.
So if I look at the final application, let's sign out.
And if you go log in, you're going to see this separate page.
And that is the clerk authentication component.
So in here, it's going to be very simple.
I'm just going to do export default function page.
And we're just going to return sign in like so.
And we are going to import it from at component sign in.
So it's basically the component page.
So with that, let's actually look if we have this particular file.
So we're going to say sign in.
And we should be able to see we have the sign in component exactly what we expect.
And this is very nice because setting this up is pretty annoying
and can be very complicated and cause security issues if we do not do it correctly.
However, this is not the styling that we kind of want.
So the first thing I want to do is in this auth folder, I'm going to create a new layout.tsx.
So this will determine the layout for our page, specifically for the authentication pages.
So I'm going to do rafce.
I'm going to call this layout with a capital L inside here.
I'm going to pass in children.
And over here would be children in curly braces, colon react.react node.
And over here, I'm going to do div class name, pass in auth-layout
with another main class name, auth-layout_main, like so.
Make sure we close that out.
And we also close out our main element.
And inside here, this should be children, like so.
And so now this should be centered and right in the right,
basically in the right spot that we want.
So pretty simple, but we also want to be able to style this appropriately.
So we're going to go back to our sign-in component.
And what we want is to deal with the appearance prop.
So appearance prop is where we can style it very well.
So the first thing we want to do is give it a base theme of dark.
So this makes it easier for us to style.
We can customize it without using this, but this makes it a lot easier.
So the dark variable is going to come from import dark from @clerk/themes.
So that gives us the dark color, but this is not perfectly in brand with the colors.
So we're going to customize this quite a bit.
And the way we customize it is pretty simple and interesting.
So if I open this up, like so, I'm going to click some of these elements.
And the way you basically style this is that you take one of these CSS elements
and you can see the classes that are placed on it.
So CLFormField.
Let's say we want to modify the form field.
Or actually, let's look at...
So let's say we want to modify this text right here.
You can see that we have a class of CLFormField label.
There's an easy way to style this and we can use the elements property.
Pass in an object and we can write form field label like so with colon.
And then from here, we can actually just pass in tailwind classes.
So I'm going to do text white of 50 and font normal.
Now, if you take a look, it's no longer super white.
It is a normal font and it's no longer bolded.
So it's very nice to be able to style this using their classes over here.
So you can directly style it using all the classes.
So I'm going to go through this pretty quick.
The first thing we want to style is going to be flex or root box.
Justify dash center items, dash center with py of five.
We're going to give it a card box and we're going to give it a shadow of none.
So there's no shadows.
We don't want any kind of border because that's not part of our style.
And for the card, we're going to give it a background of custom grays,
which is a color I have specifically set.
Secondary PG with a full and a shadow of none.
So the color in the background is now different.
Now, we also want to style the further a bit.
So, again, you can find the class elements.
So like this, this would be the further CL further.
That's exactly what I'm styling right here.
In here, I'm going to give it a background of this specific color,
25262F because that's what matches.
We're going to give it a padding of 0rem, 2.5rem.
And we're also going to target very inside.
I did a lot of experiments just to make sure we're grabbing the correct selectors.
And you can kind of do it like this.
We want to give this a background color of 25262F.
Once we have that, we're going to have a more homogenous color right there, which is perfect.
And below this, we're going to have form button primary.
So we're going to change the main button color.
Even though white looks pretty nice, it is not consistent with what we have with the other colors.
So we're going to do bg custom grays primary bg text of white 50 shadow of none.
And then form field input colon bg custom grays primary bg text of white 50.
And we are doing shadow of none.
By the way, this exclamation means it's an important tag.
Sometimes you need to do that to override certain classes.
And we're also going to change the further action link styling.
So we're going to do text primary 750 hover text primary 600.
We're going to save that.
And it does seem like I did mess up the primary.
This should not be this set.
So we're going to remove text white 50.
And we're going to change this to primary 700 like so text of white 100 and hover background
primary 600 like that.
That should give us our little button.
And we have our styling just as we this is quite good.
But now we need to do this sign up component.
So we're going to handle all the redirects and where things should go where.
But let's first create the sign up component.
So I'm going to close this out like this.
So we have more space.
I'm going to open this up, create a new component called sign up TSX.
And I'm just going to take everything in our sign in component, paste it over here.
But we're going to change sign in command the four times and changes to sign up like this.
And from here, we also want to create another folder.
We're going to have sign up passing another folder with double brackets, three dots sign
up to closing braces just like that.
And we're going to create another file called page TSX.
And we're going to go to our sign in page, we're going to copy that, paste it over here.
Change the sign in to sign up.
And now we can now go directly to the URL, go sign up.
And we should be able to see the exact same thing, but this is a sign up component.
Perfect.
So this makes it super easy.
We have the sign up component, we have all the appearance consistent with our styling,
and we have all our settings perfectly done.
And by the way, all the configurations we did, we had password, email verification name.
I also clicked name right here.
So maybe if you didn't change the setting, you wouldn't see the first name, last name
required over here for creating your account.
So it makes it super easy when we use the sign in sign up component and we configure
it over here on clerk's dashboard, which makes it so convenient and so nice.
So while we have that, we don't have some of the links right here.
So if you take a look, the sign in, it's not going to take us to the right page.
If you look at the bottom left, that's the page where it's supposed to take you.
That's the default location, but we want to take it, take us to the sign in page.
So let's take a look at our diagram.
We're going to go to this particular page.
So authentication flow right here is how the screen flows are going to work.
So in the nav bar, we're going to have a login and sign up.
The login is going to take us to the sign in page.
The sign up will take us to the sign up page.
Pretty straightforward.
And then we're going to have the sign up page take us to the sign up page or sign in
sign up text button, and then the sign in text button to the sign in page.
So we're going to have to configure that.
And then also in our checkout or guest checkout, we'll cover this later, but we're going to
have to handle this logic with our authentication flow.
The step one requires us to sign in.
We're ignoring the guest checkout because the scope was a little big.
We're ignoring guest checkout, and we're going to make sure that the user needs to
sign in and sign up before they can go to the payment checkout page.
So we'll have this sign in component over here.
And they can only then go to this page if they signed up.
So if they are signed in, we're going to take them to this payment page directly.
So that means that the user has already signed in, then they could go to this page.
So these are all configurations that we need to set.
And one last thing is right here.
Once you open the little user button, we have manage account.
So if we go to the manage account, we're going to use the user profile account.
So this is within the dashboard page.
So this is when they're authenticated.
It's going to take them to this particular page so they can configure the settings for
their user profile.
But also, if they click sign out, it's going to automatically transfer them to the landing page.
So this is basically all the directions that we need to set Clerk to do.
So there's a few route considerations that we're going to have to set up in these components.
So the sign in page includes two situations.
We have the auth page where they're just going to sign in.
But then there's also the checkout page where they can sign in there as well.
But we have different considerations when they sign in.
And the redirect is going to be different based on whether they signed in over here
or whether they signed in over here.
So the redirect URLs are going to be different.
And we need to figure out how to set that up.
So what we are going to do is we're going to grab search params.
So we are grabbing from the URL and we're going to use next slash navigation.
And then we're also going to grab the user information, which is using use user from
clerk so we can use that information as well.
And we are also going to check via the URL route.
Let's put this over here.
So is checkout page is going to be determined by whether we grab a URL that says show sign up.
So if this URL consists of show sign up, which is going to happen on the checkout page,
this page right here, remember the URL is just slash sign in.
So we don't need to, this will return false.
So if it's not equal to null, that means we are at the checkout page.
But if it is null, which you're on this page, this is going to return false.
So we are not at the checkout page.
So that's how we determine whether we are on this page or this page.
And then course ID is we are going to grab it from search params dot get dash ID.
And remember, this is again only going to happen if they're on the checkout page.
So the way we are going to grab the sign up URL, the reason why we need to sign up URL
is going to redirect them.
So basically this button is going to redirect them to this page.
If we are on this page, otherwise over here, if they click sign up, it's not going to redirect
them to this page.
It's not going to do that.
We want to keep them on the checkout page.
So this component is going to turn into a sign up component right here.
So we're not redirecting, we're redirecting them to a new URL.
We're just going to take them over here and just switch out the components essentially.
So we're going to do is checkout page and we are going to pass in a string.
If we are on the checkout page, we're going to do checkout question mark step is equal
to one.
Given an and variable with and is equal to course ID.
And we are going to do and show sign up is equal to true.
So that means we are going to set this to be a sign up component.
Otherwise, we are just going to take them to the sign up page.
So with that sign up URL, we're going to go down over here.
We're going to say sign up URL.
So that will determine what that sign up URL button goes to.
And it's going to take us to the right page.
So if I go to local host and again, this needs to be a use client component because we are
using use search params.
So let's actually start in the sign in page.
We're going to hit sign up and that should take us to this sign up page right here.
If you look at the URL, it took us from sign in to sign up.
So I click here, sign up.
Later on, when we are on the checkout page, this will play a role and we're going to take
us to a different page.
And then we also need to configure where it takes us once we sign in and sign up.
So we need to figure out what the URL is going to be after the user signs in, signs up, and
it's going to have different scenarios again.
So get redirect URL is a function we're going to need.
So if we are at the is checkout page, we're going to return to slash checkout question
mark step is equal to two.
And we're going to do ID is equal to course ID like this.
Otherwise, we're going to do different routes depending on whether they are a teacher or
a student.
So we're going to grab the user type and we're going to use public metadata.
And we are going to grab the user type, as we mentioned before, which we'll talk about
shortly.
We're going to do if user type is equal to a teacher, we're going to make sure that they
go to the URL slash teacher slash courses.
Otherwise, if they're not the user type of teacher, they're going to go to user slash
courses.
And we are going to need to pass this in via force redirect URL.
We're going to do get redirect URL, invoke that function to get us a string.
It's a little bit complicated, but that's mostly because we do have two different scenarios
where we use sign in and sign out.
Finally, we want to set the routing to be a hash.
Otherwise, all of this won't work.
And then the after sign out URL, like we mentioned, this is a URL that we go to after they
sign out.
And that's just going to be the landing page.
And there we go.
That's most of what we need for sign in.
Sign up is going to be very, very similar.
So if I go to the sign up component, we're just going to basically copy everything in
here.
We're going to make sure we import everything correctly.
We're going to change the sign up URL to sign in URL.
This show sign up is going to be false.
And this is going to be sign in.
Now, if you don't understand the checkout, we're going to be talking about that very
shortly.
So don't worry about that.
All of this can remain the same.
And we're going to go back to the sign in component, copy all of this.
Paces over here, except this should be sign in.
And this should be pretty much good to go after we add use client at the top.
So with all of that, we should be able to now create our account.
So I'm just going to give this a dummy account.
So first name is going to be some dumb.
And then our email address is some dummy email at gmail.com.
I'm just going to do it.
One, two, three, Apple bees for the account.
We're going to hit continue.
And you're going to have to verify on your email account.
And over here, I have seven, one, one, eight, two, seven.
And when you succeed, it should take you to user slash courses.
And we're going to say page could not be found.
That's who we to be expected because we haven't created it.
And we're just going to go back to local host.
So now if you go to the homepage right here, you won't be able to see if you signed in
or out.
So if we want to check, we can go to, let's go to the landing page.
And what we're going to do is go up here.
We're going to remove the console log of courses.
We don't need those, but we're going to grab user from use user from clerk.
And we can console log this.
I'm going to save this.
Open up our console.
And you can see we have our user information as has all the details over here.
So we have the first name, full name, some dumb email address all over here.
So everything that we need is provided automatically.
So this is great.
So that's good for us that we can see that in our console log, but for the user,
there's no way of them knowing that they're signed in.
So we need to create a user button.
So again, I'm just going to remove that from the landing page.
And what we're going to do is we're going to go back finally to our non-dashboard
nav bar over here, and we are going to add the sign in buttons.
So the way this works is we're going to use signed in from clerk.
So this is just a situation where this is the condition of whether we are signed in.
We are going to display the user button component from clerk next JS.
We're going to display that if we're signed in.
But then you also want to set up the signed out.
So this will show whatever you want over here, what it looks like when they're signed out.
So in here, we're going to have a link with href is equal to slash sign in.
With the class name of non-dashboard nav bar, double underscore auth dash button dash dash log
in.
Pass that in over there.
This is going to be log in like so.
And then I'm going to copy this, paste it over here.
We're going to do sign up.
And this should be instead of log in, sign up.
And this should be sign up right here as well.
But let's save it.
And as you can see, we have our user button.
It shows everything and everything is as we expect.
So now this is a little bit jarring because it is light mode.
We want a dark mode and we want to customize this a little bit.
We also want to display the name or email address if they have it in the user button.
So the user button is going to require some appearance.
So we're going to use the appearance prop as well over here.
We're going to pass in base theme as well.
So we're going to pass in dark from clerk themes.
We're going to set elements.
And we are going to give it some styling user button outer identifier.
We're going to do text custom, raise dirty gray like this.
And then user button box colon scale of 90 and scale
of 100 on larger screens like so.
And we're also going to pass in a few other props like show name.
So we just want as pretty self-explanatory.
We want to have the name shown.
User profile mode is going to be navigation so that we have user profile use the URL.
So that will determine basically this manage account URL.
So if the user role is equal to teacher,
we're going to pass in slash teacher slash profile.
Otherwise we're going to pass in slash user profile over here.
But the user role is not identified.
So we're going to go scroll all the way to the top.
And we are going to pass in user.
Grab use user from at clerk next JS.
You're going to pass in user role user question mark public meta data question mark user type
as student or teacher like so.
We're going to set that.
And again, this is now going to be a client component.
So we're going to do use client over here.
And now we should see that the name is popping up.
We should see this box.
We should see a darker color.
And if I click manage account, it's going to take us to the user profile.
And that's based on this user role.
By default, we're going to do user profile, which is a user account.
Now, if I go back to the main oops.
If I go back to the main page, let's hit sign out.
It's going to take us to the home page.
And we are going to see this particular page.
The login takes us to this URL.
Sign up takes us to the sign up account.
And it's pretty nice, right?
So we already have our flows.
Let's say since we already created our account, we're going to click sign in.
I'm just going to sign into the account that we created.
So just some dummy email at gmail.com.
And over here, you can see the password pops up.
And that makes it super easy to hit continue.
And that takes us to the user courses again.
We have not created that page.
So this is perfectly a valid point.
So authentication is pretty much set.
Now, the last thing I want to take care of is how do we set the user roles, the user types?
So I was going to create a separate page for like an admin who determines whether the user
that signed up is going to be a teacher or a user.
So that you typically would have some kind of admin person to be able to make a specific
user into a teacher if they wanted to for extra security.
However, the scope would have been too big.
So instead, the easiest way to do this is we go, we can look at their users inside our
clerk.
So you can see that we have our user that signed up.
And we can click on this.
And the way we do this, now, if you're using a paid account, you would use something like
organizations.
That's more for a paid account.
But if you are doing like a free tier, you can set up the roles via using the user metadata.
So now the user metadata is a way for us to save information about the user onto clerk.
So this is a way to keep information relevant to that user on clerk itself, not in our own
database.
We could provide information on our users and create it separately on our own database.
But that makes it a little more complicated.
So it's best to put that user metadata on the user clerk information as well.
So if I go back, I just want to show you one last thing.
Go back to our ERD diagram over here.
You can see we have our clerk user.
They have a user ID and a lot of other information.
The clerk is going to save information.
But here we're going to set up in our clerk user in the public metadata.
We're saving settings information.
So that will include information about the specific users and then also the user type
as well.
So we're all keeping it in the public metadata.
You can keep information about private metadata if you want to keep their stripe key on clerk
user.
We don't need to do that.
But if you wanted to do something like that to keep it extra secret, you can use the private
metadata to do so.
Unsafe metadata is metadata that you can change on both the front end, back end, whereas public
metadata, you can only change it from the back end, whereas private metadata is even
more secure.
So anyways, with that long spiel out of the way, we can go to our user metadata.
We can actually edit this directly.
And what we want to set is going to be user type like this.
And we can change this to student or teacher.
But for now, we're going to have this person as a student.
So now we can double check if this is working.
So let's go over here.
We can copy this.
Let's actually console log this right here and go to our application.
And you can see I'm going to refresh it.
The user type was now student.
Before it would be undefined.
Before we put this.
Now it is registering as student.
So let's actually change this to teacher just to show you one more time how this works.
You save it.
You can refresh it.
Now you should be able to see that it's a teacher now.
So I mean, this is kind of a easier way to set a specific type of user for now without
creating like a separate admin page.
Clerk makes it pretty easy to do.
All right.
So from here, we're going to go into author or user pages.
You can see that we have the profile account.
So this is actually a clerk component.
And we're just going to slap this in into our profile page.
So we're going to use that for the user profile page and the teacher profile page.
So this will be super easy.
So we're going to close this up right here.
So we're going to go up here.
We're going to have two different types of folders.
Right now we see non dashboard, but we're also going to have another folder called dashboard.
So this includes all the pages that's going to be behind authentication.
And that includes all of these user pages and teacher pages that we have seen before.
So the user and teacher page both have this profile component.
So we are going to create a new folder.
We're going to call this user and also teacher as well.
And for each of these, we're going to create a new folder as well.
We're going to call this profile.
And we're also going to create another folder for the catch all dot dot dot dot profile.
We need to do this anytime we are using clerk components.
And we're going to use a new file.
We're going to do page dot TSX.
So inside here, I'm going to do RAFCE.
I'm going to call this user profile page.
And I'm going to do an empty string or empty, empty fragment, just like that.
And what we're going to do is we're going to create a header component real quick.
So that is going to be this particular text right here.
And because we're going to be using this in multiple places,
we're going to put it in the components folder.
We're going to call this header dot TSX.
We're going to do RAFCE.
Inside here, we're going to pass in title, subtitle, and right element optional.
So this won't play into a role for this particular component.
But later on, we're going to be using it.
We're going to give a div with the class name.
Inside here, I'm going to do a div with h1 class name of header underscore title.
With string pass in title as the variable with a p tag.
It's going to be class name of header underscore subtitle.
And pass in subtitle over here.
And then from here, we're going to do right element.
If that exists, we're going to pass in a div.
We're going to give this a right element like so.
Close out the div.
And we should be basically good to go.
So we can now go to our page component.
We can pass in header from the components.
And we can do title is equal to profile.
With subtitle, view your profile like this.
Close this out.
And then finally, we can pass in user profile from @clerk next JS.
We're going to save it like this.
So now let's actually just see what it looks like.
And the way we are going to look at this is we're going to write since we are users,
we're going to do user slash profile.
And because we're locked in, logged in, we should be able to see this.
So this is fully interactive.
And this is kind of the nice thing about @clerk.
Because you are able to see this, you are able to basically configure everything you need.
And this is super nice.
Setting this up and creating this yourself is basically a huge pain.
So just FYI, having something like this makes life a lot easier.
But anyways, we can go over here and we are going to set the path to be slash user slash profile.
And the routing is going to be path.
So that we are configuring this correctly for the values.
And then the appearance, we're going to do a base theme and it's going to be dark again.
Pass that in.
Give it elements with scrollbox colon bg custom grays with dark gray with navbar.
And give it a string with int div colon nth child one.
Like so.
Give it a background of none.
If we save that, we should see it's going to be in a darker mode.
More consistent with the styling.
Now we can go further and make it a little better.
But for now, this should be good.
So this is pretty good.
We're going to do the same thing for teacher.
So we're going to grab this profile component or profile folder.
Paste it all of that into the teacher.
We're going to go over here and just change one little thing.
Teacher.
And we should be good to go.
And we're not going to test this because this currently is a user account.
We can check things later.
So that's how easy it is to create a profile account and be able to change.
Add all the functionality for all of this.
And by the way, if we go back over here, we've already set it up that if you go to manage account,
it will take you to that specific page.
So all that configuration we did earlier will take you to the correct page.
All right.
So now if we go to the manage account, we have this profile page.
But we do not have what we need over here, which is going to be all of this sidebar.
Now, fortunately for us, and unfortunately for myself,
we got this new app sidebar from ShadCN.
So if you go over here, you can see ShadCN.
This is a new component that ShadCN provides.
And we're going to be using this, providing a lot of functionality.
It was unfortunate for me because they released this
after I've already built the sidebar component.
So instead, I refactored it, made it so we are using that sidebar component.
For this specific use case.
So to do this, I'm going to close all these pages out, open up our dashboard.
And now all we have to do is create a file called layout.tsx,
which will apply to all of the pages in our dashboard group.
So this layout is going to be applied to every single one.
And that would make sense because it's across all these pages that we see.
All right. So we're seeing this error because we have nothing in our layout page.
Oh, by the way, if you go to the teacher profile, this should not be user profile page.
This should be teacher profile page.
Make sure you change both of those.
We're going to save that.
And we are now going to add the app sidebar to our layout component.
So what we're first going to do is go to our layout over here,
copy everything just so we have some template that we can modify.
So I'm going to scroll this up so we have more space.
And we're going to do a couple of things.
We're going to import navbar from at slash components slash navbar.
So we have not created that just yet.
And we're just going to remove all of this.
Like so.
And we're going to make some modifications.
So over here, we're going to call this dashboard layout instead.
And inside, like right above the return, we're going to grab the path name
and we're going to grab use path name from next navigation.
So this will be important because the app sidebar will look different on certain pages.
And that is specifically, namely, this particular page that we see here.
This is where we see the videos.
And in the videos, we have this extra sidebar that we are going to create.
So when this happens, we are going to create this component specifically for this URL,
but also close our app sidebar when we are on this page.
So this page will be special.
We'll be handling that later when we get closer to it.
But we're just going to set up some of the layouts over here.
So we're going to do course ID, set course ID over here.
We're going to grab that from use date.
Put in string with null like so.
Pass in null over here.
And then we're also going to grab our user because now we have the user information
from clerk and we can easily grab it with use user.
And I'm just going to create a comment saying handle use effect is course page.
Now we'll take care of it later because it will make more sense later if we do that.
But for now, if the page is not loaded, we can do return and we're going to use our loading
component.
So that makes it super easy because we've created all of that.
And if user is not signed in, we can do return with div.
Please sign in to access this page.
So a couple of things.
We're going to change the non-dashboard layout because this is now dashboard.
This should be dashboard body underscore body like so.
And we're going to add a few things.
So our sidebar will go here, but our div is going to be including a class name with dashboard
underscore content.
And I'll explain how this layout will work.
So this should all enclose that.
And over here is going to be where the chapters sidebar will go if it is the course page,
which we'll handle later.
And finally, we're going to have a div with class name.
And this is the first time we're going to be using CN, which is a utils from Tailwind
to make it a little bit nicer.
We're going to pass in dashboard double underscore main like so.
We're going to keep it like this for now.
And we're also going to set the style to be a height of 100 viewport height.
So this will give us full height for the actual main section.
Now, again, we have an error because we need to do use client for the specific page.
And finally, what we need for the sidebar is we're going to provide a sidebar provider.
So this comes from the sidebar component, and we need to wrap our sidebar component
with this sidebar provider so that it is able to access the state and we can access the state
as we want.
And inside our dashboard component, this is where our app sidebar will exist.
So this is this right here.
Dashboard is going to flex both this item and the rest of the content.
So that means if you were to look on this layout, the sidebar would exist right here.
And then the content will be the rest of this page.
That's how this will basically work.
And if the sidebar does exist for the chapter sidebar, that will go over here as well.
So this is all kind of flexed apart to make sure everything is aligned correctly.
It'll make more sense as we go along.
So let's actually create our app sidebar.
So let's go down into our components, create a new file, and we're going to call this
app sidebar dot TSX.
Inside here, I'm going to call this RAFCE.
And we are going to import a few things.
Now, if you notice on the app sidebar.
Right here, scroll over here, you can see we have a sign out button,
so we can do that exactly the way we've been doing it.
This one is a little bit different.
So first, we want to make sure the user is signed in.
So we're going to have use user.
We're also going to grab sign out.
So this is just a hook function that we can grab from use clerk.
So this if we have a button, we can make sure the user clicks this button.
And if this is this function is triggered, then the user is signed out automatically.
And then from here, we're going to grab the path name,
grab the path name from navigation.
We can do toggle sidebar.
We're going to use sidebar like so grab it.
Now, use user is hasn't been imported.
And personally, when I import ShadCN components, I personally like having the at alias.
By the way, I haven't covered it, but the at alias allows us from Next.js
to start and grab imports directly starting from this source directory.
So at components, UI sidebar.
So that's how we can grab it.
And then from here, we're going to be creating all the nav links that we need for the entire
sidebar, and we're going to have two different sets.
So inside here, we're going to have student colon within the array,
and we're going to pass in icon with a book open.
So from Lucite React, we're going to have a label of courses and an href
colon of user or slash user slash courses like so.
And what I want to do is just copy this four times because we have four links on our sidebar.
This one is going to be a briefcase.
Make sure you import that.
And this one is going to be billing.
So we're going to have user slash billing like so.
And then the next icon is going to be user from Lucite React.
This is going to be a profile label.
And this is going to be user slash profile.
And then finally, we're going to have settings.
But the label of settings and then the href is going to be user slash settings.
And then we're going to copy this entire thing, but put teacher for the next one and paste it
over here.
Most of this is going to be the same.
We're going to change this to money, let's say, or dollar sign.
I don't know.
Doesn't really matter.
But every single one where you see slash user.
So I'm going to do command D for all of them and pass in teacher like this.
By the way, these should not be capitalized.
So we have settings.
So this will set up our nav links.
And then from here, we're going to do if statement just to make sure we have this loaded check.
We're going to return loading.
Right here from our loading components makes it super easy.
If and the user is not found, we're just going to return div user not found.
And then from here, we're going to grab the user type because the user type is what matters.
So the nav links is dependent on the user type that we have.
So we're going to grab user public metadata dot user type.
And we're going to set that as student.
This is for TypeScript typing or teacher.
Or if none of those exist, we're going to default to student.
And we're going to set const current nav links to be nav links of user type.
So depending on the user role, we're going to set that to the correct list of nav links.
All right.
So over here, we're going to pass in sidebar from at component slash UI sidebar.
We need to make this collapsible and set this to icon.
That allows us to collapse it to the icon size of the sidebar.
And we're also going to give it a style of height collapsible.
Height colon 100 viewport height.
Sometimes you have to use these inline styling instead of tailing classes
because it is not specific enough and sometimes it does not work.
And we're going to set this to be background custom grays, promy, BG, border of none.
Shadow is going to be large.
So inside our sidebar, we're going to have a sidebar header.
Make sure we pass that in for the right import with sidebar menu.
With class name of app dash sidebar underscore menu.
Close that in.
Give it sidebar menu item.
Close that.
Make sure we import those though.
And then finally, we're going to have sidebar menu button.
Make sure you import that.
Inside here, we're going to do size is going to be large.
By the way, there's a lot of documentation for this.
So you can take a look.
There is a lot of different options.
Little rough around the edges, but they just released it couple one week ago
from the release of this video or maybe like two weeks ago.
So just realize it's very new, but it's quite nice.
Sidebars are kind of a pain.
I'll tell you sidebars are very pain.
You don't want to deal with it.
And then we're going to grab the toggle sidebar that we created or that we
got from you sidebar.
So this allows us to close and open the sidebar and collapse it if we need to.
And make sure we invoke it like this.
So we're going to have a class name is equal to group with hover BG custom
graze secondary background like so.
And by the way, we are currently building out this top line.
So if we click on it, it's going to help us close it.
So over here, we're going to have a div with class name app slash sidebar
underscore logo dash container group like so.
I'm just going to grab all of this.
Like so.
So we don't have to write that every single time.
I'm going to do div paste that logo wrapper.
Close that out.
Bring in the image component from next.
And we're going to do source is equal to slash logo dot SVG.
And by the way, I have not actually imported this.
If you go to asset downloads, you should have a logo SVG.
I just forgot to add it while I was recording it.
So I added it.
You should be able to see this.
You should copy this, go to public and paste it over here.
So you should have that logo.
So I'm going to close that over here.
Go back to writing our code.
So over here, I'm going to do alt is equal to logo.
And width is going to be 25.
Height is going to be 20.
The class name of app dash sidebar underscore logo.
And we're going to do a p tag with.
Class name app sidebar underscore title colon ed row.
And over here, we're going to do a panel left, which is an icon from Lucid React.
Give it a class name with app dash side sidebar underscore collapse dash icon like so.
And we can save it.
It's very nice.
Just a lot of components right here.
There's just a lot of JSX elements below this sidebar header.
We are going to create the sidebar content.
We're going to import that from sidebar.
And then inside here, we're going to pass inside bar menu, which we've already imported.
Give it a class name of app sidebar underscore nav dash menu.
Close that.
And from here, we can now pass in the current nav links.
So these were the headers.
Now we're dealing with the content.
So that's going to display out these elements.
So current nav links, we're going to map this out, pass in the link.
And put an arrow function, make sure we close this like so.
We're going to have const is active is equal to path name dot starts with and link dot href like so.
So we're going to determine if it's active.
And if it's active, we're going to give it a different background color.
So sidebar menu item.
And in here, we're going to pass in a kink or a key link dot href.
And we're going to do class name is equal to what CN pass this in app dash sidebar
underscore nav dash item.
However, we're also going to have a conditional.
We're going to do is active.
And when it's active, we want to add a class of background gray 800.
And make sure we import CN from libutils.
We're going to close the sidebar menu item up and inside here.
We're going to add a sidebar menu button.
Close this.
Inside here, we're going to set this as a child.
Give it a size of large.
Give it a class name of colon CN app sidebar underscore nav dash button.
And if it's not active, we are also going to give this a text of custom grays.
Dirty gray.
Like so.
And finally, inside here, we're going to give it a link with the href link dot href.
I'm going to paste app sidebar nav dash link colon like this.
Inside here, I'm going to pass in link dot icon.
Close this out.
Inside here, pass in class name is equal to is active.
And if it is active, we're going to give it a text of white 50.
Otherwise, we're going to give it a text of gray 500.
I want to make sure we passed in the link tag from next link.
And we're also going to pass in a span.
And we're going to give it a class name with CN.
I know this is a lot of styling and setup, but it is a sidebar.
So give it a nav text like this is active.
Question mark text of white dash 50 colon text of gray 500.
And inside here, we're going to pass in link dot label.
OK, so we're almost there.
We're almost there.
Let's actually see if we can see it.
Nope.
We're going to pass app sidebar in.
OK, and then if we open it, we can see most of it.
It seems like our text is not displaying.
Let's go back and we should probably get to fixing some of this.
So over here, we're going to close this and we're going to say is active.
And we're going to give it a div class name.
App sidebar underscore active dash indicator.
Close that out.
And we're going to go down right below sidebar content and we are going to pass
in sidebar further from the components.
We're going to pass inside bar menu.
Close that out.
Sidebar menu item.
Close that out as well.
Sidebar menu button.
We're going to set this as as child.
Close that and give it a simple button tag.
Inside here, I'm going to do on click and we're going to finally use that sign out
function that we talked about earlier.
Give it a class name of app dash sidebar underscore sign out.
And we're going to pass in the component log out from Lucidwiki.
Give it a class name.
With margin right of 2h6 width of 6.
Close that.
Give it a span and we're going to sign out.
So with this, we do have some issues, as you can see.
Some of the colors are off and then the text is not even visible.
So let's try and fix this.
The reason why is because of this link dot icon.
Let's remove that.
This should be self-closing over here.
And then you should be able to see the text now.
And so with that, it should be pretty good now.
So now if you can see, you can collapse it.
You can see all of this working as expected.
So if you go further, it's going to collapse on its own, which is good.
This is exactly what we want.
So now we have a new component.
So now we have our app sidebar, which is very nice and convenient.
We do need a nav bar at the top.
So if you go over here, you can see every page is going to have this top nav bar as well.
So we need to create that so we can go back to our layout page.
We're going to create a nav bar component up here, which we have not created.
So let's go over here, create a component, and we're going to call this navbar dot TSX.
Now inside here, I'm going to just grab everything we had in non-dashboard navbar,
copy it, paste it into the navbar component.
Now we'll just do a lot of modifications from here, but it should give us a good starting point.
So I'm going to change this non-dashboard navbar, and we are going to pass in is course page.
And this is the navbar is going to be slightly different,
depending on if we are on the course page, as we mentioned before.
Now from here, we're going to add is dark mode.
We're going to set is dark mode as well.
Pass in use state from react.
Pass in false for the state as well.
And for now, we're just going to grab all of these non-dashboards,
select all of them by pressing command D and just holding it.
Change this to dashboard dash navbar, and we're going to make some modifications.
So we don't need this link tag anymore, but instead we're going to give this a div,
and we're going to do a class name of when it's larger than medium size screen,
we're going to give it a hidden.
And what we're going to do is we're going to pass inside bar trigger.
And that comes from the UI component.
So this is from the shadcn.
We want to make sure we grab this.
This is so that we can collapse the sidebar as we normally did,
but it's in the navbar itself.
We're going to pass this class name like this.
Go over here and save it.
Over here, we're going to keep a lot of this the same and pass in cn with parens.
And we're going to add dashboard dash navbar underscore search dash input
colon or comma with curly braces.
And we're going to grab, we're going to remove this right here.
Inside here, we're going to put a string.
We're going to say bg custom grays secondary background.
And that is only if it is a course page like this.
We're going to grab the cn from libutils.
And we are missing a closing curly braces right here.
And we're going to keep most of that the same.
And from here, we can keep the bell icon.
Actually, I don't know why I put the is dark mode, we can just remove that.
We're going to keep everything the same.
And for this part, we actually don't need the sign in signed out
because we've already protected it.
We can just keep the user button like this, pretty much everything the same.
And we're going to remove non dashboard, which is going to keep navbar just like this.
And now we should be able to see what we have over here.
And for this part right here, you can see that this is a bell icon.
That's because these are not styled.
We're just going to default to using non dashboard navbar to make it look nice.
And you can see, we have everything set up.
So if I go over here, close this out, we can see we have this icon.
So this is how it looks like when we are on this.
The only thing is we do get these errors.
Dialogue content requires a dialogue title.
I'm not exactly sure how to solve that one because
app sidebar has abstracted out a little bit of the dialogue content.
I guess if you can go to sidebar dialogue, we can write sheet title over here,
place it in, we can say menu sidebar, something like that.
And maybe if you refresh it, we're going to open this up and we don't have an error.
But we do have this problem over here.
So we want to pass in visually and we're just going to pass in class name of hidden.
So that will basically get our error out.
So this will fix the error that we had.
So I refresh the page, open this up.
We no longer have an issue with that.
All right.
So the next page we're going to be looking at is over here.
If we go down, we can see the user settings page.
This user setting page is going to store information in the clerk user data.
So basically, if I go back to our diagram, you can see that we have clerk user.
We have settings being saved here.
So we're going to be saving course notifications, email alerts, SMS alerts, and notification frequency.
We're going to store that information into clerk itself.
Now, it's not ideal to store information in clerk because there's a limit to how much you can store.
But it is nice to keep that type of information together.
So to do that, we need to create an endpoint.
So let's close all of this out.
And we're going to start by going back to the back end.
So I'm going to close out client and go back to our server.
So we're going to go to our controllers.
I'm going to create a new file.
And I'm going to just call this user clerk controller to be more specific.
And in here, I'm going to go back to course controller.
I'm going to copy this get course just so we have like a template.
And I'm going to paste it over here.
Now, we're obviously missing a few things.
So I'm going to rewrite this.
Get request from Express.
Get response from Express as well.
And we should have most of what we need.
Now, for us to save information into our clerk, we need to create a clerk client.
So we would go to the index file.
And I would go all the way up to configurations.
And right here, I would write export const clerk client.
Because we want to instantiate it in our index file.
So basically, when the server starts, we're going to use create clerk client,
which is going to be imported from create clerk client from @clerk/express.
And we're going to pass in secret key with process.env.clerk_secret_key.
So this is how we connect to our clerk client from our Express server.
So the first thing we need to do is grab this @clerk/express,
close out our server, and write npm i @clerk/express.
Once we have done that, we can run npm run dev once again, close this out.
And now we can import in our user controller, we can import clerk client
from dot dot slash index.
And then from here, we're going to change this to update user.
Go over here, we're going to just do const user ID to grab user ID from rec dot params.
And then grab user data from rec dot body.
And get rid of all of this because we no longer need it for this one.
But we need to do a wait clerk client dot users dot update user metadata.
So this is how we update the metadata in our clerk client.
And we do need to pass in the user ID and pass in public metadata colon object,
we pass in user type like I mentioned before.
So we're going to grab that from public metadata dot user type,
which we grab from the front end.
And then also settings, which we also grab from user data dot public metadata dot settings.
And then from here, we can just write user updated success fully.
And we don't need to pass data for this one specifically.
We can change this to error updating user, keep the error as is.
Now the only thing we have left to do for this is we need to change this
or we need to add this environment variable for clerk secret key.
So if you go back to your env dot local on your front end, we can grab all of this,
go to our dot env, and then paste it over here.
And then finally, we need to set up a route for this specific controller.
So user clerk routes dot ts.
And I'm going to go to course routes, just copy all of this, paste it over here.
And I'm going to replace this with update user.
And we are going to grab this from user clerk controller.
And then change all of this to rather dot put string slash user ID, like so.
And then we're going to do update user.
And then finally, we go to our index file.
And then I can go to right below the app dot use.
We can write slash users slash clerk for our particular route.
And we can set user clerk routes like so.
And we need to make sure we import that from dot slash routes slash user clerk routes.
All right, so here, I'm going to close all of these out right here.
And now we can finally go back to our front end, we can go to source state API.
Inside here, I'm going to scroll down, go to our endpoints.
And right above here, we can have a separate endpoint, and we can call this update user.
Now this time, this is not build query, it's going to be build mutation,
because we're updating instead.
So when you are using like a put method or anything that involves delete, post,
anything that changes data in the back end that's already existing,
or creating a new one, then you use build dot mutation.
So what it's going to return is going to be the user object,
whereas we are going to pass in partial user information to the back end.
And we are going to also send user ID colon as a string for the types.
And in this object, we are going to set query, and we are going to pass in both user ID
dot dot dot updated user with an arrow function and putting in URL with template string users,
because that's the endpoint that we're using.
And we're also passing in user ID as well.
The method is going to be put and body is going to be updated user.
And finally, we are going to invalidate tags of users, which we do not have just.
So this part invalidates tags.
That means that anytime we update a list of users, the entire users list will be refetched.
If we do have a list of users, but in this case, we're not really refetching it.
So it's not a big concern.
So you don't have to worry about it right now.
All right, with this, we can scroll down.
And because this is a mutation request, instead of being it use update user query,
it's going to be mutation.
So use update user mutation for this.
Now we can go over here, go to our app, go to our dashboard.
And inside users, we can create a new folder, we can call this settings.
And we can do the same thing in teachers.
But let's actually create a file called page.tsx in our user page.
And I'm going to do rafce.
This is going to be user settings.
And inside here, I'm just going to do, I'm going to close this out, give it a class name.
Of width of three feet, like this.
Now inside of this div, we're going to have shared notification settings.
And we're doing this because this page will be exactly the same in the teacher page as well.
So we just want to be able to share this component and be reused for both those pages.
So we're just going to leave it like that.
So we're just going to leave it like this.
And I'm going to go to components page.
And we're going to create a file called this shared notification settings.tsx.
All right, so inside here, I'm going to do rafce shared notification settings.
And we're going to have an object.
And this is going to be title.
And by default, we're going to give it a notification settings as the text.
And subtitle is going to be manage your notification settings.
So if you wanted to change it, you're able to with these props.
And we're going to do colon shared notification settings props like this.
From here, we're going to grab the user information because that's where we get
our clerk information over here.
And then we're also going to grab update user from as an array.
And we grab it from use update user mutation.
And we're going to grab it from the API file that we created.
So this is exactly how we update our user.
Note that this is slightly different from what we've seen before.
When we go to non dashboard, we go landing page.
This is an object and we have data is loading is error.
Those are destructured from an object.
Whereas over here with the mutation, this is an array.
And this first element is going to be a way this is a function that we can invoke
to update our user on the back end.
All right, so from here, we're going to grab current settings.
And we're just going to do user question mark dot public metadata.
And we kind of have to do all this weird funky stuff because of TypeScript yelling at us.
We're going to set this as user settings like so with question mark dot settings.
And we're going to give it an empty object just so TypeScript doesn't yell at us
if it doesn't exist.
And then now here, because the user settings, if you look, take a look, this is a form
and forms we're going to be using Zod as well as ShadCN forms, which is also using
React hook forms.
So it's a lot of libraries combined together.
But the way we start is we're going to set up methods and we're going to grab use form
from React hook form.
And inside here, I'm going to do notification settings form data because we have already
created the schemas.
We've already passed that in because it's kind of a hassle not to do so.
So if you look, go to the schema page, you can see this is our notification setting schema,
of course, notification Boolean email alerts is a Boolean SMS alerts are Boolean notification
frequency is an enum with those values.
We're just basically making that into a type, passing it in over here, and we're using it
as part of the form.
All right.
So in here, we're going to grab the resolver property and then we're going to grab Zod
resolver.
Which we're going to have to import manually, we're going to do import Zod resolver and
we're going to import from at hook form slash resolvers slash Zod.
And then from here, we can pass in notification settings schema directly from our files, and
then we can do default values and we can pass in course notifications, which will be current
settings dot course notifications.
Otherwise, it's going to be false.
Just so we have something to set.
I'm just going to copy.
Let's actually copy this entire line, paste it four times, but we're going to be changing
some of these.
So this course notifications is going to be email alerts like so.
Next line is going to be SMS.
Alerts.
And the last one is going to be notification frequency.
This value should be daily as a default.
So when you do the forms, you're going to have to also have an on submit function.
So let's create that.
So on submit is equal to async data, colon notification settings, form data.
We're going to pass that in, have an arrow function, and we're going to say if user does
not exist, we're just going to return just to make sure the user has been identified.
And then we're also going to do updated user.
We're going to have an object and this is what we're going to pass into the back end,
which is going to be the user ID.
So user.id like so.
And then we're also going to pass in the public metadata as we mentioned before.
We're going to grab the user.publicmetadata.
This is mostly so we can retain what was already existing in the public metadata.
But then we grab the settings and we're going to pass in the current settings.
So anything that's changed in this particular form.
And we're also going to pass in the new data that we get.
So current settings is what we already have currently.
And then the data is going to be the new information that we have.
All right.
So right below the updated user, we're going to have a try catch block and we can just
run a wait update user with updated user.
So by the way, again, we grab this update user from use update user mutation.
And over here we have this particular error and that's because if we go back to API,
this user object is the wrong one.
So we actually need to import this directly.
So import user from at clerk slash next JS slash server.
So once we have that, this should be OK now.
And we can just do catch with error object like so.
And we can just say console error failed to update user settings colon error like so.
Over here, I can just say if user does not exist, we are just going to return a div that
says please sign in to manage your settings.
All right.
So from here, we can add a class name.
We can pass in notification settings as the class.
And we're going to erase this shared notification settings.
We're going to pass in a header with title being the title that we defined earlier from
the props and that subtitle is going to be subtitle over here.
We're going to close that and we're going to make sure Heather is being imported from
components.
We're going to save that.
And just to check, let's go to our user page.
We're going to just define the title and subtitle over here.
So I'm going to say title is going to be user settings and subtitle is going to be manage
your user notification settings.
And we're going to make sure we import that.
So and then from here, we can actually go to our application.
Let's make sure everything is running.
And it is.
So if we now go to our sidebar that we can go, we can go directly to the settings page.
And what we get is this basic unhandled error runtime.
And that's because if we go back to shared notification settings, it needs to be a client
component.
And we can see we have our Heather.
All right.
So from here, we're going to go scroll down and we're going to now create our form.
Now, we are using form from React hook form, but Shad CN's version of React hook form.
So not the React hook form that we want.
We want the UI form that we're going to grab from at components slash UI slash form.
This is a specific type of form that Shad CN has.
That's kind of like abstracted over on top of React hook form that you can use.
And we're going to pass in dot dot dot the methods that we created earlier.
And then we're also going to encase that with the form HTML.
So we're going to have on submit and we're going to pass in methods dot handle submit
with the on submit function that we created earlier.
And we're going to pass in class name is going to be notification dash settings,
double underscore form.
And we're going to close this like this.
So right now, we don't have our form set up.
And then from here, we are going to use something that I imported earlier from our assets.
So from our asset file, I created this custom form field that we had.
And this includes a long list of form fields where we're going to have different types,
like text area, select, switch.
So we have different type of inputs that we can use in this form field.
This is something I created.
I might create this into like a library, but this makes it a lot easier.
And the code is a lot simpler than doing all the shad CN component inputs,
because it makes it very, very verbose if you were to write this.
But this makes it so it's super simple.
We do need to install a few things.
So we're going to install all of these.
So I'm going to cancel out.
I'm going to install npm iReactFilePond, FilePondPluginImage-Preview,
and then FilePondPluginImageExifOrientation.
This is all for images, by the way.
And I'm going to do legacy-peer-deps.
Make sure we install all of those.
We're going to run npm run dev and go back to our shared notification settings.
And with this set up, I'm going to create a div called class name
with notification-settings_fields.
Pass that in and we're going to pass in custom form field from our components.
And we can do something like npm run dev.
From our components and we can do something like name course notifications
with the label of course notifications.
And we are going to use type is equal to switch.
And I'm going to close that out.
And once we refresh this particular page, we get can't resolve FilePond.
And that's because I do need to install npm FilePond like so with legacy-peer-deps like that.
We're going to do npm run dev once again.
And there you go.
We have course notifications.
So if you see here, we don't see anything.
That's because we need to go and modify our switch component from our ShadCN.
Because it is it doesn't show the color right away.
So we need to set this to be data state is equal to checked with a background primary 700 like so.
And also data we need to put another string.
We're going to do data of state is equal to unchecked.
Give it a background of custom grays, dirty gray, comma, save that.
And over here on the next line, we're going to do a comma, bg gray of 100.
And we need to make sure that there is a closing brace like that.
And if we do that, we can see that we now have our switch component.
So yeah, so this custom form field makes it super easy for us to make inputs.
And it's already directly connected to our use form.
So let's say we want to do email alerts, SMS alerts like this.
I can just grab this, say it's email alerts.
Pass this email alerts like this.
And then we're going to have another Boolean.
And then finally, we need to switch the last one.
SMS alerts.
And then I'm just going to pass this as SMS alerts like so.
This makes it super easy for us to use.
And finally, we are going to have another custom form field.
But this time it's going to be a switch input or not a switch input.
It's going to be a select drop down.
So I'm going to set this to be notification frequency.
The label is going to be notification frequency.
And the type is going to be select.
Yes, I did create this to make it a lot easier.
So it has all these different type of inputs.
It doesn't have everything and it's not fully comprehensive.
But once I have a lot of this set up, I might just create a library,
separate library for this.
So you guys can download.
So making forms, especially in videos like this, it takes too much time.
And I don't think there's a lot of value.
So I think it's better for me to abstract some of that process
so we can focus more on the logic.
So with the select drop down, we can do value.
I'm going to put an immediate with the label of immediate like so with the string.
I'm going to copy this, paste it three times,
and we're going to change this to daily and this one to weekly.
Make sure we capitalize this label as well as weekly.
And once we save it, we can see that we have a notification frequency
with a drop down that looks pretty nice.
And then right below this div, we also obviously need a button.
We can say type is equal to submit.
And we're going to class name is going to be notification dash settings.
Underscore submit.
And we can do update settings.
But this button component is not defined, so we need to import that.
I'm going to go back up, change this to at slash components.
And now we should be pretty good with our user settings.
Now, let's say I change this email alerts.
Let's see if this particularly works.
So we're going to open this up, click network, and I'm going to hit update settings.
And we do get one specific error.
And that's because we do need a data object.
And it seems like I did make a mistake.
So if I go over here, close all of this out.
Let's go to our back end, go back to our server controller with user clerk controller.
And we're just going to set data.
We can say this is const user is equal to await.
And we're just going to pass in user as well.
So we're going to refresh the page.
And I'm going to hit SMS alerts and hit update settings.
And now we don't get any issues.
So the way we can check that it's working is if we refresh the page, everything should be saved.
If it resets, then it's not done correctly.
So this is how easy it is to create a form if we're using a lot of these.
It's abstracted quite a bit.
But basically, if we use all of this, it makes it super easy to create forms,
which are probably one of the more time consuming aspects,
especially with front end and connecting it to your back end.
And now we do have, we're going to close all of this, go to our settings page.
We already have this for user.
But we want to copy this to teacher because it's going to be exactly the same.
Just a little minor change.
So I'm going to paste it into teachers.
We're going to go to this page.
And over here, I'm going to change this to be teacher settings.
And manager teacher notification settings.
And that's pretty much it.
Actually, we need to do change the user settings to be teacher settings like this.
And yeah.
Now there's two other things that I want to do,
which is the first thing is I want to secure our back end.
Because right now, if we go back to our back end,
if we go and hit list courses or get course, you can directly hit your back end.
But you want to have your back end API endpoints also secure with authentication.
Because you don't want random users to be able to hit your API endpoint and exploit it,
especially with user clerk information.
If someone's able to access this without authenticating,
they can update someone's user account, which is not very good.
We can leave list courses and get course.
You know, that is perfectly fine for someone to hit your endpoint.
You can secure it if you really want to,
if you worry about someone DDoSing your website.
Which is not that big of a concern when you're using something like DynamoDB.
But you probably should do it.
But for now, we're not going to secure this endpoint,
but we're going to definitely secure the update user.
So to do that, we're going to do right below our course,
we're going to do app.use_clerk_middleware.
And we're going to grab it from @clerk_express.
And we're going to execute it like that.
And then from here, what we want to do right here with users_clerk,
we want to secure this particular route.
So we're going to use require_auth from @clerk_express.
And we're going to invoke that.
So what happens now is if we actually try to update our backend,
let's say update settings, now we're going to get an error.
It's going to say publishable key not valid.
We aren't able to access it.
Let's say if I just got rid of it, we can do update settings, refresh it.
And if we are to remove the @clerk_middleware,
we are able to update the settings like this.
However, if we add it back again, add require_auth like so,
it's going to prevent us from accessing the backend.
So now we get this error.
So how do we authenticate the users?
So this is where Redux Toolkit API query is very, very nice.
We want to be able to authenticate for every single API call.
So we can now go back to our custom base query,
and we can add those authentication credentials to every single request
by going up here in the custom base query.
Oh, right here.
So if we go and write prepare headers,
actually, we should just get the property, colon, async, pass in headers like so,
with an arrow function like this, and we can just get token await is equal to await.
And we need to grab window.clerk session?get token.
So this is how you can grab the clerk session token.
For some reason, the linting doesn't work unless you import clerk from @clerk/clerkjs.
That's why we installed this one as well.
For some reason, it prevents it from doing anything, even though it's not really using it.
Anyways, if token exists, then we can set our headers to be set to authorization, comma,
bearer, and we're going to add token like this, and we're going to return headers.
Now, this is very common practice to prepare headers,
have it set to authorization with a bearer token.
Even Cognito does this.
So this is how you can make an API request to authenticate every single API that you have on
your back end.
So if I open this back up in our network tab, let's refresh to make sure everything is expected.
Let's say we remove those, update settings, and we do get error publishable key not valid.
So there is a bit of a misname on the .env.
We actually have to change next_public to clerk publishable key because this is on the back end.
So obviously, we should not have done that.
And so let's refresh the page to double check everything is working, remove both of those,
and you're going to have to restart the server for your back end, which I did.
And as you can see, it finally worked.
So if I refresh it just one more time, click this, we can hit our endpoint because we now
have the authorization token.
So if I were to do this, we close this out, we change a few settings.
Let's say we turn it all off.
You can see we get an error.
But if we were to uncomment this out and I change these settings, it should now work.
User updated successfully.
So this is our headers in action.
And you want to be able to authenticate for every single route.
That's why we pass the authorization token when we call our back end.
This is one of the beauties of Redux Toolkit Query.
It makes it super simple to do things like this.
And it is a very common pattern with authentication secure type security.
So one thing that is still missing from this application is when you update settings,
we're not getting, we might get feedback in our console.
We know that a network request is being sent because we see the server.
But for the user, they don't know if something happened.
So we want to have like a toast notification.
So if you look on ShadCN, we have, if we hit add to calendar,
you can see that there's this notification that popped up over here.
So we want to do something like this.
However, I recommend not using the toast component in ShadCN.
Rather, the sonar component in ShadCN.
Because if you show toast, you can actually combine and you can see multiple of the notifications.
Otherwise, toast is just a singular one.
So just be aware.
I got confused one time, but sonar is a way to have multiple notifications.
And it's a very nice UI for something like this.
And so again, I want to brag about how nice Redux toolkit query API is.
I'll show you in just a second.
But the first thing we want to do is set up our layout.
So for our toast notification, we need to go down right below our div.
We want to pass in toaster.
And we're going to set rich colors and close button like this.
And we are going to import toaster from sonar.
And this is one of those things I need to make sure we install npm isonar.
And don't forget the --legacypeerdeps.
And then rerun our server.
We're going to refresh this page.
So by default, obviously, this is not connected.
Doesn't mean that it's going to automatically know to create those notifications.
So this is where we go to our custom base query.
And we want to configure this appropriately.
So now there are a lot of API requests.
We want to not have -- if you go to our backend, and we go to course controller,
we have these messages.
And we want to display these messages if it succeeds.
However, we don't want to do it for any kind of like get request.
If we're just grabbing a list of courses, obviously, we don't want to show the message
for that.
Because that's kind of annoying.
We only want to show the message when we update or do some kind of mutation on the backend.
When we update a user, you know, delete a user or create a user.
Things like that.
Those are the times we want a success message.
Something like this where we do user settings and we hit update settings.
That's when we basically want the message to be shown.
And it's better to use the message that comes from the backend.
Because it's a lot easier.
And the way to do this is we can configure our custom base query to do something like
this.
So over here, right above the result data, let's close this out so we have more space.
We can say if result.error.
So any time our result from our -- any API call that we make, if we get some kind of
error, we want to make sure we check for that error.
Now that error can look like multiple different ways.
So we're just going to grab any kind of error message.
So error data question mark dot message.
So that is possible.
We can also get an error message saying result dot error status to string like this.
We can also just say an error occurred if we don't have anything else.
And we want to use that message for our toast error.
So now toast needs to be imported from Sunner.
We can grab this error message and we can say error like so.
Pass the error message over here.
By doing this, this applies for every single API request.
So any time we have an error, we can show that.
So now we also do want to check if it's a mutation type request.
And the way we do this is using use mutation request.
And we're going to bring in args as fetch args.
So these are just typings.
So we're going to grab the method property from args and args as fetch args.
Like so.
Again, this is just typing kind of a pain.
And if it does not equal to the get.
Basically, we're just grabbing this property method.
And if it's not equal to get, then we can say it is a mutation request.
And if is mutation request, what do we do?
We grab the success message, which is going to come from result.data.message like this.
We're going to grab if success message exists.
We are then going to pass it into toast success.
Success message like so.
And by doing this, we can see the results automatically.
We have in toast message user updated successfully.
And this is the beauty of both Redux toolkit query and our toast ShadCN component.
There's also one last thing that we need to add is just in case.
This is just the error handling that I've encountered.
I'm not exactly sure when this happens.
But if we get a 204, basically an empty object from the back end, we need to handle that edge case.
So this is how I solved it.
I'm not exactly sure on how this particular thing works.
But if this is the case, we just return with data.
No, this is basically handling content if we have no response.
And I did mess this up because that should not be curly braces and like this.
And so there we go.
We now have toast message for any time it's a successful mutation request.
And if we do receive an error, it's going to pop up as the error message.
But we haven't checked that.
But that will it'll probably happen at some point and you'll be able to see the error message.
And it's pretty nice.
So this is our custom base query.
Focus on the checkout.
The checkout flow is a little bit complicated, but it is definitely manageable.
So basically, when you go to the first checkout page, we're going to see the course that we've
have chosen.
We're going to see a guest checkout.
Now, this is not going to be functional.
This is just something I create, but the scope got out of hand.
So I'm just going to use this authentication.
So basically, when the user signs up, hits continue, they're going to be taken to this
particular page.
If they receive this page, then we have this stripe checkout.
So this stripe checkout allows us to get user information for the credit card or billing
information.
And once they hit pay with credit card, it's going to do multiple things.
First of all, it's going to take them to the completed page if everything goes successfully.
But it also will create multiple things.
I know there's quite a lot of things that happen.
So when we pay with credit card, it's going to create a stripe payment, and it's going
to go directly to stripe.
So it's going to create like an actual payment over there, and it's going to handle the transaction.
But it's also going to create a transaction so the user can fetch transaction records
later.
So this is a transaction database that we have.
So if we ever need to grab transactions or information about the payment that was made
and the course, we are saving it into our transaction database.
And that is later going to be used for our payment history page where it shows the amount
and the payment method.
Furthermore, we also need to add the user to the course.
So in our course database, we're going to add an enrollment to the course.
And also, we also need to add progress data for the initial course enrollment.
So user course progress.
So I'll cover this a little more.
This plays into, plays more of a role into when the user is viewing the video and it
tracks the progress.
This is going to play a role in that case.
So later on, when we go to my courses, this is how we check if the course has been created.
So we are keeping track of that in our databases.
So that is essentially our checkout flow.
It's a little complicated when completing the order, but we needed to save all that
information so that we can access it later on.
So the first thing we need to do is I want you to create an account in Stripe.
So make sure you create an account in Stripe, follow the instructions.
And once you're ready, you're going to hit test mode.
You're going to make sure this is selected.
And also you want to select developers.
And we're going to go and select API keys so we can see the publishable key and the
secret key.
So when you have that, we are going to go to our env.local, close that up.
And I'm going to copy next_public.
We're going to write Stripe.
Make sure you spell it correctly.
We have public_key.
And we're going to just copy this value and paste it over here.
And then also we need a next_public, Stripe, redirect URL.
And the redirect URL is going to be the page where the Stripe is going to redirect to once
the transaction is completed.
So we are going to set this to be for now localhost 3000 checkout question mark step
three.
So this is the completed page that we just saw.
And then from here, we're going to go to our back end now.
We're going to go down to.env.
And here we're going to paste in the Stripe secret key.
Underscore key is equal to.
And we are going to copy this.
So I'm going to delete this secret key later on.
But make sure you have your own secret key.
Use that.
I know some people always accidentally use the same key that I have.
And I can see that these are all test keys.
You want to use your own so you have access to your own.
All right.
With all of that set up, we're going to close all of this.
Open up our terminal.
We're going to close our front end.
And we're going to install MPMI at Stripe slash react dash Stripe dash JS and then at
Stripe slash Stripe dash JS.
And you want to make sure we do legacy.
Peer DPS and make sure you spell Stripe correctly.
If you see, I have at Stripe.
It should be at Stripe right there.
And we're also going to go to our server and we're going to just do MPMI Stripe.
So from here, we're going to go to our back end.
We're going to go to controllers and we're going to create a new file.
And we're going to call this transaction controller dot TS.
We're going to close up the terminal.
And in here, I'm going to do several things.
So I'm going to import Stripe from Stripe package that we created.
Then we're also going to import dot env because we want to use the environment variable.
And I'm going to invoke dot env dot config so we can actually use the environment variable.
And we're also going to do if process dot env dot Stripe secret underscore key.
We are going to throw new error.
Stripe secret.
Let's just copy this.
Paste it over here is required, but was not found in env variables.
And then below this, I'm going to say const Stripe is equal to new Stripe with process
dot env dot Stripe secret key.
So this is how we instantiate our Stripe variable so we can use it.
And so what we need to do is we need to create this create Stripe payment intent.
So this is if we want to use the Stripe payment system, we need to create a payment intent
on the back end, and we need to connect it to the front end as well.
So this is part of using Stripe and making sure everything works.
So we're going to do create Stripe payment intent.
We are going to do async with rec colon request.
That should be from Express and then res colon response.
That should be from Express as well.
So actually, we can go back to course controller.
I'm just going to copy and paste it.
We have everything.
So from promise, we're going to keep all of that like that.
Inside here, I'm going to do let amount is equal to rec dot body.
And we are also going to do if amount and amount is less than or equal to zero,
we are going to set to amount to be equal to 50, basically 50 cents.
The reason why we do this is because Stripe has a minimum of 50 cents.
There is.
I didn't get to the edge case, but you should be handling this on your own where you have
the amount in the course, like the course price should never be allowed to be set to
zero or if you have some kind of other configuration, we need to handle that edge case later on.
But for now, we're going to keep it like this so we don't get any kind of errors.
So we're going to remove all of this and we're going to say payment intent and we're going to
do a wait stripe dot payment intents dot create.
We're going to pass in the amount.
Currency is going to be in USD.
You can set it to whatever you want.
Automatic payment methods colon is going to be enabled to be true and allow redirects
should be never.
And finally, we do not want message.
Because we do not want like a message happening on the front end, so that's why we keep it
blank like that.
And in the data, we are going to.
Pass in the client secret, which is payment intent dot client secret.
So this gets sent to the front end and we want to use that for our information.
So over here we are just going to say error creating.
Stripe.
Payment intent.
All right, so this is necessary to make a connection to stripe when we first initialize
the stripe payment card checkout.
This is a very secure way and it fits into what's called the PCI DSS, you know, privacy
credit card information, making sure you are doing your handling users data in a very.
Safe way.
So with that, we created this endpoint.
We also need to create the routes, so we go to routes, create a new file.
We're going to create transaction routes dot TS.
And here we are going to copy everything from course, paste it over here so we can do the
same thing.
So here the endpoint is going to be stripe.
Slash.
Payment.
Dash intent and the rather should not be get it should be post and we are going to grab
create stripe payment intent from the controllers, remove all of these and remove this endpoint
right here.
And finally, we can now go to the index page, go to our routes and we're going to do app
dot use.
We're going to pass in slash transactions.
This should be definitely authenticated, so we are going to use require.
Off like so and we are going to pass in transaction routes which are not.
Defined, so we're going to go up here.
Transaction routes.
From dot slash routes.
Slash transaction routes like that.
OK, so now we can go back to our front end.
We can go to API dot TS and over here.
We can Scroll down.
And we can go over here and we can create a new endpoint and we're going to call this
crate stripe payment intent.
And like before, since now we've already have this example, we're just going to copy
this build mutation, paste it over here and we can modify things as we go.
So right here.
Instead of this being a user, this is going to be client.
Secret should be a string.
And then on this next line, this should be amount colon number.
In the query instead of user ID, this should be amount.
And with the URL is going to be slash transactions.
Slash stripe.
Slash payment.
Dash intent.
The method should be a post and the body should be.
An amount.
We do not need any tags for this, so we're creating a stripe payment amount or payment
intent, sending the amount to the endpoint that we just created.
And then from here, we need to create an endpoint for this, so we're going to do use
crate stripe payment intent mutation.
So that should be sent to our back end.
All right, so we're going to close all of this and I'm going to open up and go to our
front end.
So now all of this is going to happen on the non dashboard page.
So here I'm just going to create a new folder and we're going to call this checkout.
Inside the checkout, we're going to create a new file.
We're going to call this page dot TSX.
I'm going to close this up, do RAF, CE, and this should be called checkout wizard.
Now we first need to check if the user is loaded, so we are going to grab is loaded
from use user from clerk next JS.
And we are obviously, of course, going to make sure it is loaded.
So if it isn't loaded, we are going to return the loading component that we've created,
which is very nice and convenient.
And we're going to create something called render step, which is a function.
And this is going to return and this is going to determine the step that we are on for the
checkout.
So there is three steps.
The first step we're going to call the checkout details page.
Second is going to be the payment page.
And the third is going to be the completion page.
So I'm going to use a switch statement, which is not often.
And we are going to have this variable called checkout step.
So this will determine what step we are on in terms of the pages that we have.
So we haven't identified yet, but for now, we're just going to do return.
We're going to say checkout details page, and we're going to fill out the rest of it.
Case two is going to be a return payment page like so.
And then case three is going to be return completion page.
And then we always need to set a default and the default is just going to be return checkout
details page.
So for now, we'll get back to how we identified the checkout step because it is a little bit
of a logic challenge that we need to handle.
But first, let's set up the JSX over here.
We're going to give this a class name of checkout.
And then we're going to pass in a div with class name checkout_content.
In here, we're going to have a render step, and that's going to be what we created before.
So that's going to be displayed.
But we also need the wizard stepper.
So if you take a look at the checkout page, we have this stepper component right here.
Let me open this up.
We have the stepper component with details, payment, and completion.
So we need the logic to handle that aspect.
Whereas the render step represents everything under it.
So this is going to be dependent on the page we are at.
So I'm going to create a component called wizard_stepper.
And we are going to pass in the current step, which is the checkout step, like so.
So let's create that.
So I'm going to go over here, go to our components directory, create a new file,
and call this wizard_stepper.tsx.
Inside here, I'm going to do r-a-f-c-e.
And inside here, we need to pass in the prop that we just added,
which is the current step, with wizard_stepper_props.
Now inside here, I'm going to have a class name.
Oops.
Class name of wizard-stepper.
Now I'm going to copy right here, so because we are going to use that class multiple times.
And then in here, I'm going to do colon div class name wizard_stepper_container.
And we're going to do 1, 2, and 3.
So we have three steps.
So we're going to map this out with a step, comma, index.
And we're going to do an arrow function.
And we're going to return a react.fragment.
We're using the text react fragment this time because we need to pass in a key.
You cannot pass in a key without the react.fragment directly.
So inside here, we're going to have a div.
We're going to have a class name.
But this time, this is going to be cn_wizard-stepper_circle.
Now make sure you spell that correctly.
I'm going to copy this because we're going to use this multiple times.
Actually, let's copy this right here.
And then we're going to do comma.
And we're going to have different conditions.
So the wizard_stepper is a little complicated when it comes to the display of the colors.
And things like that.
So if the circle is completed, we are going to have a logic based on the current step.
If the current step is greater than the current step that we are at.
So if the current step is like one, or the current step is two,
but the step that we're talking about is the first step.
That's what we're talking about here for that condition.
If that's true, or if current step is equal to the last one, and step is equal to three,
we're going to use the completed CSS.
So this is when it becomes like a checkmark.
So if we're at step three, it's going to become a checkmark like this.
Over here, we're going to do wizard_stepper, circle for current.
So if it is the current one, which is current step is equal to step.
But if it's not equal to the final step, this is going to be what we are going to use.
So current represents a situation where it's going to be purple like this.
This is the purple color.
And for final condition is going to be the circle when it's upcoming.
So that means we are not at that step yet.
So that one's pretty simple.
Current step is less than the actual step we are at.
So we have these three different conditions for the different classes.
Whereas this is just like the base class.
We're going to add these different classes depending on what step we are.
A little confusing, but we had a lot of different conditions for each color.
And then in here, we're also going to have a situation where we check current step.
If it's greater than step, we are also going to do current step like this.
So basically, we're just going to copy this over here, paste it over here.
We're going to do question mark, pass in a check component from BlueSide React, which is an icon.
So class name is going to be width five, height five.
So we have a check mark when it's completed.
Otherwise, we're going to do a colon like so.
We're going to pass in span and then we're obviously going to pass in the step,
which is just a number.
And that's going to show the little check mark or basically a number.
Below this, we're going to have a p tag.
And this is going to be class name with CN once again.
And we're going to do wizard dash stepper underscore text comma and curly braces.
We're going to copy the wizard dash stepper once again.
Underscore text if it's active.
So now we're handling the text part of it.
The text color also needs to change.
So if it is current step is greater than or equal to step, we're going to give that active class.
Otherwise, we are going to do text dash dash inactive class if current step is less than step.
For the text, it's not as complicated because we don't need to do as many things.
And we also need to make sure we close this p tag.
And then we're going to have step if that's equal to one.
We're going to have details.
Just copy this two more times.
Change this to two changes to three.
This should be payment.
And this should be completion.
And we also need to add a div around like right below the react fragment.
We're going to do class name is equal to wizard stepper.
Underscore underscore step like this.
And we need to make sure we close that around the p tag over here.
And then finally, we have this line.
We need to make sure if it's completed, it's going to be green.
We're just going to do if index is less than two.
We're going to have a div.
And we're going to give it class name of cn wizard dash stepper.
Actually, you know what?
Let's just copy this entire thing that we had before because it's pretty similar to this one.
We're going to change the text to be line for all of these.
Then change this to completed.
And then this one should be incomplete.
And we're just going to reverse this current step should be greater.
And this one should be less than or equal to.
And then make sure we do a self-closing tag of the div.
So this determines the line for our stepper.
And so we have our stepper component.
We need to make sure we import it for our checkout wizard page.
And now we can start handling the checkout step logic.
So this will be determining the routing and the navigation for these three pages.
So what we're going to do is we're going to create a separate hook for this to keep it nice and clean.
So I'm going to go over here.
I'm going to say const checkout step.
And we are going to do use checkout navigation.
And this will be a hook that we create in our hooks folder.
And we're going to call this use checkout navigation dot ts.
All right.
So in here, we're going to do rafce.
We're going to have use checkout navigation.
And in this case, we're just going to change this to export const
use checkout navigation instead of using default.
Now, this is not a TypeScript component or it's not a React component.
So we're just going to remove the return.
We're going to do router.
And we're going to use navigation.
So basically use router from next slash navigation.
And then we're also going to grab the search params,
which is use search params.
And we are going to do const is loaded and is signed in.
And we're all going to grab this from use user from clerk next JS.
And we're going to invoke that as well.
And use search params should also come from next navigation.
So what I want to show you is the URL that we're using for the checkout pages.
So it's going to look like this checkout slash.
You don't have to write this.
We're going to have slash checkout, which and then the step that we are on
the course ID that we're using and whether we should show sign up.
Now, this show sign up is going to be representative
for this particular page right here.
So if you take a look, let me move this up.
If you take a look, this right here is the sign up page.
But then we also have the sign in component.
So if they already have an account, they can hit sign in,
but we don't want them to be navigated to the sign in sign up pages that we're
at earlier that we already created.
We want to keep them on this particular page.
So that sign up component becomes the sign in component.
And we keep that state in the URL via this show sign up.
Meaning true, that means we are on this page.
If it's false, we are on the sign in component.
And this is only applicable for step one, basically.
And then we also didn't mean to do that.
We also need to show the course ID as well.
So that determines what course they want to purchase.
So that's going to be held in the URL.
So with that, let's get started on figuring out this code.
So we're going to find the course ID via the search params.
So we're grabbing the ID from the URL.
And we're going to make sure it's at least double question mark
and instantiated with string to make sure we don't have any TypeScript errors
and make sure it is identified.
And then we also have checkout step.
Now, checkout step is when we grab it from the URL,
it's going to be a string, but we need the number version of this to use in our code.
So search params dot get, we're going to grab the step.
And we're going to instantiate to default to be one.
That's like the default.
And we're going to make sure this is a number.
So we have the checkout step number.
And we also need to do use effect.
We're going to make sure if the user is loaded
and if they are not signed in, and if the checkout step is greater than one,
we're going to do navigate to step one.
So this is basically a check.
Remember, we don't want them to hit this page, like the payment details page,
if they're not signed in.
If they try to hit completed, we also want to redirect them to this particular page.
That's what we're doing right here.
And what we need is to create that function, navigate to step.
And we're going to use a use callback from React to make sure this works.
And then we have step with a number.
We're going to do an arrow function.
And we're going to pass in new step, a math dot min.
So math dot max of one comma step comma three.
So we're just going to determine if the step is between one and three, essentially.
And we want to take the number that is lower than three.
We want to make sure we grab the step value if it's greater than two or three.
That's essentially what this is doing right here.
And making sure that it's never above three as well.
So this is kind of a weird way to do it, but it makes it easier.
And then from here, we're going to do show sign up.
And we're going to say if the user is signed in, we are going to put true for the string.
Otherwise, we are going to say false.
And it needs to be in string form.
So we do that using router dot push.
And we are now going to be able to grab this URL,
push all those values that we've created into the URL, and we can navigate there.
And then finally, what we need to do for use callback is pass in all the values that may change.
And we're going to pass in router like so.
And we do have an error with the semicolon.
So make sure you have that.
And use effect needs to be imported from React.
And we also need to make sure that it is correctly having the correct dependencies for redirecting.
So is signed in, checkout step, we're going to have navigate to step as well.
So this part is for making sure the user is signed in.
This part is the function that allows us to navigate to a specific step.
This is the functionality for that.
And whereas checkout step is the value that we grab from the URL,
and that is the current step we are at.
So this one hook is doing all of the navigation for our checkout.
And all we want to do is we're going to return the checkout step and the navigate to step function.
So this does basically everything we need in terms of navigation for the checkout page,
which is quite complicated.
And then we're going to make sure we import that.
All right, so from here, now we can lay out the specific steps of these particular pages.
So the first thing we're going to do is create the checkout details page.
Like so we're going to create a component for this.
So we're going to go back to our directory.
Inside our checkout, I'm going to create a component called checkout.
I'm going to create a component called details.
And this time, I'm just going to call this indexed.tsx.
We're not going to create a separate, you know, page.tsx.
This should be index.
We're going to do rafce.
I'm going to call this checkout details page.
Now inside here, I'm going to grab the search params
because we are going to try and grab the current course that we have selected.
So we're going to use use search params.
We're going to grab course ID, search params.get ID.
And if it doesn't exist, we just want to make sure we grab that edge case.
And we also want to grab the data of the course.
Like so.
And we are going to do use get course query.
We also need to pass in course ID into this particular hook.
Now this is going to be reused in another page.
And it's kind of a hassle to rewrite all of this.
So what I'm going to do is I'm going to open this up,
go to hooks component or hooks folder.
We're going to create a new file.
And we're just going to do use current course like so.
And we're going to do .ts.
And we are going to export const use current course like so.
We have an arrow function.
And we're going to paste in what we just wrote.
Make sure we import that.
Make sure we import this one.
And we're just going to do .rest.
So we can just grab everything that we need for the get course query.
If we need it, we're going to do return.
We're going to grab course course ID dot dot dot rest.
So this is just an easy way for us to grab the current course in multiple different files.
So if I were to go back to our checkout details page,
instead of having this, we can instead use use current course from the hooks.
And we can grab const course, which is the selected course that we have selected.
We're going to pass in is loading because that comes from the dot dot dot rest that we created.
And we're able to grab it all in one go with just use current course.
And we're doing this because we are using this in another file.
So we're going to do search params one more time.
And this time we're doing this because we're not incorporating it in the use current course
because this is just going to be used one time, which is for a const show sign up.
And this will determine whether we show the sign in component or the sign up component.
We're going to show sign up and this is going to be true like so.
And before we write out the elements we are going to do is loading.
Make sure we do return loading component.
Should return that if is error, we are going to return div failed to fetch course data.
And then if selected course is not returned, we are going to say return div course not found.
Sure, there's no space.
And now let's actually run up our server, make sure everything is working.
We're going to make sure we import checkout details page while we run our server.
We're going to go back, save this, and we are going to refresh.
And we're going to hit select or search courses, which will take us to this particular page.
And what we want to do is click on a role now.
And so once again, we need a use client directory.
And that's going to happen on the checkout details page right here.
So we're going to do use client and I'm going to get rid of this because we don't need that.
Save it. And we're going to go back, open up use checkout navigation,
because we need use client anytime.
We are using search param. And we're going to do this one by one.
We're going to go to checkout wizard because we're also using their use client as well.
And here, perfect. We have what we are seeing in here.
We see the checkout details page. So we see this.
So technically, when we're signed in, we should be redirected to payment page on step two,
but that's only when we have the component.
So when we create this sign in component, we are going to have this redirect URL.
That's going to take us to step two of the page if we are on this particular one.
So let's start by filling out our checkout details page code.
So inside here, I'm going to have a class name. I'm going to pass in checkout dash details.
Get rid of that. And then we're going to have another div.
We're going to do class name of checkout dash details underscore container.
I'm going to copy this right here so we don't have to rewrite it every single time.
So we're going to do div, paste that with preview.
And we are going to pass in the course preview we created a long time ago.
So course preview. Actually, sorry, we didn't create the course preview.
We created the accordion, but the course preview will have the accordion.
I think that's what I meant to say. So course, we are going to pass in selected course.
Now we're going to close this and we are going to create our course preview.
So I'm going to go over here. I'm going to open this up in the components,
create a new file, and we're going to call this course preview that TSX.
And call this RAFCE. And we are going to pass in the course that we did
and have it course preview props like so. And we are going to grab the price.
We're going to say format price, which is from Utils.
So we're going to have course dot price like so.
And we're going to be using that to create our course preview.
So this is pretty straightforward. We're going to have class name with course dash preview.
Once again, we're going to copy the class name and that value.
So we're going to have div class name course preview underscore container.
And then another div with class name course preview.
This is going to be the image wrapper.
And inside here, we're going to have an image from next image component.
We're going to do source is equal to course dot image.
And we're going to make sure we have some kind of placeholder.
We don't have a preview placeholder image. You can add that if you would like.
We're going to have a course preview as well. The width is going to be 640.
Height is going to be 360. Class name is going to be width of full.
We're going to make sure we close the image tag.
So. Get rid of the course preview text.
And right below the first closing div, we're going to have another div.
Set this to be H2 class name course preview underscore title.
Close that out with course dot title like so.
Go to the next line. We're going to do P tag with class name.
Actually, this time we don't need the course preview.
We can just do text gray 400 text MD margin bottom of four.
And we can say by course that teacher name.
Below this, we're going to have a P with class name is equal to text, small text,
custom graze, dirty. Gray like so.
As you can see, there's a lot of styling to it,
and that's why I'm using all these tailoring classes,
because it is quite the hassle to write all of them, because some of these classes,
well, some of them might be short like this one.
There are other ones that are super, super long in terms of the amount of classes that you need.
And I don't know how instructional that is.
That's why I created all these classes for those.
Below this, I have H4 tag. We are going to pass in class name once again, text white 50.
And if you wanted, you can do an opacity of 90.
So that's how you would do it with tail one.
We're also going to have font semi bold margin bottom of two.
Pass that in, call this course content, save it.
And then on this next particular line, we are going to do accordion sections.
And we're going to pass that in from the accordion sections that we created
a long time ago from the search page.
We're going to pass in course dot sections like so.
And we're almost done with this page.
So below the two closing divs, we're going to have another div right here.
And we're going to paste course preview underscore container.
Inside here, we are going to have an H3 class name of text, Excel margin bottom of four.
We're going to do price details of one item.
You can only buy one item at a time.
I did not add the functionality.
It's up to you.
If you want to make that a stretch goal, we could add this.
And it seems like this page, I particularly didn't create enough classes for all of these.
Don't know why.
But anyways, custom grays, dirty gray text base like so.
And inside here, I'm going to do a span with class name of font dash bold with string.
I'm going to do one X course title.
And I'm going to copy this, paste it over here.
I'm going to copy this entire thing, paste it over here like that.
Instead, this is going to be border T like that.
This is going to be border custom grays, dirty gray.
And this is going to be padding top of four font bold course title.
This should be a price.
Right here with the font bold, this should be total amount and the text should be large.
This should also be text large as well.
And we are going to put price as well over here.
We're going to save that and we're going to go back over here into our checkout details page.
Finally, import the course preview.
Refresh the page.
And now we should see the course preview on the left side.
Now, the other part is this guest checkout.
I don't normally do this, but I'm just going to copy and paste it.
You can pause it if you want to add it, but the functionality for this is not really there.
So I'm just adding it to show you this would be best practice on a checkout system.
It was just the scope became so out of control for this application that I just added this.
But I did not.
I'm not going to go through all of it.
Make sure we import all of this.
And right here below this closing div, I'm just going to call this stretch feature like so.
And I'm going to make sure we import from React hook form.
We're going to import custom form field.
We're also going to import button as well.
And I believe we are missing a closing div as well.
Oh, you got to be careful like I wasn't.
So import form from at components at slash components slash UI slash form.
So you want to import it from Shad CN, not react hook form because those are different.
So we'll have the guest checkout just like that.
Pretty simple.
Typically, you would have to save this information in your state and then use that later.
And then you would create a transaction.
But I didn't want to do that because it's just too much already.
And then after that, I'm just going to paste this.
This is only if you have the checkout.
You can pause it and just write this if you would like.
That gives us an or option.
And then below this, this is where we can actually put class name.
Checkout dash details underscore off.
Close this out.
We can do show sign up and we can pass in sign up component from not.
Let's redo this sign up should be coming from the sign up component that we created.
Not not the sign up component from directly from next clerk, basically.
But we want to do it from the one that we created.
So sign in component.
And we're going to do just like that.
So there you go.
With this, it's going to automatically redirect us on to checkout step two page.
And the reason why that's happening is because we have the component redirecting it if we're
signed in.
So if I go to step one.
So if we did, if you wrote step one, it should technically take us to step two of this page.
And by the way, I did make a mistake over here.
If you go to the sign in component, we actually need to set this to be and sign up to be true
for sign in.
Actually, this should be false or true, just like that.
And then over here for sign up, this should be and sign up should be false like this.
So the reason why we do this is so that we know if we go to directly to step one, but
we're signed in.
It's going to take us to the correct page.
Let's say enroll now.
It's not going to take us to the details page as we expect.
So this is perfect.
So let's say we sign out.
And we try to enroll in this specific course.
We try to enroll now, we would go to this particular page.
And if we tried to go directly to step two in the URL, it's going to redirect us to this
page because we need to sign in.
This is exactly how we wanted to do.
So let's say we signed in.
We are going to be taken to the payment page.
Let's try signing in one more time.
I want to show you one more thing.
If I hit sign up, it's going to take you to the sign up the same page with the sign up
component.
So it's a nice way to show our checkout flow.
So I'm just going to log in.
So take us to the payment page, which we'll work on next.
So I'm going to close all of this.
So from here, I'm going to go back to our checkout wizard and we're going to go over
here.
I'm going to call this payment page like so.
And inside our directory for checkout, I'm going to create another folder.
I'm going to call this payment and I'm going to create a file called index.tsx.
Call this RAFCE payment page content.
We're going to give it as content as well.
And then over here, I'm going to create another file.
I'm going to call this stripe provider.
We need this stripe provider for us to make it work with stripe.
So essentially, in our index file, we're going to create another component and we're
going to remove this export default.
I'm going to say const payment page, and this is going to be an arrow function and
we are going to wrap our stripe provider that we're going to create around our payment
page content.
So this is kind of how you would work with stripe provider.
You need to wrap it around payment page context because they are using react context to
provide state into payment page content.
Otherwise, you won't be able to use it.
So we have export default payment page.
So we're going to do that.
Now we're going to go to stripe provider and inside here, I'll just do RAFCE.
We're going to keep it like that.
But for now, we're going to go and deal with environment variables.
So process.env.nextpublicstripe public_key.
Make sure you spell this correctly.
So this is the environment variable that we set earlier.
So we're going to grab this next public stripe key.
Make sure that if it doesn't exist, we're going to throw a new error.
So we always want to make sure there's some error handling.
Otherwise, it's not going to work.
Is not set is what we'll say.
And below this, we need to create a stripe promise so we can load stripe as we need.
So we're going to do process.env.nextpublicstripe public_key.
And this load stripe is going to come from stripe.js.
And it apparently does not do IntelliSense.
Load stripe from @stripe/stripe.js.
So if we do that, we should be pretty good to go.
And stripe has basically some value that we need to use for appearance.
So we have an appearance variable.
And we're going to grab appearance from stripe.js for the typing.
And we can do theme to be stripe.
And then we're going to set variables for our properties.
So color primary.
So I've already set this styling basically up.
And in this case, I'm just going to paste it because this is kind of a hassle to write.
But you can pause the screen, take a look at all of these colors.
This is basically setting up our stripe component to look and feel consistent with our own brand.
OK.
So from here, we also need to pass in children for our stripe provider because we are using
a parenting style of React where we pass it in.
And over here, we are going to grab the client secret.
Now, if you remember set client secret or I mean the client secret that we talked about,
that is coming from our back end.
And we need to use that so that we can connect to stripe.
So this is the whole purpose of stripe payment intent.
It allows us to connect to stripe directly.
But we need to do it from our back end.
So we're going to do a string like this and make sure we import use state.
We're also going to grab create stripe payment intent.
And this is going to come from the mutation that we created for stripe payment.
And we're also going to grab our course with using use current course like so.
As I mentioned, we are using this hook multiple times.
And to use our payment, we need to actually use use effect.
Inside here, we are going to do if course doesn't exist, we're going to return.
But if it does exist, we're going to say fetch payment intent with async arrow function.
We're going to do result const result is equal to await create stripe payment intent.
We're going to pass in the mount colon course comma dot price.
But we need to handle the edge case just in case it doesn't exist.
And we're just going to put a ridiculously large number
so that no one can actually get charged if that were to happen.
Let's actually make this higher.
So this should be dot unwrap like so.
And then set client secret will be the result dot client secret that we set.
And finally, we are going to invoke that function we just created,
fetch payment intent.
And this will grab the stripe payment.
Dot price and then course, so these are the dependencies for the use effect.
So this is how you would use stripe provider.
This is essentially their process of doing so.
Then we need to set the options.
We're going to do stripe elements options.
We need to import that from stripe as well.
And we are going to set the client secret and appearance.
So those are the settings that we are passing into stripe.
And if client secret doesn't exist, we are going to return a loading component.
And inside our div, this should instead just be elements.
From react stripe JS.
So we need to import this manually elements from at stripe slash react stripe JS.
So this will allow us to give us the component like the card component directly.
And it makes it look pretty nice.
So stripe promise with options is equal to options like so.
And we need to pass in children.
So that gives us the stripe provider.
This is everything we need for it to connect to stripe directly from our UI to our back end and then to stripe.
So by doing so, we can now import stripe provider.
And from here, we can now create the payment page content.
So everything that we need to set up normally for this payment page, we can then implement over here.
But there are a couple of things that we are allowed to use now.
So that's going to include stripe from you stripe like so.
And const elements is equal to use elements like so.
So if we didn't set up the stripe provider around this payment page content as the children,
we would not be able to access these hooks.
That's why this particular section is necessary for us to create this payment page content.
All right, it is important.
From here, we're going to create a transaction.
And we're going to put this on halt.
So this is going to be a function that we'll create.
This is like an API call or create.
We'll just comment this out.
But for now, we are going to navigate to step.
We're going to use use checkout navigation to grab that function.
We're going to grab the course and the course ID.
Once again, this hook is very useful because it allows us to grab the course in one go.
And we're also going to grab the user from use user, which is coming from clerk next.
Yes.
And we're also going to handle the sign out functionality from use clerk.
And that will be provided for this particular page.
If you go over here, switch account.
If you hit this account, it's going to log you out and take you back to checkout step page one.
Make sure we import that correctly as well.
So over here, I'm going to make sure if is course is not logged out, we're going to return
null in this case.
And inside here, I'm going to do class name payment underscore like that.
I actually keep it like this for now.
Copy this because we're going to be reusing that class multiple times.
So I'm going to do div class name payment underscore container.
Close it out like that.
Let's get rid of this text because we don't need it.
And we're going to have again in order summary, which is the course preview.
And we're going to do div class name payment underscore preview.
Like we did before, and we can bring in course preview.
There's a reason why we created it in the components folder because we are going to
reuse it.
We can save that and then go to payment form as a comment.
It's nice to make sure we have kind of all of this separated out to make it easier.
We're going to have a div the class name payment form dash container.
Inside here, we're going to have a form with ID of payment.
Dash form.
With an on submit handler.
And we're going to do handle submit, which is a function we have not created.
So I'm just going to comment this out.
And I'm going to pass in class name payment underscore form like so closed out the form
component.
And over here, we have a div class name payment underscore content.
So have an H1 tag class name payment underscore title.
Close this out with checkout.
And then we're going to have a P tag class name payment sub title.
And we're just going to say fill out the payment details below to complete your purchase.
And then below the P tag, we're going to do another div class name payment underscore
method.
And we're going to have an H3 tag class name payment underscore method dash title.
This should be the payment method.
Below this H3, we're going to do a div class name payment card.
Didn't mean to do that payment underscore card dash container.
Close this out.
We're going to have another div class name payment underscore card dash header.
Close this.
And we're going to pass in credit card, which is a Lucid React icon with a size of 24.
Close this out.
Have a span of credit slash debit card.
And then below this, we're going to have a div class name payment underscore card dash
element.
And we're going to have a payment element component from React Stripe JS.
So all of this work is so that we can use the payment element component, which will
provide us with a nice little component that makes it easier to have an input from Stripe
so that they can put their credit card information.
And it makes it look pretty nice.
So now there's a lot of closing div tags.
What we want to do is go all the way after the second closing div tag from the form and
below or above the last closing div.
And we are going to add the navigation buttons over here.
So over here, we're going to have a div the class name payment actions like so.
We're going to pass in button component from ShadZn.
Give it a class name of hover with background white of 50 with 10 opacity on click.
We are going to do handle sign out and navigate.
So we have not created that yet, but that's going to handle the sign out for the switch
account button.
So we're going to have a variant of outline with a type of button like so.
And we're going to say switch account.
And then finally, we are going to have one more button.
I'm just going to copy this to make it easier.
But this time, this is going to be a form with payment form type should be submit this
time.
Because this one will be the one to submit the actual form that we created with the class
name payment underscore submit.
We're going to get rid of the variant, get rid of this on click, and we are going to
set disabled if stripe or elements has not been loaded.
So this is going to say pay with credit card.
And then let's go back to checkout wizard and we are going to import payment page and
let's double check how it looks.
So this is our payment page.
We have the course preview that we already know and see the sections.
And then now we can see that we have credit debit card, secure checkout with link.
I don't know if you'll see that.
Not exactly sure if you'll see that.
I think that's only if you're on the Brave browser.
OK, it is not a brave browser.
If you go to create next app, basically, if you go to this page where you're in settings
and then you go to payments, payment methods, it'll show you the things that you are on.
You have this link.
You can deactivate it if you want, but all the settings for your payment checkout is
going to be based on the settings that you have in your stripe dashboard, which is pretty
nice.
So, yeah, so we'll have this basically and we'll have pay with credit card, switch account
if we want to log out and this should be pretty much all set.
Now, like I said before, with the handle submit, it's going to involve a number of things.
If you go back over here, we need to create a transaction.
We need to create a stripe payment.
We need to create a course and we need to do create a user course progress.
So let's actually go back to our back end and let's set all of that.
Up before we create our handle, submit component, handle, submit function.
So on our back end, we're going to go to controllers.
We're going to go back to a transaction controllers and right above or right below the create
stripe payment intent.
We can create another function and let's just let's just copy this entire thing right here.
And then we could just erase everything inside.
We don't really need all of this, but we're going to call this create transaction.
With the lowercase r.
Inside of here, we're going to grab a lot of information from the front end.
So that includes user ID, course ID, transaction ID, the amount and the payment provider.
And we're going to grab this from rec.body.
So the first step we need to do is get course info and we need to grab the course info so
we are able to grab and update our course appropriately or to make sure that the course
exists and so that we can connect it to our transaction.
So we're going to do course.get course ID and we need to make sure we import the course
from our models directory.
Then we need to create transaction record.
So the way we create our transaction record, we can just do a new transaction and we are
going to set transaction, which is going to come from our transaction model.
And we are going to put every property, you know, like date time.
So we need to set a new date to iso string for the time of our transaction.
We also need to set the user ID, course ID, transaction ID, amount and payment provider.
And then we do that, we create the transaction, but we also need to save it into our database.
So that takes care of this part right here.
So this creates the transaction.
And if you want to double check, we can go to the transaction model.
This includes all the properties that we have.
So it makes a lot of sense.
Oops, didn't mean to do that.
Then we also need to create the user course progress right here.
So to do that, we're going to do initial progress.
And this is why we needed to fetch the course information.
Otherwise, we would not be able to create this.
So we're going to do new user course progress.
Passing an object with user ID, course ID, enrollment date is going to be the same thing
that we have over here with the new date, meaning it is the current time.
With an overall progress of zero, meaning they just started.
And then we are also going to pass in sections.
Now sections is probably the most complicated part of courses because it is very nested.
We have section colon any, and we're going to have an arrow function.
And we are passing in an object with section ID with section dot section ID like so with
chapters and then section dot chapters dot map with chapter colon any.
And then we have an arrow function like so chapter ID colon chapter dot chapter ID.
And I know it's a little ridiculous, but for every time we need to track the progress of
each chapter and we'll go more in details for this.
But this is just updating the initial progress.
We're just setting this up.
And we're also going to do last accessed timestamp.
Like so timestamp.
Paste the new date ISO string.
And we are missing in closing parentheses, so make sure you have the correct parentheses
right there.
And then we're going to do a wait initial progress dot save.
So we save that.
And then that takes care of the user course progress.
But we also need to add the enrollment to the specific course.
And that one's pretty simple this time.
So we're going to do a wait course dot update.
And we are going to pass in course ID like so.
And we can do this simple dollar sign add colon enrollments.
And pass in an array with object of user ID.
So let's save that.
So for here, I'm just going to say create initial course progress.
It's better if we have these steps written in comments.
Add enrollment to relevant course.
So we now have everything we need that we set up.
We just don't have the Stripe payment.
We haven't created the Stripe payment directly on the front end.
But that will happen in the component that we created earlier.
So this res dot JSON, we're going to have a message.
We're going to say purchase course successfully.
Like this.
And the data should be transaction would be a new transaction like so.
And we can also pass in course progress to be the initial progress that we saved.
And then below this, we can say error creating transaction and enrollment.
So that will be our transaction.
That covers everything we need when we create a Stripe payment.
So this is all important.
It's a lot of data in different tables.
And we basically needed all of those.
So we can now go back to transaction routes.
And over here, we're just going to do router dot post with it.
Empty domain, we're going to say create transaction, grab it from the controllers.
So that sets up our routes, close both of these.
And then we can now go back to our API.
Let me close this out.
We can set a little endpoint in our API Redux toolkit query, call this create transaction.
We're going to call this copy this build dot mutation, we're going to put transaction.
And we're going to put partial transaction.
So that's what we are going to send to the back end.
Put an object, we're going to do query with transaction inside here.
Return an object that says URL transactions like so.
This is going to be a method of post with the body of transaction that we will send.
We don't need any kind of tags for this.
So we can scroll down, go over here, and we can say use create transaction mutation.
And now we can close these guys out, except for this payment page content.
We're going to open this up and import our mutation from our API.
So we now have this create transaction function that we can use.
So the first thing I want to handle is the handle submit.
What happens when we click the pay with credit card from the front end.
So we're going to have a handle submit async with e dot react dot form event.
You're going to use an arrow function like so.
You're going to do e dot prevent default.
And if stripe or elements does not exist, we are going to say toast error and make sure we
grab the toast from Sunner.
And we are going to give it a string of stripe service is not available.
Good to have these error checks.
So we're going to return.
And then we're also going to do result is equal to a weight stripe dot confirm payment.
Elements.
So that grabs the elements information like the inputs that we had.
They already handle it behind the scenes.
And we're going to confirm the params of return URL.
And we are going to use the process dot env dot.
Next.
Public.
So this is the environment variable that we created.
Stripe redirect URL.
We're going to have an ID, of course.
ID like so.
And we are going to make sure redirect if required.
So this right here is that stripe payment.
This is where we are creating this stripe payment directly on there.
And finally, we want to say if result dot payment intent dot status has succeeded.
Just to double check.
We can now create the transaction data that we need to send to the back end.
And we're going to make sure we type it correctly.
And then we have transaction ID with the result payment ID.
So the transaction ID is coming from stripe payment ID.
So if we ever need to grab information from stripe about the payment transactions,
this is the ID that we're using.
And it's coming directly from stripe.
So it's important to understand that our transaction table basically has connections
to the stripe information.
This is very important.
Sometimes you really do need the link so that you are able to grab user transaction information
from stripe.
Otherwise, you have no way of knowing which users are which, which is very bad.
And then also for the user ID, that's going to come from clerk.
So we have the user dot ID.
Course ID is obviously the course ID that was selected.
And it's coming from the search params.
Payment provider.
In this case, we're only having stripe.
So it's pretty redundant.
But if you ever wanted to add things like PayPal, you can have this as different.
And the amount of this is course dot price.
Otherwise, we're going to set this to be zero.
We're going to set await create transaction.
And we're going to pass in transaction data.
And we are going to navigate to step three.
So after our transaction completes, we are going to go to step three.
And that's pretty much our handle submit.
This is everything we need to do.
So if we go down, we see our on submit, we have our handle submit.
So that will handle our payment.
And then finally, for the switch account, we're going to have handle sign out and navigate
function, which we are going to set is going to be an arrow function.
Like so we're going to do await sign out is coming from that function.
And we are going to navigate to step one like this.
And we're going to scroll down to this button on comment what we did earlier.
And we did spell this wrong.
The end should be capitalized.
And over here, we're going to do 424242.
So if you want to test out stripe, you would use 42424242 like that.
And I'm just going to put 033.
It doesn't after this.
It doesn't really matter.
This allows you to basically, basically just use any value that you want.
So as long as you use this one, which is stripes test account, this you should be good to go.
We can ignore that and we can select pay with credit card and say no thanks.
And when it says purchased course successfully, that means everything should have worked as
expected.
And the way we can check is if we go to no SQL workbench, we can go back to our connection
and we can test out to see if we got a new transaction.
And right here is what we just, you know, added.
This is specifically new date that we had.
Otherwise everything else is 320.
So this is all like mock data.
But the one we just created was today right here, 2024, three right here.
So yeah, everything is working expected.
So let's get to the completion page.
So we're going to open up right here, create a new folder.
Oh, I did not mean to do that.
Let's create a new folder called completion and create a new file called index, index.tsx.
And inside our checkout wizard, we're just going to do completion page like so.
We haven't created it yet.
So we're going to create it completion page.
And this should be pretty simple.
We're just going to have a class name with completion.
Remove this completion page text.
We're going to have a div class name.
I'm going to copy this right here.
So it's easier for us to finish this content like so.
We're going to have another div completion icon like so.
And then we're going to import check from Lucide React.
We're going to have a class name with width of 16, height of 16.
We're going to close that out.
Below this, I'm going to have an h1 tag class name, completion title.
We're going to do completed.
And below this, we're going to have a p tag completion underscore message like so.
And you can have this emoji right here.
I just copied and pasted it.
You can figure out how to do that.
I'm going to say you have made a course purchase success fully.
I'm going to paste that.
And then below this, we're going to have another div.
Oops.
Completion like so with support.
We're going to have a p tag.
We're going to say need help contact our string with space.
We're going to import a button from ShadCN.
With a variant of link as child class name with padding of zero, margin of zero, text
primary of 700.
We're going to have an a tag with href is equal to mail to colon support at example.com.
We're going to put custom or support and put after all this, a period.
Close this out with a div.
We're going to have class name, completion action.
And finally, just a link from next.
Href should be user slash courses.
And we can do go to courses.
I'm going to save that.
Go to our page with checkout wizard.
Make sure we import that correctly.
And for this safe return, we're just going to just place checkout details page just for that.
Once we have set that, we have our completion page.
Now, as the last part of the checkout flow, we want to create this particular table of
grabbing the transactions from our database and putting it in the billing page.
So we just want to do that.
So we need to create an endpoint that list all the transactions.
And then we just need to create the UI on the front end for those transactions.
So we're going to go back to transaction controller.
We're going to go up, copy all of this once again.
And we're just going to go and paste all of this information.
Remove everything over here.
Remove all of this.
And we are just going to say list transactions.
And from here, we want to grab the user ID, which is going to be passed as a query string.
So rec.query.
So we're going to grab that information from the URL.
So const transactions is going to be user ID.
We're going to await a transaction.query.
Grab the user ID.
We're going to make sure it's equal to user ID.
And we are going to execute.
And then we are also going to await transaction.scan.execute,
making sure the transactions all grab the transactions.
So this allows us to either grab the entire list of transactions,
or if we have the user ID, then we just grab that user.
So basically, it is optional and it serves a multifunction for this particular endpoint.
In this case, we just need the user ID.
So over here, we're going to say transactions retrieved successfully.
This should be plural, like so.
And the data should be remove the object.
It should just be transactions, like so.
And we can say error retrieving transactions, like that.
It should be simple enough.
Now we're going to go back to transaction routes.
Go over here.
This should be pretty simple.
Router.get with a slash.
We're going to do list transactions and grab it from our endpoint.
So this should be very, very simple.
And now we're going to go to our front end.
Go to our API.
And go over here, right above the create stripe payment intent.
We're going to do get transactions.
And we're going to do build.query.
We're going to pass in the transaction interface.
That's going to be returned from the back end as an array.
And we're just going to pass in the string for our query.
And then we're going to have a user ID is what we're going to be using.
And that will be part of the query string when we call our back end.
So user ID is equal to user ID, like so.
I'm going to grab that.
And then we're going to scroll down.
We're going to do up here, use get transactions query, like so.
All right.
So from here, we can go to our app.
We can go to dashboard.
From here, we have user.
We're going to create a new folder.
And we're going to call this billing.
Inside here, I'm going to create a new file.
I'm going to call this page.tsx.
I'm going to close that up.
And over here, I'm going to do rafce.
This is going to be the user billing page.
Inside here, we're going to set a payment type.
We're going to set the payment type as well.
Let's make sure we capitalize that.
We're going to use state from React.
We're going to do all, like so.
And over here, I'm going to set user is loaded.
And set use user.
So this is grabbing the user from our Next.js application.
Because we need that user information so that we can make an API call
for the transactions relevant to our users.
So we're going to do is loading.
But this is going to be set to is loading transactions
because it's different from the other one.
We don't want to get it confused with this one.
So here, we're going to do use get transactions query.
And I'm going to put this on the next line.
And over here, we're going to do user question mark ID.
If it doesn't exist, we're going to have an empty string.
However, what we want to do is make sure this doesn't get called
until user ID is identified.
So you can use something called skip.
And because this, you can't really control like the timing of the React component sometimes.
Skip is a nice way to make sure we make the API call under certain conditions.
So if it isn't loaded and the user does not exist,
we're not going to make this API call.
That's exactly what the skip function is doing.
So that's why we pass this in.
So until this happens, then user ID will get passed after those conditions are met.
OK.
So from here, and it's one of the nice things again about Redux toolkit query.
So we have filtered data.
And we are going to pass in transactions.
And we're just going to do a quick little filter.
For the transaction with an arrow function.
So we're just filtering and we're just filtering to make sure matches the type that we have,
which is payment type.
Make sure it is equal to all of them.
Otherwise we say transaction.paymentProvider is equal to payment type.
Otherwise we just return matches type as well.
And we just want to make sure we have at least an empty array.
So basically we're just filtering based on the payment type.
It doesn't really do anything because we only we do only have one payment type.
But just in case if you ever wanted to expand this application, then you can do so.
And over here, we're going to return loading from the component loading.
And if user does not exist, we're going to return div.
Please sign in to view your billing information like that.
All right.
And then from here, we're going to write the div.
Again, we're going to have class name billing like so.
And make sure we copy that so we can use it for our div.
Div class name billing_container with h2 class name billing_title payment history.
And then div class name billing_filters.
And then we're going to import select drop down from add components UI select from shadcn.
And we're just going to pass in value with payment type.
And on value change is the function.
We just need to set payment type like so.
Close that.
And we are going to set the select trigger from add components UI select.
We're going to paste billing select like so.
Make sure we have the right styling.
And then select value should come from add components.
Again, placeholder is going to be payment type.
And we're going to make sure we close that.
And then from here, we're going to do select content.
And again, make sure you import it from shadcn.
We're going to do class name billing_select-content.
Inside here, we're going to have select item.
So that's also going to be imported from shadcn.
Class name billing_select-item with value of all.
And we make sure we close that.
And inside here, I'm going to say all types.
And it seems like I did not correctly import it.
So make sure to do that.
I'm going to copy paste this two more times.
The value should be stripe.
And let's say if we actually added PayPal, we're going to keep it like that.
By the way, I did add PayPal before, but it was just too much to handle in terms of scope.
The scope just blew another control for this application.
Not exactly sure why.
Anyways, so we have a div.
And I want to copy the billing over here once again with class name billing.
And this time, it's going to be a grid.
Inside here, this is going to be our table component.
So our table component right here.
And we're just going to use simple shadcn table.
And I'm going to pass in is loading transactions.
So over here, if it's loading transactions, we're going to add the loading component.
And like I said, it is super useful because we are reusing that loading component.
And it is very useful for multiple types of scenarios.
All right.
So in here, if it is loaded, we are going to add table component.
And we're going to grab it from shadcn table.
Pass in billing table like so.
Then we're going to pass in table header.
Get it from shadcn.
Class name billing table dash header.
And then table head.
Pass that in.
Pass in the billing table dash cell.
Close that.
And I did miss one, which is table row.
So that should also come from the table component with class name billing table dash header dash row.
Pass that in.
And we need to make sure the table head is within the table row.
We're going to pass that in three times inside the table row.
Save it so it is unified or linted correctly.
And then here in the table head, we're going to have date amount and payment method.
That's good.
And then below this header, we are going to add table body shadcn component with class
name billing underscore.
Table dash body.
Now, the only downside about using shadcn is that you end up having a lot of these components.
I know it makes it more composable and more modular, makes it usable in different ways.
But it is sometimes kind of a pain.
I mean, there's always trails, right?
So anyways, filter data length is greater than zero.
So if we have any kind of value, we're going to use filter data dot map pass in transaction
using arrow function with table row.
Like so past.
Oops.
Not to do that.
Table row like that.
Let's just close that in because we are going to pass in a few things.
Billing table dash row.
But we also need to add a key, which is going to be transaction dot transaction ID.
Over here, we're going to add table cell.
Pass that in from shadcn class name billing table dash cell.
And we are going to copy this two more times.
And over here, it's going to be billing underscore amount.
And over here, we are just going to leave it.
But inside this particular table cell, we are going to add a date.
New date object with transaction dot date time.
Time to convert it to the correct date string on the front end.
So we pass that in.
And over here, we are going to do format price.
Make sure you import that transaction.
Dot amount.
And then over here in this table cell, we are going to do transaction payment.
Provider if it's equal to stripe.
Actually, we are just going to set it to the string.
That should be good.
And then finally, we actually have another condition.
So if we do not have any values, we want to pass in table row with class name.
Like so with billing underscore table dash row.
We're going to close that out.
Pass in table cell.
Let's actually grab one of these.
Paste it over here.
And then we are just going to add a property called text center.
Like so with column span of three.
Inside here, we are just going to add no transactions.
No transactions to display.
And over here, we did miss a few closing parents.
So make sure you have two of those.
And when we save it, this page should be pretty good now.
So everything is as expected.
Now let's double check.
Let's see if our server is running.
So our servers are running.
We're going to go click manage account.
Click manage account.
That takes us to the profile page.
But now we can check out the billing page.
So again, use state.
I always seem to forget.
We're going to put use client as well.
So now we do have some kind of error.
All right.
So we do have an error.
And that's because this is singular.
The URL should be plural.
So as you can see, when you have this error,
I just wanted to remind you that you can see this error happening,
which is very, very good.
You can see why we get an error.
And by doing so, we have our custom base query telling us that we got some kind of error.
So if I were to look get transaction, that's because this should be plural right here.
So let's refresh the page.
And there you go.
We have our list of transactions and everything is as expected.
If we were to do PayPal, should be no transaction.
If we do all types, Stripe should be working perfectly.
Now we want to do the exact same thing for the teacher.
So let's do that really, really quickly.
We don't need to double check because we're just going to copy this entire page.
Go over here to the teacher page, create a new folder called billing.
Inside here, I'm going to create a new file.
I'm going to call this page.tsx.
And I'm just going to paste it over here.
Scroll up.
Select both of these with Command D.
I'm going to do teacher billing, like so.
Save it.
And most of this should be a single transaction.
And most of this should be pretty identical.
You know what?
It is basically identical, except for the name of the component.
So you can leave it like that.
So the teacher can have a billing history in case the teacher also bought something as a user.
So just to be clear, you can create a reusable component.
I just didn't get the time to do that.
So you can use a reusable component that applies to both of these.
So you don't have to repeat the same code.
All right.
So looking to our completed application, the next part we're going to do is handling edit course
and creating a course.
This is actually a little more complicated than you would expect because our course,
our course data is very, very extensive.
There is courses, there are sections, there's a chapter, there's even comments.
But it's pretty extensive.
And it's going to include also videos that we need to upload onto S3.
So let's take a look at the final application on how this is supposed to look like.
So when you create a course, it's going to create a default course like so.
But it's also going to take you to the edit page.
So the course is more like kind of like a draft where you can have a course,
whether it's not drafted versus whether it's published or not.
So you'll have a course, you can set up the course title, description.
I'm just going to put random things over here.
It doesn't really matter.
But then when you add a section, you can have that saved over here.
But you can also add a chapter for each section.
So this is kind of like the way Udemy has their setup.
But then over here, we have a chapter video.
And let's just put a random video up here.
When you hit save, what's going to happen is that this doesn't save the sections into the backend.
Right now, all the data you see here, this is stored on the front end.
This is for more of a UX perspective.
And we are going to store this state into Redux.
And the reason why we don't store this into the backend is because
if you just constantly make API calls just for any kind of little edit
to make it consistent between front end and backend,
whereas some people don't want you to store any kind of like front end state.
This is problematic because a lot of times when you have the save draft,
that's the user experience that most people expect.
When you save it, that is what you are saving onto the backend.
Anything here is ephemeral, temporary.
So you want to make sure none of this gets saved until someone hits save draft.
And this is kind of what we'll create.
And this is a very common user experience that you see
when you have something that's very large.
You don't want to publish it right away.
These are the type of user experiences that people expect.
And we're going to have that basic flow.
So to start off, we're going to have to create our backend.
And that's going to include different aspects,
such as creating the course and then updating the course
and also a separate endpoint for uploading video.
So let's get started with all of that.
Let's move all of this.
We're going to open up our directory.
We're going to close the client directory.
And we are going to go straight to course controller.
And below our get course, we're going to copy this.
And I'm going to paste it over here because we're going to create a new function.
And we're going to call this create course like so.
Inside here, I'm going to get rid of all of this.
And we're just going to get rid of most of this information.
We don't need it.
So what we're going to grab from the body is we're going to grab the teacher ID
and the teacher name because we need to grab that from the front end.
And then if teacher ID does not exist, or if the teacher name doesn't exist,
this is just extra validation.
We're just going to send to the front end that the message of teacher ID and name are required.
Otherwise, we're just going to have an error check,
making sure that people can't log in unless they're the correct teacher
or they have specified a teacher.
All right.
And then from here, we're just going to create a new course.
So as you saw the flow earlier, where we have the course, we create the course first.
We're just going to put the course with, you know, default values.
This is exactly what we're going to be doing over here.
And the first thing we want to do is we're going to import the UUID.
So we're going to say V4 as UUID V4.
And we're going to grab that from UUID.
Because when we create a course, we need a unique value.
That's what we're setting as the course when we create it.
And then from here, we're going to set the teacher ID as well as the teacher name
with the title being Untitled Course with a description of an empty string,
category of Uncategorized.
And then we're going to have an image.
We're going to not have an image for this.
We're going to have a price of zero with a level of beginner and status being a draft.
Initially, there's only draft and published for this.
And then we're also going to have sections, which is going to be an empty array,
as well as enrollments, which is also going to be an empty array.
And then from here, we're just going to do a wait new course dot save to save our course
that we just created.
And then on the front end, we're just going to set or send back the new course.
And we're just going to say new course or create course created successfully.
And we're going to say error creating course if there is a problem.
So that's pretty straightforward.
Now, what happens if we want to update the course when we hit that save draft, that save button,
then we need another function for this because this is creating the course,
but we want to update and change that information.
So that's going to be a separate endpoint.
So I am once again going to copy all of this, paste it over here,
and we are going to change a number of things.
So this is going to now be called update course.
We're going to change or we're going to grab some values that we grab from the front end.
So the front end is going to need to send us to the back end, the course ID through params.
And remember, params is more required value from the front end.
And then update data is going to be just the entire request body.
So like all the extra information that we're grabbing.
And also, we also want to grab the user ID as well,
and we can just grab that from Clerk Express.
So we just grab that as well.
That's more authentication purposes.
And we want to make sure we know that we are using the correct user.
And then from here, I'm going to do const course await course dot get course ID.
So we just we're going to grab the course based on the course ID.
So we have all of the information that we currently have on our back end, just to make sure, you know.
And then if the course does not exist, we are going to do res dot status.
404 dot JSON, we're going to say message is course not found, and we are going to return.
We're going to remove all of this right here for the if statement.
And we also need to check if course dot teacher ID does not equal to user ID.
So we need to make sure the user ID that is authenticated is the teacher.
So this is very good and important because creating a course and having it published,
it needs to be very correct.
So having very secure functionality for this is important.
So we're just going to say not authorized to update this course.
We're going to have that and we are going to return.
And then from here, we're just going to remove everything we did before.
And we just need to do one thing about the price because the price needs to be stored as basically
a number like an integer instead of decimals, because when you have a price,
you have if you're using US dollars, for example, you have fifteen dollars dot zero zero.
You need to convert that to fifteen hundred.
So we're basically multiplying it by one hundred.
This is important because you don't want to have integer issues.
So this should be update data, by the way, so const price is equal to parse int.
Update data dot price, we're going to keep it like that.
So if price is not a number, we're just going to do some checks to make sure everything works.
We're going to do res dot status 400 just in case we have a non number.
It's important to check stuff like this because pricing is a very important issue.
And then we're going to send an error to the front end.
Price must be a valid number.
From here, we're going to say return and below this, we're going to say update
data dot price is equal to price times one hundred.
So once we know it's a number, we're going to multiply it by one hundred, which is very important.
And then from here, we're going to update data dot sections.
Const sections data is equal to type of update data dot sections.
If this is equal to a string, we're going to parse it because when we have sections,
it's possible that we are sending a parsed version of the sections, which is a bunch of arrays.
So yeah, let me let me go through this real quick.
So if you go to the course model, you can see that we have a bit of a complicated scenario.
It's better to look at the seed data because this will automatically show in JSON format
of what we're looking at.
So for every course, we have a sections property.
So every section is going to have an ID title description and another property of chapters.
So it's basically a bunch of nested arrays with objects that have another nested array
and objects.
So every chapter is going to include all of this information.
And we're going to include all of that for every chapter for every section.
It's going to have its own set of chapters.
And chapters can have content as well as the video URL.
So this is kind of how this is set up.
So now I'm there might be a better way to set this up, better way to organize it.
I originally thought, you know, course, you can have that in one go.
But after doing it, after building this application, you know, it is possible that there
might be a better option by having a chapter individually.
That is the beauty of data modeling and schemas is that there's multiple ways, multiple
possible solutions that might be better.
But a lot of times there are a lot of tradeoffs.
The biggest negative downside of this is that when you're handling these sections, when
you want to modify it, you have to dig deep through this nested array or nested objects
as well to figure out what you want to change.
Like if you wanted to update this video, you have to go through the sections, then you
have to figure out chapters, then you have to do that video.
It is quite the pain and gets code a little bit convoluted and hard to understand sometimes.
So just getting you aware, because there's going to be some crazy logic happening.
And that's mostly because I'm just trying to find the right property.
That's all it is.
Nothing too fancy there.
So update that data of sections is what we're going to parse.
And we're going to do update data dot sections.
So this is if it's parsed or not.
And then from here, we want to remove the ID in case we want to replace it.
So let's grab the updates data.
It'll make sense when I write this out.
We're going to grab the sections data dot map.
We're going to grab the section.
We're going to put in any tag for now.
And we're going to do arrow function.
We're going to.
So we're going to spread out the sections array.
We're going to pass in the section ID and section ID.
If it doesn't exist, we are going to pass in UUID for.
So this is if it doesn't exist.
Otherwise, we just pass in what already exists for the ID.
And then we're also going to have the chapters.
We're going to replace section dot chapters with another map.
Chapter colon any with the nested or with the return object.
And we're going to spread out the chapter.
As well as a chapter ID.
So you're going to grab chapter of chapter ID, pass in UUID V4 and execute that.
So this is basically how we update the sections that we want.
So we cycle through every section.
Make sure we update that data.
And we can then replace whatever information we need.
We're also going to have to replicate the object.
So we're going to do object assign, grab the course.
That we have over here and we are going to pass in update data.
So we're basically replacing it with a new object.
And then once we're done with that, we are going to do a wait course dot save.
So we replaced our course with new information.
I know this part is a bit tricky, but for the most part, we're just merging our sections
together with the new data.
That's the main thing you have to understand.
And this should be just course.
And we can say course updated successfully and an error updating.
So now we have the update.
And for this course, we're doing the full crud.
So we're also going to do delete course.
So I'm going to go back, copy this over here from the create course, scroll down below
the update course, paste it.
And we are now going to call this delete course.
In here, or at least above the tribe block, we're going to do const course ID.
We're going to do rec dot params, do const user ID.
And we are again, grabbing that from get off, get the request, pass it in there.
And over here in this tribe block, we're going to do const course is equal to a weight
course dot get course ID.
So we're just double checking.
And again, let's scroll up because I don't want to rewrite this once again.
Copy all of this and we can replace everything over here.
And then we're going to change this to not authorized to delete this course.
Again, these are just safe checks.
Otherwise, it's pretty simple.
I'm going to remove this, say a weight course dot delete course ID.
And the message should be course deleted successfully.
And we don't need to bring any kind of data for this particular situation and error
deleting course.
So now if you take a look, we have course over here, we have update course, but this
does not handle uploading video.
And we're not going to do that just now.
We're going to do that a little bit later once we get to the S3 buckets.
And so we can upload onto our S3 buckets when we deal with more AWS things.
So for now, we're going to keep it like this.
And then we are now going to create course routes.
So if I go back to course routes over here, we need to add all the routes that we have
just created.
So below the list course, I'm going to do router dot post.
And over here, when we want to create a course, we want require auth.
And we want it specifically for this route.
And we want to import that.
So if you remember, we did require auth over here, which will gatekeep users, clerk and
all the transactions, but we didn't do it for course routes.
That's because we want it specifically for certain routes in our application.
So this is how we do that.
And then from here, we need to add the other ones.
So we're going to do router dot put slash colon course ID.
We're going to do require auth as well over here.
And this is where we're going to use something called malter.
Malter makes it so that we can upload files and images.
And it basically stores it temporarily until we upload it onto AWS.
So what we need to do is set up this malter.
And we are going to use malter dot memory storage and invoke it and make sure we import
malter.
So we're going to import malter from malter like so.
And I really thought I installed this.
So we're just going to cancel out our server.
We're going to do NPMI malter like so.
And I do think I did install it.
I just didn't install the @types/malter.
So you need the TypeScript types for malter so it doesn't yell at you.
And there you go.
We're going to run back our server up, close this terminal out, and then go back to upload
over here.
We have the upload working correctly.
But over here with the course, we are going to set upload dot single image like so.
And we are going to update our course.
Now, I ran out of time.
Originally, I was going to have the image upload, but things again were ballooning out
of control.
So I did not input this.
But for your sake, if you ever want to upload, we're going to be using this.
This malter will be used later on for uploading video.
So it's not completely useless in this regard.
And finally, we're going to do router dot delete colon course ID as well.
Require auth.
We're going to invoke that.
And we're going to bring in delete course.
So we now have CRUD functionality for our courses essentially.
All right.
So now we can move on to the front end.
So let's go over here.
We're just going to close everything out.
And now we can go to our client directory, go to source, go to API, and we can make our
connections to our back end.
So we're going to go back up to where we have all our courses, and it's a good time to start
organizing all our courses.
So I'm just going to copy this over.
You can see I have courses like this, and I'm going to paste it over here.
User clerk.
This is just a better way to organize your endpoints.
You can create different slices if you want to organize it that way.
But I prefer to have it in one location because it is not too many.
And we're going to keep it like this.
And then from here, I'm just going to copy the create transaction because the first one
we're going to handle is going to be update video or update course.
I'm sorry.
So update course.
This is going to be build on mutation.
We're going to pass in a course over here.
And on the next line, I'm going to pass in an array or actually an object with course
ID colon string form data will be a form data type.
We're going to save that.
Query should instead have the arguments of course ID and form data.
So this is what's going to be passed into our body.
And the URL is going to be courses slash course ID as we expect.
Make sure this is a template string.
And this should not be capitalized.
The method should be put for updates.
And finally, we're going to pass in form data.
And when we update the course, this is where invalidates tags is pretty nice and convenient.
We want to do result error is saved into Redux toolkit query.
We're going to pass in an array.
We're going to have a type colon of string courses like so with ID of course ID.
So basically what happens is when we have a list of courses, when we grab the get courses,
we're going to have the tag of courses saved into Redux toolkit query.
When we hit the update course, typically if you're not using any kind of tooling,
you would have to fetch or send a put request to update your course.
And then also have to retrieve updated information for this course because sometimes you have to
make a second request to get the updated list, like the updated course as well.
But by doing so, you don't have to worry about this because you invalidate the tags,
you're updating that specific course via course ID.
So let's say you updated the name of the course, it's going to refetch from the backend,
the outdated or invalidated course information.
So you're always going to have the updated information and it automatically handles it
for you.
It is kind of a pain if you don't have a tool like this.
React query does the same thing.
All right, so we have update course.
We also need create course as well.
So above here, I'm just going to copy the update course,
paste it over here and call this create course instead.
Now this is slightly different.
Instead of having course ID, we're going to have teacher ID.
Instead of form data, it's going to be teacher name, colon string.
In here is going to be a body.
And we are going to have a URL of just courses with post as the method.
And the body should just be a body tag like this.
And finally, invalidate tags.
This is pretty simple because we just want to fetch the entire list of the courses.
So we want to update that way.
And then finally, I'm going to copy create course.
We're going to have delete course as well.
It's a pretty simple delete course.
Build a mutation.
This right here should be message colon string instead.
And what we send to the back end should be a string.
The URL should be or the query argument is going to be a course ID.
This is going to be courses slash course ID like that.
The method should be a delete method.
Remove the body, invalidate tags of courses.
And we should be good to go.
So if I scroll down.
We can now put the courses that we created or the queries that we created.
Use create course mutation.
Use update course mutation.
And use delete course mutation like so.
All right, with our back end now set up, the first thing before we get to the page
where we are editing and creating a course, we want to create this particular page where
we have a list of courses.
And this list of courses is all the courses that, you know, all the teachers that have
put in the course into this system.
So you should be able to see that they have a view only course.
So they can't edit courses that are not theirs.
So we do want to have a create course button, which will allow us to create course that
will allow us to edit and delete that course.
But only if it's their course.
We also have a search functionality and categories.
This is all done on the front end.
So it's based on that.
So if I do advanced, so it's all searching on the front end.
So we're going to go through this pretty fast because this is pretty straightforward.
So we are going to go to dashboard, go to teacher, create a new folder.
We're going to call this courses.
And inside here, I'm going to say page.tsx.
And inside here, I'm going to do rafce, call this courses page, and I'm going to start.
So we're going to grab the router from use router in Next Navigation.
Grab that.
We're going to grab user from use user.
That's going to be coming from clerk.
And then we're also going to grab the list of courses via data courses is loading is
error like so.
And we're going to do use get courses query.
Make sure it is the plural one like so.
And we are going to do category colon all like so.
And then we also have a couple functions that we are going to use for like the API calls.
So create course is going to be from use create course mutation.
So we created that already.
We're also going to grab delete course.
And that's going to from use delete course as you expect.
Mutation like so.
And then we are also going to have a state for search term, set search term.
And we are going to set use state.
Grab that from react.
Put an empty string as a default and also selected category set selected category as well.
And we're going to do use state pass in all.
Now I'm not going to go through this part.
I'm just going to copy this part because right now I want to get through this a little bit
quicker.
We're getting to the end of the application.
So we want to import use memo.
But this is a filter course.
All it's doing is if courses doesn't exist, we're going to filter through make sure it
matches the title of the course for their search.
And we are also making sure the category is matching for the selected categories that
we have.
So it's basically just a simple logic that filters all the categories that we need.
And we're memorizing it just for performance purposes.
And then below, I'm going to copy this and paste it over here.
Pretty straightforward, but I'm going to go through each one.
So there's going to be three functionalities.
Handle edit is going to be a button that's going to exist.
So let me create a course.
And go back to courses and you're going to be able to see there's an edit and delete.
So this edit course is going to be a button that takes us to that specific page.
Handle delete is going to be another button that takes us to or that basically asks us
if we want to delete the course.
And we're going to make sure we delete the course.
And then handle create course will be this specific button up here where we create the
course.
We're going to call the function that we created pass in teacher ID as well as the name.
And then we're going to make sure we take the user to that specific edit page.
So teacher courses, course ID, that's the page that the URL where we edit the course
when we hit edit.
All right.
And then from here, I'm going to do if is loading, we're going to return loading component.
So we're going to import that loading component.
And then if is error, we're going to make sure courses does exist for us to enter our
logic.
We're going to do error loading courses.
If some of them have a problem.
And now in here, I'm going to say class name is equal to teacher dash courses.
And in here with the courses, we are going to pass in Heather and that's going to come
from our components.
So title should be courses.
And then also subtitle should be course.
And then also subtitle should be browse your courses like so.
And we're going to have a right element.
Pass this in.
We're going to have a button component coming from ShadCN and we're going to set on click.
And we are going to pass in handle create course, which is what we created earlier.
And we're going to set class name to be teacher dash courses underscore header like so.
Close this out.
We're going to have a create course button.
Close this Heather with a self-closing tag and we should be able to see Heather like
so.
And now from here, we're going to have a toolbar that we are going to create.
I'm going to put on search.
It's going to be set search.
Search term.
We're going to pass that in and on category change is equal to set selected category.
Pass that in and we are going to create the toolbar component, which we are going to
go over here.
Components create a new file called this toolbar dot TSX.
And I am going to do something I normally don't like to do, which is just copy and paste
a number of things.
I'm only doing this because.
This app has been quite large and it's getting to be quite long, so I'm going to do this.
I'm going to pass in.
On search on category change and we're going to grab toolbar props as well.
But from here.
We are going to add search term with use date.
So we are going to save that we're going to handle search as well.
And we're going to set the search term and when we hit on search, we're going to set
that value as well.
And I'm going to pace everything we need for this part.
So here we have a class name of toolbar.
This will be the input that you see over here and we are going to make sure we handle search
with the placeholder everything that you know and love.
Make sure we import.
At components.
Slash components like this and we are going to import everything else with select trigger.
Select value.
Select content.
And let me move this up so you can see this is everything you need.
This is a color and those are the hovers sections and we are going to grab at components select
items.
And course categories is just going to come from lib utils.
So I made sure to import that those are values so bit basically straightforward.
I didn't want to spend time.
I feel like sometimes some of this code is pretty redundant.
So but it's just building functionality.
So from there we are going to import at components toolbar.
Make sure that's imported and.
If you were to go to here we can do manage account.
And we can go to courses page and once again we need to do use client at the top.
And we should be able to see the toolbar and by the way I didn't show this but if you go
to your user this is a user I signed in with.
I changed this to user type of teacher.
That's why I'm able to see this particular page.
Otherwise you wouldn't be able to access unless you add this user type.
So now I've changed this person to a teacher so I can see search categories.
I can see the categories.
And so on.
All right so we have the courses we have the header and toolbar but we do need to add a
but we do need to display.
The list of courses so over here I'm going to do div class name.
With teacher dash courses.
Underscore grid like so and I'm going to pass in filtered courses.
And I'm going to map it out with course with an arrow function.
And I'm going to create a separate card specifically for this.
I'm going to call this teacher course card.
We're going to close this out and I'm going to have a key with course dot course id.
Course is equal to the course value on edit.
I'm going to pass in handle edit.
I'm going to pass in on delete for the props.
We're going to handle.
Delete will be the function and is owner.
We want to make sure that the owner is the only one who can modify it.
We already have checks on the back end.
We already have a class.